<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<QuestionAlternativeOverrides>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Where was Paul when he wrote/was writing this letter?</Original>
		<Alt>Where was Paul when he wrote this letter?</Alt>
		<Alt>Where was Paul when he was writing this letter?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What is the reason that there is no real value in people carefully obeying/for people to carefully obey such rules?</Original>
		<Alt>What is the reason that there is no real value in people carefully obeying such rules?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that there is no real value for people to carefully obey such rules?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What does Christ do for the body/the church/the believers?</Original>
		<Alt>What does Christ do for the body?</Alt>
		<Alt>What does Christ do for the church?</Alt>
		<Alt>What does Christ do for the believers?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did the prophets write about Jesus/the Messiah long ago?</Original>
		<Alt>What did the prophets write about Jesus long ago?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did the prophets write about the Messiah long ago?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What is the reason that the men from the "Synagogue of the Freedmen" were not able to win out over Stephen/prove that Stephen was wrong when they argued with him?</Original>
		<Alt>What is the reason that the men from the "Synagogue of the Freedmen" were not able to win out over Stephen when they argued with him?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that the men from the "Synagogue of the Freedmen" were not able to prove that Stephen was wrong when they argued with him?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>When Abraham arrived there/in that country, what land did God give to him?</Original>
		<Alt>When Abraham arrived there, what land did God give to him?</Alt>
		<Alt>When Abraham arrived in that country, what land did God give to him?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did the patriarchs/Joseph's brothers do to him?</Original>
		<Alt>What did the patriarchs brothers do to him?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Joseph's brothers do to him?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Then, when the Messiah came, how had the religious leaders to whom Stephen was speaking acted towards him/the Messiah?</Original>
		<Alt>Then, when the Messiah came, how had the religious leaders to whom Stephen was speaking acted towards him?</Alt>
		<Alt>Then, when the Messiah came, how had the religious leaders to whom Stephen was speaking acted towards the Messiah?</Alt>
		<Alt>When the Messiah came, how had the religious leaders to whom Stephen was speaking acted towards him?</Alt>
		<Alt>When the Messiah came, how had the religious leaders to whom Stephen was speaking acted towards the Messiah?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What else did the voice/Jesus tell Saul?</Original>
		<Alt>What else did the voice tell Saul?</Alt>
		<Alt>What else did Jesus tell Saul?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did Peter remind Cornelius and his relatives and friends that they knew/had heard?</Original>
		<Alt>What did Peter remind Cornelius and his relatives and friends that they knew?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Peter remind Cornelius and his relatives and friends that they had heard?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Who heard that some Gentiles had believed the message about Jesus Christ/received the word of God?</Original>
		<Alt>Who heard that some Gentiles had believed the message about Jesus Christ?</Alt>
		<Alt>Who heard that some Gentiles had received the word of God?</Alt>
		<Alt>Who heard that some Gentiles had believed the message about Jesus Christ and received the word of God?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did Paul and Barnabas do for each of the churches/group of believers?</Original>
		<Alt>What did Paul and Barnabas do for each of the churches?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Paul and Barnabas do for each of the group of believers?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did Paul and his companions do on the Sabbath/rest day of the Jews?</Original>
		<Alt>What did Paul and his companions do on the Sabbath of the Jews?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Paul and his companions do on the Sabbath day of the Jews?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Paul and his companions do on the rest day of the Jews?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What dangerous/very bad result did Demetrius say might happen if people continued to believe what Paul taught?</Original>
		<Alt>What dangerous result did Demetrius say might happen if people continued to believe what Paul taught?</Alt>
		<Alt>What very bad result did Demetrius say might happen if people continued to believe what Paul taught?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>With what did Paul compare the believers and the church leaders/elders whom he had appointed to watch over them?</Original>
		<Alt>With what did Paul compare the believers and the church leaders whom he had appointed to watch over them?</Alt>
		<Alt>With what did Paul compare the believers and the elders whom he had appointed to watch over them?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>How did Paul describe the group of believers/the church</Original>
		<Alt>How did Paul describe the group of believers</Alt>
		<Alt>How did Paul describe the church</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did the commander do in order to be able to hear/find out what Paul had done?</Original>
		<Alt>What did the commander do in order to be able to hear what Paul had done?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did the commander do in order to be able to find out what Paul had done?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>In what language did Paul speak to him/the commander?</Original>
		<Alt>In what language did Paul speak to him?</Alt>
		<Alt>In what language did Paul speak to the commander?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did those Jews ask the priests and elders of the Sanhedrin/Supreme Council to do?</Original>
		<Alt>What did those Jews ask the priests and elders of the Sanhedrin to do?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did those Jews ask the priests and elders of the Supreme Council to do?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did the priests/religious leaders say about the things that Tertullus accused Paul of doing?</Original>
		<Alt>What did the priests say about the things that Tertullus accused Paul of doing?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did the religious leaders say about the things that Tertullus accused Paul of doing?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did the crew do to cause the ship to move a little slower/not quite so fast?</Original>
		<Alt>What did the crew do to cause the ship to move a little slower?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did the crew do to cause the ship to move not quite so fast?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What do you think it means for someone/a person to be holy?</Original>
		<Alt>What do you think it means for someone to be holy?</Alt>
		<Alt>What do you think it means for a person to be holy?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What does Christ do for his church/those who follow him?</Original>
		<Alt>What does Christ do for his church?</Alt>
		<Alt>What does Christ do for those who follow him?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What were the reasons that Paul said/For what reasons did Paul say that the believers should not pay attention to a false teacher?</Original>
		<Alt>What were the reasons that Paul said that the believers should not pay attention to a false teacher?</Alt>
		<Alt>For what reasons did Paul say that the believers should not pay attention to a false teacher?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What do you think it means for a person/someone to treat someone else in a just way?</Original>
		<Alt>What do you think it means for a person to treat someone else in a just way?</Alt>
		<Alt>What do you think it means for someone to treat someone else in a just way?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Who accompanied/went with Tychicus?</Original>
		<Alt>Who accompanied Tychicus?</Alt>
		<Alt>Who went with Tychicus?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Who, besides/except for Paul, sent greetings to the Colossian believers?</Original>
		<Alt>Who, besides Paul, sent greetings to the Colossian believers?</Alt>
		<Alt>Who, except for Paul, sent greetings to the Colossian believers?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What is the reason that Paul praised/gave thanks to God?</Original>
		<Alt>What is the reason that Paul praised God?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that Paul gave thanks to God?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did God reveal/make known to us?</Original>
		<Alt>What did God reveal to us?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did God make known to us?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What happened when the non-Jews believed the Good News/the Gospel?</Original>
		<Alt>What happened when the non-Jews believed the Good News?</Alt>
		<Alt>What happened when the non-Jews believed the Gospel?</Alt>
		<Alt>What happened when the Gentiles believed the Good News?</Alt>
		<Alt>What happened when the Gentiles believed the Gospel?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>When God appointed Christ as supreme head over all things, who benefited/received the good from that action?</Original>
		<Alt>When God appointed Christ as supreme head over all things, who benefited from that action?</Alt>
		<Alt>When God appointed Christ as supreme head over all things, who received the good from that action?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What does the church/the body of Christ have available to it?</Original>
		<Alt>What does the church have available to it?</Alt>
		<Alt>What does the body of Christ have available to it?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Since God did that in spite of the fact that we were spiritually dead/like dead people, what do we know about God?</Original>
		<Alt>Since God did that in spite of the fact that we were spiritually dead, what do we know about God?</Alt>
		<Alt>Since God did that in spite of the fact that we were spiritually like dead people, what do we know about God?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Whom has Christ reconciled/caused to be at peace?</Original>
		<Alt>Whom has Christ reconciled?</Alt>
		<Alt>Whom has Christ caused to be at peace?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>How could the Ephesian believers learn more about this mystery/secret plan?</Original>
		<Alt>How could the Ephesian believers learn more about this mystery?</Alt>
		<Alt>How could the Ephesian believers learn more about this secret plan?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What is God's mystery/secret plan?</Original>
		<Alt>What is God's mystery?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is God's secret plan?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What was the reason that God chose Paul to be a servant of/preach the Good News?</Original>
		<Alt>What was the reason that God chose Paul to be a servant of the Good News?</Alt>
		<Alt>What was the reason that God chose Paul to preach the Good News?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What is the reason that we believers can be bold to pray to God with freedom and confidence/without fear?</Original>
		<Alt>What is the reason that we believers can be bold to pray to God with freedom and confidence?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that we believers can be bold to pray to God without fear?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that we believers can be bold to pray to God with freedom and without fear?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>How long did Paul expect Christ to live/dwell in their hearts/with them?</Original>
		<Alt>How long did Paul expect Christ to live in their hearts?</Alt>
		<Alt>How long did Paul expect Christ to live with them?</Alt>
		<Alt>How long did Paul expect Christ to dwell in their hearts?</Alt>
		<Alt>How long did Paul expect Christ to dwell with them?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What is the reason that Christ would live/dwell in their hearts/with them?</Original>
		<Alt>What is the reason that Christ would live in their hearts?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that Christ would live with them?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that Christ would dwell in their hearts?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that Christ would dwell with them?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What do you think it means for a person/someone to commit sexual immorality?</Original>
		<Alt>What do you think it means for a person to commit sexual immorality?</Alt>
		<Alt>What do you think it means for someone to commit sexual immorality?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What other reason did Paul give them for not doing/committing the sins/bad deeds he mentioned in 5:3, that is, being immoral, indecent or greedy?</Original>
		<Alt>What other reason did Paul give them for not doing the sins he mentioned in 5:3, that is, being immoral, indecent or greedy?</Alt>
		<Alt>What other reason did Paul give them for not doing the bad deeds he mentioned in 5:3, that is, being immoral, indecent or greedy?</Alt>
		<Alt>What other reason did Paul give them for not committing the sins he mentioned in 5:3, that is, being immoral, indecent or greedy?</Alt>
		<Alt>What other reason did Paul give them for not committing the bad deeds he mentioned in 5:3, that is, being immoral, indecent or greedy?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What can people see when someone shines a light on something that was in darkness/the dark?</Original>
		<Alt>What can people see when someone shines a light on something that was in darkness?</Alt>
		<Alt>What can people see when someone shines a light on something that was in the dark?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did Paul tell the Christians/the believers to do?</Original>
		<Alt>What did Paul tell the Christians to do?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Paul tell the believers to do?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>When they thank God, through whom/whose name do they mention/depend on/do they pray?</Original>
		<Alt>When they thank God, on whom do they depend?</Alt>
		<Alt>When they thank God, through whom do they pray?</Alt>
		<Alt>When they thank God, whose name do they mention?</Alt>
		<Alt>When they thank God, on whose name do they depend?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>How can believers honor/show respect for Christ?</Original>
		<Alt>How can believers honor Christ?</Alt>
		<Alt>How can believers show respect for Christ?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What is the reason that a wife should submit herself to/obey her husband?</Original>
		<Alt>What is the reason that a wife should submit herself to her husband?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that a wife should obey her husband?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that a wife should submit herself to or obey her husband?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What are all the believers regarded as/called in their relationship to Christ?</Original>
		<Alt>What are all the believers regarded as in their relationship to Christ?</Alt>
		<Alt>What are all the believers called in their relationship to Christ?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>How did Christ show his love for the church/the believers?</Original>
		<Alt>How did Christ show his love for the church?</Alt>
		<Alt>How did Christ show his love for the believers?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What is the reason that Christ died for the church/the believers?</Original>
		<Alt>What is the reason that Christ died for the church?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that Christ died for the believers?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did Christ do to make the church/the believers pure/sanctified?</Original>
		<Alt>What did Christ do to make the church pure?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Christ do to make the church sanctified?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Christ do to make the believers pure?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Christ do to make the believers sanctified?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What is the reason that Christ did that/sanctified them/made them pure?</Original>
		<Alt>What is the reason that Christ did that?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that Christ sanctified them?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that Christ made them pure?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What is the first commandment [which God gave] and which included a promise of something good to those who obey/follow that command?</Original>
		<Alt>What is the first commandment which God gave and which included a promise of something good to those who obey that command?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the first commandment which God gave and which included a promise of something good to those who follow that command?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the first commandment that included a promise of something good to those who obey that command?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the first commandment that included a promise of something good to those who follow that command?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did God promise to those who follow that/the first command?</Original>
		<Alt>What did God promise to those who follow that command?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did God promise to those who follow the first command?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What is the reason that we ought/it is necessary for us to be prepared to resist the Devil?</Original>
		<Alt>What is the reason that we ought to be prepared to resist the Devil?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason it is necessary for us to be prepared to resist the Devil?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>If believers use all the resources that God gives them to protect themselves/the whole armor of God, what will they be able to do?</Original>
		<Alt>If believers use all the resources that God gives them to protect themselves, what will they be able to do?</Alt>
		<Alt>If believers use the whole armor of God, what will they be able to do?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did Paul tell the believers to do in order to face/resist those enemies/evil spirits?</Original>
		<Alt>What did Paul tell the believers to do in order to face those enemies?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Paul tell the believers to do in order to face those evil spirits?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Paul tell the believers to do in order to resist those enemies?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Paul tell the believers to do in order to resist those evil spirits?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>If they trust/have faith in Christ, what will they be able to do?</Original>
		<Alt>If they trust Christ, what will they be able to do?</Alt>
		<Alt>If they have faith in Christ, what will they be able to do?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What do you think the term/the title "God the father" means?</Original>
		<Alt>What do you think the term "God the father" means?</Alt>
		<Alt>What do you think the title "God the father" means?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did Paul do to the believers when he was involved in Judaism/the Jewish religion?</Original>
		<Alt>What did Paul do to the believers when he was involved in Judaism?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Paul do to the believers when he was involved in the Jewish religion?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did Paul say about the way he formerly followed Judaism/the Jewish religion?</Original>
		<Alt>What did Paul say about the way he formerly followed Judaism?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Paul say about the way he formerly followed the Jewish religion?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What was the reason that God made known/revealed his son to Paul?</Original>
		<Alt>What was the reason that God made known his son to Paul?</Alt>
		<Alt>What was the reason that God revealed his son to Paul?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What is the reason that people are no longer to follow the law/be controlled by the law?</Original>
		<Alt>What is the reason that people are no longer to follow the law?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that people are no longer to be controlled by the law?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>To what is an heir, who is a child, just like/similar?</Original>
		<Alt>To what is an heir, who is a child, just like?</Alt>
		<Alt>To what is an heir, who is a child, similar?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What was the reason that God sent the Holy Spirit/the spirit of his son into their hearts/lives?</Original>
		<Alt>What was the reason that God sent the Holy Spirit into their hearts?</Alt>
		<Alt>What was the reason that God sent the Holy Spirit into their lives?</Alt>
		<Alt>What was the reason that God sent the spirit of his son into their hearts?</Alt>
		<Alt>What was the reason that God sent the spirit of his son into their lives?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What does the author say about this expectation/hope they have? (or, What does it say about an anchor?)</Original>
		<Alt>What does the author say about this expectation they have?</Alt>
		<Alt>What does the author say about this hope they have?</Alt>
		<Alt>What does it say about an anchor?</Alt>
		<Alt>What does the author say about this expectation they have? (What does it say about an anchor?)</Alt>
		<Alt>What does the author say about this hope they have? (What does it say about an anchor?)</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What were they doing that made Paul believe that they were becoming slaves of those things/worshipping false gods/following false teachings again?</Original>
		<Alt>What were they doing that made Paul believe that they were becoming slaves of those things again?</Alt>
		<Alt>What were they doing that made Paul believe that they were worshipping false gods again?</Alt>
		<Alt>What were they doing that made Paul believe that they were following false teachings again?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What was the attitude of those other people/false teachers toward the Galatians?</Original>
		<Alt>What was the attitude of those other people toward the Galatians?</Alt>
		<Alt>What was the attitude of those false teachers toward the Galatians?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>When did Paul say they should have an interest in someone/be zealous for someone?</Original>
		<Alt>When did Paul say they should have an interest in someone?</Alt>
		<Alt>When did Paul say they should be zealous for someone?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did Hagar stand for/represent?</Original>
		<Alt>What did Hagar stand for?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Hagar represent?</Alt>
	</Alternative>	
	<Alternative>	
		<Original>What did Paul say about the Jerusalem that is above/is in heaven?</Original>
		<Alt>What did Paul say about the Jerusalem that is above?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Paul say about the Jerusalem that is in heaven?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>	
		<Original>What did Paul want them to learn from that illustration/all of that?</Original>
		<Alt>What did Paul want them to learn from that illustration?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Paul want them to learn from all of that?</Alt>
	</Alternative>	
	<Alternative>
		<Original>According to God, for what reason would his Spirit not remain with people/mankind forever/for a long time? -OR- According to God, for what reason would he not allow people/mankind to live forever/for a long time?</Original>
		<Alt>According to God, for what reason would his Spirit not remain with people forever?</Alt>
		<Alt>According to God, for what reason would his Spirit not remain with people for a long time?</Alt>
		<Alt>According to God, for what reason would his Spirit not remain with mankind forever?</Alt>
		<Alt>According to God, for what reason would his Spirit not remain with mankind for a long time?</Alt>
		<Alt>According to God, for what reason would he not allow people to live forever?</Alt>
		<Alt>According to God, for what reason would he not allow people to live for a long time?</Alt>
		<Alt>According to God, for what reason would he not allow mankind to live forever?</Alt>
		<Alt>According to God, for what reason would he not allow mankind to live for a long time?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What happened to Dinah? // What did Simeon and Levi do about/do for Dinah?</Original>
		<Alt>What happened to Dinah?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Simeon and Levi do about Dinah?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Simeon and Levi do for Dinah?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>How did Paul say the whole law was summed up/fulfilled/completed by people?</Original>
		<Alt>How did Paul say the whole law was summed up by people?</Alt>
		<Alt>How did Paul say the whole law was fulfilled by people?</Alt>
		<Alt>How did Paul say the whole law was completed by people?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did Paul tell them to do, if one of the believers had sinned/had done something wrong?</Original>
		<Alt>What did Paul tell them to do, if one of the believers had sinned?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Paul tell them to do, if one of the believers had done something wrong?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did Paul say about the cross of Jesus Christ/what Christ accomplished on the cross?</Original>
		<Alt>What did Paul say about the cross of Jesus Christ?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Paul say about what Christ accomplished on the cross?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>About what event is this passage? // What events are recorded/written about in this passage?</Original>
		<Alt>About what event is this passage?</Alt>
		<Alt>What events are recorded in this passage?</Alt>
		<Alt>What events are written about in this passage?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Tell me the main events recorded in this passage. (If necessary, prompt with: What was the world like? What happened on each day/of the days?)</Original>
		<Alt>Tell me the main events recorded in this passage. (If necessary, prompt with: What was the world like? What happened on each day?)</Alt>
		<Alt>Tell me the main events recorded in this passage. (If necessary, prompt with: What was the world like? What happened on each of the days?)</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>As you read/heard this passage, did you think the author wrote it/was writing mostly for children? Or did he write it mainly for adults?</Original>
		<Alt>As you heard this passage, did you think the author wrote it mostly for children? Or did he write it mainly for adults?</Alt>
		<Alt>As you heard this passage, did you think the author was writing mostly for children? Or did he write it mainly for adults?</Alt>
		<Alt>As you read this passage, did you think the author wrote it mostly for children? Or did he write it mainly for adults?</Alt>
		<Alt>As you read this passage, did you think the author was writing mostly for children? Or did he write it mainly for adults?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did God do to make light/to cause light to appear?</Original>
		<Alt>What did God do to cause light to appear?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did God do to make light appear?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>In what way/How did God make humans/people different from (the way he made) animals and fish and birds?</Original>
		<Alt>In what way did God make humans different from (the way he made) animals and fish and birds?</Alt>
		<Alt>In what way did God make people different from (the way he made) animals and fish and birds?</Alt>
		<Alt>How did God make humans different from (the way he made) animals and fish and birds?</Alt>
		<Alt>How did God make people different from (the way he made) animals and fish and birds?</Alt>
		<Alt>In what way did God make humans different from animals and fish and birds?</Alt>
		<Alt>In what way did God make people different from animals and fish and birds?</Alt>
		<Alt>How did God make humans different from animals and fish and birds?</Alt>
		<Alt>How did God make people different from animals and fish and birds?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What do we read about in this passage/here?</Original>
		<Alt>What do we read about in this passage?</Alt>
		<Alt>What do we read about here?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>After God formed man from the dust/soil, what did God do to cause him to live/become alive?</Original>
		<Alt>After God formed man from the dust, what did God do to cause him to live?</Alt>
		<Alt>After God formed man from the dust, what did God do to cause him to become alive?</Alt>
		<Alt>After God formed man from the soil, what did God do to cause him to live?</Alt>
		<Alt>After God formed man from the soil, what did God do to cause him to become alive?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What was the source of water for the many trees in that garden/Eden place?</Original>
		<Alt>What was the source of water for the many trees in the Garden of Eden?</Alt>
		<Alt>What was the source of water for the many trees in that garden?</Alt>
		<Alt>What was the source of water for the many trees in Eden?</Alt>
		<Alt>What was the source of water for the many trees in the Eden place?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>From this passage, what do we learn about those/the four rivers of that garden?</Original>
		<Alt>From this passage, what do we learn about those four rivers of that garden?</Alt>
		<Alt>From this passage, what do we learn about the four rivers of that garden?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>For what purpose did God place the man in the Garden of Eden/Eden place?</Original>
		<Alt>For what purpose did God place the man in the Garden of Eden?</Alt>
		<Alt>For what purpose did God place the man in that garden?</Alt>
		<Alt>For what purpose did God place the man in Eden?</Alt>
		<Alt>For what purpose did God place the man in the Eden place?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>In the future, what will the serpent do to the woman's offspring/descendent(s)?</Original>
		<Alt>In the future, what will the serpent do to the woman's offspring?</Alt>
		<Alt>In the future, what will the serpent do to the woman's descendent?</Alt>
		<Alt>In the future, what will the serpent do to the woman's descendents?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Whom did God expel/send away from the Garden of Eden?</Original>
		<Alt>Whom did God expel from the Garden of Eden?</Alt>
		<Alt>Whom did God send away from the Garden of Eden?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Do we know what Cain produced/looked after on his farm?</Original>
		<Alt>Do we know what Cain produced on his farm?</Alt>
		<Alt>Do we know what Cain looked after on his farm?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Tell me about one/Give me an example of one of the people mentioned in this chapter.</Original>
		<Alt>Tell me about one of the people mentioned in this chapter.</Alt>
		<Alt>Give me an example of one of the people mentioned in this chapter.</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What were people like/What was mankind like at that time?</Original>
		<Alt>What were people like at that time?</Alt>
		<Alt>What was mankind like at that time?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>How many of each kind of animal was Noah to take into the boat/on board?</Original>
		<Alt>How many of each kind of animal was Noah to take into the boat?</Alt>
		<Alt>How many of each kind of animal was Noah to take on board?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>As the waters began to recede/go down, where did the large boat finally come to rest?</Original>
		<Alt>As the waters began to recede, where did the large boat finally come to rest?</Alt>
		<Alt>As the waters began to go down, where did the large boat finally come to rest?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>After the dove flew away and did not return, and after Noah looked out and saw everything drying up, he still did not leave the large boat. Two more months passed/went by. What happened before Noah left the large boat?</Original>
		<Alt>After the dove flew away and did not return, and after Noah looked out and saw everything drying up, he still did not leave the large boat. Two more months passed. What happened before Noah left the large boat?</Alt>
		<Alt>After the dove flew away and did not return, and after Noah looked out and saw everything drying up, he still did not leave the large boat. Two more months went by. What happened before Noah left the large boat?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Even though the thinking of people/mankind is very bad/thoroughly corrupt, what did God declare (that he would not do again)?</Original>
		<Alt>Even though the thinking of people is very bad, what did God declare (that he would not do again)?</Alt>
		<Alt>Even though the thinking of people is thoroughly corrupt, what did God declare (that he would not do again)?</Alt>
		<Alt>Even though the thinking of mankind is very bad, what did God declare (that he would not do again)?</Alt>
		<Alt>Even though the thinking of mankind is thoroughly corrupt, what did God declare (that he would not do again)?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did the chief baker/the leader of Pharaoh's bakers think about the dream of the chief drink-server/cup-bearer?</Original>
		<Alt>What did the chief baker think about the dream of the chief drink-server?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did the chief baker think about the dream of the chief cup-bearer?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did the the leader of Pharaoh's bakers think about the dream of the chief drink-server?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did the the leader of Pharaoh's bakers think about the dream of the chief cup-bearer?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Tell me about the dream of the chief baker/the leader of Pharaoh's bakers.</Original>
		<Alt>Tell me about the dream of the chief baker.</Alt>
		<Alt>Tell me about the dream of the leader of Pharaoh's bakers.</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did Pharaoh's magicians/priests and wise men tell him about the meaning of his dreams?</Original>
		<Alt>What did Pharaoh's magicians and wise men tell him about the meaning of his dreams?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Pharaoh's priests and wise men tell him about the meaning of his dreams?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Tell what happened with Joseph's family/Joseph's father and brothers during the time of famine.</Original>
		<Alt>Tell what happened with Joseph's family during the time of famine.</Alt>
		<Alt>Tell what happened with Joseph's father and brothers during the time of famine.</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Who promised to be responsible for/take care of Benjamin?</Original>
		<Alt>Who promised to be responsible for Benjamin?</Alt>
		<Alt>Who promised to take care of Benjamin?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did Reuben say to his father, as a guarantee that he (Reuben) would truly watch out for/protect Benjamin? (37)</Original>
		<Alt>What did Reuben say to his father, as a guarantee that he (Reuben) would truly watch out for Benjamin? (37)</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Reuben say to his father, as a guarantee that he (Reuben) would truly protect Benjamin? (37)</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Reuben say to his father, as a guarantee that he would truly watch out for Benjamin? (37)</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Reuben say to his father, as a guarantee that he would truly protect Benjamin? (37)</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Which of the brothers became the spokesman/began to speak on behalf of all of the brothers?</Original>
		<Alt>Which of the brothers became the spokesman?</Alt>
		<Alt>Which of the brothers became the spokesman for the brothers?</Alt>
		<Alt>Which of the brothers began to speak on behalf of all of the brothers?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did the brothers suppose that Joseph might do to them if he thought that/because they had not paid for the grain?</Original>
		<Alt>What did the brothers suppose that Joseph might do to them if he thought that they had not paid for the grain?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did the brothers suppose that Joseph might do to them because they had not paid for the grain?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>According to Joseph, if God had not brought him to Egypt, what would have happened to Joseph's relatives/Joseph's extended family/Jacob and Jacob's descendents?</Original>
		<Alt>According to Joseph, if God had not brought him to Egypt, what would have happened to Joseph's relatives?</Alt>
		<Alt>According to Joseph, if God had not brought him to Egypt, what would have happened to Joseph's extended family?</Alt>
		<Alt>According to Joseph, if God had not brought him to Egypt, what would have happened to Jacob and Jacob's descendents?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>According to Joseph, what was one bad thing that God used in order to bring about/cause good?</Original>
		<Alt>According to Joseph, what was one bad thing that God used in order to bring about good?</Alt>
		<Alt>According to Joseph, what was one bad thing that God used in order to cause good?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>At this time, what did Joseph add to what his brothers were to tell their father about him/his position in Egypt?</Original>
		<Alt>At this time, what did Joseph add to what his brothers were to tell their father about him?</Alt>
		<Alt>At this time, what did Joseph add to what his brothers were to tell their father about his position in Egypt?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did God tell Jacob not to fear/not to be afraid of?</Original>
		<Alt>What did God tell Jacob not to fear?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did God tell Jacob not to be afraid of?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What are four wonderful promises that God spoke to/promised to Jacob?</Original>
		<Alt>What are four wonderful promises that God spoke to Jacob?</Alt>
		<Alt>What are four wonderful promises that God promised to Jacob?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>In counting Jacob's 66 own offspring/66 direct descendents in this account, who was not included in the count/list?</Original>
		<Alt>In counting Jacob's 66 own offspring in this account, who was not included in the count?</Alt>
		<Alt>In counting Jacob's 66 own offspring in this account, who was not included in the list?</Alt>
		<Alt>In counting Jacob's 66 direct descendents in this account, who was not included in the count?</Alt>
		<Alt>In counting Jacob's 66 direct descendents in this account, who was not included in the list?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did the Egyptians think about herdsmen/people who worked with livestock?</Original>
		<Alt>What did the Egyptians think about herdsmen?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did the Egyptians think about people who worked with livestock?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>If a person considers carefully not only what [God's] law says, but also does what it tells him to do, what will [God] do to/for him?</Original>
		<Alt>If a person considers carefully not only what God's law says, but also does what it tells him to do, what will God do to him?</Alt>
		<Alt>If a person considers carefully not only what God's law says, but also does what it tells him to do, what will God do for him?</Alt>
		<Alt>If a person considers carefully not only what the law says, but also does what it tells him to do, what will God do to him?</Alt>
		<Alt>If a person considers carefully not only what the law says, but also does what it tells him to do, what will God do for him?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What very important law/command [has God] given in his word?</Original>
		<Alt>What very important law has God given in his word?</Alt>
		<Alt>What very important command has God given in his word?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did God promise then/at that time?</Original>
		<Alt>What did God promise then?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did God promise at that time?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Tell me about what happened to Abram here/at this time.</Original>
		<Alt>Tell me about what happened to Abram here.</Alt>
		<Alt>Tell me about what happened to Abram at this time.</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Did Abram and his group reach Canaan/arrive at Canaan?</Original>
		<Alt>Did Abram and his group reach Canaan?</Alt>
		<Alt>Did Abram and his group arrive at Canaan?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Where did they stop/make their first stop in Canaan?</Original>
		<Alt>Where did they stop in Canaan?</Alt>
		<Alt>Where did they make their first stop in Canaan?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did Abram do there/at Hebron?</Original>
		<Alt>What did Abram do there?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Abram do at Hebron?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>How did Abram know that Kedorlaomer had captured/taken away his nephew, Lot?</Original>
		<Alt>How did Abram know that Kedorlaomer had captured his nephew, Lot?</Alt>
		<Alt>How did Abram know that Kedorlaomer had taken away his nephew, Lot?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>When Abram found out that Lot had been carried off/taken away, what did he do?</Original>
		<Alt>When Abram found out that Lot had been carried off, what did he do?</Alt>
		<Alt>When Abram found out that Lot had been taken away, what did he do?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Who offered Abram food and drink/bread and wine?</Original>
		<Alt>Who offered Abram food and drink?</Alt>
		<Alt>Who offered Abram bread and wine?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>We learn that Melchizedek brought Abram food and drink/bread and wine. What else did Melchizedek do for Abram?</Original>
		<Alt>We learn that Melchizedek brought Abram food and drink. What else did Melchizedek do for Abram?</Alt>
		<Alt>We learn that Melchizedek brought Abram bread and wine. What else did Melchizedek do for Abram?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>As a result/So what did Hagar do?</Original>
		<Alt>As a result what did Hagar do?</Alt>
		<Alt>So what did Hagar do?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What name did God use to refer to himself in this passage/here?</Original>
		<Alt>What name did God use to refer to himself in this passage?</Alt>
		<Alt>What name did God use to refer to himself here?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>After God promised to bless/to do good for Abraham, whom did he promise to bless/for whom did he promise to do good in this passage?</Original>
		<Alt>After God promised to bless Abraham, whom did he promise to bless in this passage?</Alt>
		<Alt>After God promised to bless Abraham, for whom did he promise to do good in this passage?</Alt>
		<Alt>After God promised to do good for Abraham, whom did he promise to bless in this passage?</Alt>
		<Alt>After God promised to do good for Abraham, for whom did he promise to do good in this passage?</Alt>
	</Alternative>	
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did [God] do when Abraham believed what God [said to/promised him]?</Original>
		<Alt>What did God do when Abraham believed what God said to him?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did God do when Abraham believed what God promised him?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What does a person who does evil [deeds] think about Jesus/the light?</Original>
		<Alt>What does a person who does evil think about Jesus?</Alt>
		<Alt>What does a person who does evil think about the light?</Alt>
		<Alt>What does a person who does evil deeds think about Jesus?</Alt>
		<Alt>What does a person who does evil deeds think about the light?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What is the reason that [God] had not given the Spirit [to those who believed in Jesus] before/in the past?</Original>
		<Alt>What is the reason that God had not given the Spirit before?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that God had not given the Spirit in the past?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that God had not given the Spirit to those who believed in Jesus before?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that God had not given the Spirit to those who believed in Jesus in the past?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What was the reason that Jesus was glad that he had not been/was not there [with Lazarus]?</Original>
		<Alt>What was the reason that Jesus was glad that he had not been there?</Alt>
		<Alt>What was the reason that Jesus was glad that he was not there?</Alt>
		<Alt>What was the reason that Jesus was glad that he had not been there with Lazarus?</Alt>
		<Alt>What was the reason that Jesus was glad that he was not there with Lazarus?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did Jesus carry [to his crucifixion/on the way to be crucified]?</Original>
		<Alt>What did Jesus carry to his crucifixion?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Jesus carry on the way to be crucified?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What is the reason that [someone] wrote those things/about those events?</Original>
		<Alt>What is the reason that someone wrote those things?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that someone wrote about those events?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>In verse 18 Luke wrote that John kept on urging/strongly requesting [the people to repent of their sins] and that he preached the Good News to them. If people will be punished in the fires of hell, that does not sound like good news. What was the good news that John preached?</Original>
		<Alt>In verse 18 Luke wrote that John kept on urging the people to repent of their sins and that he preached the Good News to them. If people will be punished in the fires of hell, that does not sound like good news. What was the good news that John preached?</Alt>
		<Alt>In verse 18 Luke wrote that John kept on strongly requesting the people to repent of their sins and that he preached the Good News to them. If people will be punished in the fires of hell, that does not sound like good news. What was the good news that John preached?</Alt>
		<Alt>In verse 18 Luke wrote that John kept on urging and that he preached the Good News to them. If people will be punished in the fires of hell, that does not sound like good news. What was the good news that John preached?</Alt>
		<Alt>In verse 18 Luke wrote that John kept on strongly requesting and that he preached the Good News to them. If people will be punished in the fires of hell, that does not sound like good news. What was the good news that John preached?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What were the chief priests and the teachers of the law [planning] to do to him/the Son of Man?</Original>
		<Alt>What were the chief priests and the teachers of the law planning to do to him?</Alt>
		<Alt>What were the chief priests and the teachers of the law planning to do to the Son of Man?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What is the reason that [God] will shorten the number of days that the tribulation/the time when people will suffer will last?</Original>
		<Alt>What is the reason that God will shorten the number of days that the tribulation will last?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that God will shorten the time when people will suffer?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What was Christ's attitude about his place/position with God [in heaven]?</Original>
		<Alt>What was Christ's attitude about his place with God in heaven?</Alt>
		<Alt>What was Christ's attitude about his position with God in heaven?</Alt>
		<Alt>What was Christ's attitude about his place with God?</Alt>
		<Alt>What was Christ's attitude about his position with God?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>How did Paul say he would feel on the day Christ [returns to the earth from heaven], if the believers had been/were faithful to God?</Original>
		<Alt>How did Paul say he would feel on the day Christ returns to the earth from heaven, if the believers had been faithful to God?</Alt>
		<Alt>How did Paul say he would feel on the day Christ returns to the earth from heaven, if the believers were faithful to God?</Alt>
		<Alt>How did Paul say he would feel on the day Christ returns, if the believers had been faithful to God?</Alt>
		<Alt>How did Paul say he would feel on the day Christ returns, if the believers were faithful to God?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>In what ways did God promise to do good to Sarah/to bless Sarah?</Original>
		<Alt>In what ways did God promise to do good to Sarah?</Alt>
		<Alt>In what ways did God promise to bless Sarah?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>At that time/At the time of this incident, where was Abraham?</Original>
		<Alt>At that time, where was Abraham?</Alt>
		<Alt>At the time of this incident, where was Abraham?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>How much flour did Abraham tell his wife to prepare/make ready?</Original>
		<Alt>How much flour did Abraham tell his wife to prepare?</Alt>
		<Alt>How much flour did Abraham tell his wife to make ready?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>When Sarah heard what God said to Abraham, how did she feel/what feeling did she experience?</Original>
		<Alt>When Sarah heard what God said to Abraham, how did she feel?</Alt>
		<Alt>When Sarah heard what God said to Abraham, what feeling did she experience?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Instead of Lot sending out/giving his two visitors to the men of Sodom, what did he suggest to the crowd?</Original>
		<Alt>Instead of Lot sending out his two visitors to the men of Sodom, what did he suggest to the crowd?</Alt>
		<Alt>Instead of Lot giving his two visitors to the men of Sodom, what did he suggest to the crowd?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What do you think was the reason why Lot offered his two daughters to the crowd, instead of sending out/giving up his visitors?</Original>
		<Alt>What do you think was the reason why Lot offered his two daughters to the crowd, instead of sending out his visitors?</Alt>
		<Alt>What do you think was the reason why Lot offered his two daughters to the crowd, instead of giving up his visitors?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Did those two men/fiancs of his daughters flee the city with Lot and his family?</Original>
		<Alt>Did those two men flee the city with Lot and his family?</Alt>
		<Alt>Did those two fiancs of his daughters flee the city with Lot and his family?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Did Lot want to leave Sodom/leave his place?</Original>
		<Alt>Did Lot want to leave Sodom?</Alt>
		<Alt>Did Lot want to leave his place?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What was the reason that Lot gave to God/to the angels for not wanting to flee to the mountains?</Original>
		<Alt>What was the reason that Lot gave to God for not wanting to flee to the mountains?</Alt>
		<Alt>What was the reason that Lot gave to the angels for not wanting to flee to the mountains?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>After that/From then on, what did people call that place where Lot and his family took shelter?</Original>
		<Alt>After that, what did people call that place where Lot and his family took shelter?</Alt>
		<Alt>From then on, what did people call that place where Lot and his family took shelter?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What people-group descended/came into being from the child of the elder daughter?</Original>
		<Alt>What people-group descended from the child of the elder daughter?</Alt>
		<Alt>What people-group came into being from the child of the elder daughter?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>And what people-group is named after/named from the child of the younger daughter?</Original>
		<Alt>And what people-group is named after the child of the younger daughter?</Alt>
		<Alt>And what people-group is named from the child of the younger daughter?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Tell what Abraham and Sarah did here/at this time, and what was the outcome.</Original>
		<Alt>Tell what Abraham and Sarah did here, and what was the outcome.</Alt>
		<Alt>Tell what Abraham and Sarah did at this time, and what was the outcome.</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Where were Abraham and Sarah at this time/according to this passage?</Original>
		<Alt>Where were Abraham and Sarah at this time?</Alt>
		<Alt>Where were Abraham and Sarah according to this passage?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>I am listing/will list 5 events, and I ask you to place them in the order in which they happened: (a) Abimelech had a dream; (b) Abimelech returned Sarah to Abraham; (c) the women of the palace became unable to become pregnant/unable to conceive; (d) Abimelech took Sarah into his palace; (e) Abraham prayed for Abimelech and for his people.</Original>
		<Alt>I am listing 5 events, and I ask you to place them in the order in which they happened: (a) Abimelech had a dream; (b) Abimelech returned Sarah to Abraham; (c) the women of the palace became unable to become pregnant; (d) Abimelech took Sarah into his palace; (e) Abraham prayed for Abimelech and for his people.</Alt>
		<Alt>I am listing 5 events, and I ask you to place them in the order in which they happened: (a) Abimelech had a dream; (b) Abimelech returned Sarah to Abraham; (c) the women of the palace became unable to conceive; (d) Abimelech took Sarah into his palace; (e) Abraham prayed for Abimelech and for his people.</Alt>
		<Alt>I will list 5 events, and I ask you to place them in the order in which they happened: (a) Abimelech had a dream; (b) Abimelech returned Sarah to Abraham; (c) the women of the palace became unable to become pregnant; (d) Abimelech took Sarah into his palace; (e) Abraham prayed for Abimelech and for his people.</Alt>
		<Alt>I will list 5 events, and I ask you to place them in the order in which they happened: (a) Abimelech had a dream; (b) Abimelech returned Sarah to Abraham; (c) the women of the palace became unable to conceive; (d) Abimelech took Sarah into his palace; (e) Abraham prayed for Abimelech and for his people.</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did Sarah experience here/at this time/in this account?</Original>
		<Alt>What did Sarah experience here?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Sarah experience at this time?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Sarah experience in this account?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Tell what happened at this time/at the time of this account.</Original>
		<Alt>Tell what happened at this time.</Alt>
		<Alt>Tell what happened at the time of this account.</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did God/the angel of God say to Hagar?</Original>
		<Alt>What did God say to Hagar?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did the angel of God say to Hagar?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Tell me what happened in this account/at this time.</Original>
		<Alt>Tell me what happened in this account.</Alt>
		<Alt>Tell me what happened at this time.</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Who visited Abraham in this account/at this time?</Original>
		<Alt>Who visited Abraham in this account?</Alt>
		<Alt>Who visited Abraham at this time?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>How many days did they walk, before they could see/they saw the place where they were to go?</Original>
		<Alt>How many days did they walk, before they could see the place where they were to go?</Alt>
		<Alt>How many days did they walk, before they saw the place where they were to go?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>When Abraham could see/saw the place to which they were going, what did he say to his servants?</Original>
		<Alt>When Abraham could see the place to which they were going, what did he say to his servants?</Alt>
		<Alt>When Abraham saw the place to which they were going, what did he say to his servants?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Tell what happened at this time/in this passage.</Original>
		<Alt>Tell what happened at this time.</Alt>
		<Alt>Tell what happened in this passage.</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did the author say about Abraham at this time/at the time of this incident?</Original>
		<Alt>What did the author say about Abraham at this time?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did the author say about Abraham at the time of this incident?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>When he arrived in the late afternoon/evening, was that the same day on which he had begun his journey?</Original>
		<Alt>When he arrived in the late afternoon, was that the same day on which he had begun his journey?</Alt>
		<Alt>When he arrived in the evening, was that the same day on which he had begun his journey?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did Isaac then name the new watering place/well?</Original>
		<Alt>What did Isaac then name the new watering place?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Isaac then name the new well?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>So what did Isaac name the watering place/well this time?</Original>
		<Alt>So what did Isaac name the watering place this time?</Alt>
		<Alt>So what did Isaac name the well this time?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did they say about what they had done when Isaac had formerly lived among them/in their place?</Original>
		<Alt>What did they say about what they had done when Isaac had formerly lived among them?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did they say about what they had done when Isaac had formerly lived in their place?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>At the time that Esau (got) married/took a wife, how old was he?</Original>
		<Alt>At the time that Esau (got) married, how old was he?</Alt>
		<Alt>At the time that Esau took a wife, how old was he?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>By what means/How did Rebekah know/find out about Isaac's instructions to Esau?</Original>
		<Alt>By what means did Rebekah know about Isaac's instructions to Esau?</Alt>
		<Alt>By what means did Rebekah find out about Isaac's instructions to Esau?</Alt>
		<Alt>How did Rebekah know about Isaac's instructions to Esau?</Alt>
		<Alt>How did Rebekah find out about Isaac's instructions to Esau?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Did Rebekah think that Jacob would ever be able to return to her/would be able to return to her some day?</Original>
		<Alt>Did Rebekah think that Jacob would ever be able to return to her?</Alt>
		<Alt>Did Rebekah think that Jacob would be able to return to her some day?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>So after the sheep had gathered and the shepherds had given the sheep water, what did those shepherds do next/what was it their custom to do before leaving?</Original>
		<Alt>So after the sheep had gathered and the shepherds had given the sheep water, what did those shepherds do next before leaving?</Alt>
		<Alt>So after the sheep had gathered and the shepherds had given the sheep water, what was it their custom to do before leaving?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>According to Rachel, what would happen if she was not able to become pregnant/bear children?</Original>
		<Alt>According to Rachel, what would happen if she was not able to become pregnant?</Alt>
		<Alt>According to Rachel, what would happen if she was not able to bear children?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>This passage describes what Jacob was doing while he was caring for/looking after Laban's animals. What was Jacob's goal/intention at that time?</Original>
		<Alt>This passage describes what Jacob was doing while he was caring for Laban's animals. What was Jacob's goal at that time?</Alt>
		<Alt>This passage describes what Jacob was doing while he was caring for Laban's animals. What was Jacob's intention at that time?</Alt>
		<Alt>This passage describes what Jacob was doing while he was looking after Laban's animals. What was Jacob's goal at that time?</Alt>
		<Alt>This passage describes what Jacob was doing while he was looking after Laban's animals. What was Jacob's intention at that time?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did Jacob say that he had now accumulated/he now owned?</Original>
		<Alt>What did Jacob say that he had now accumulated?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Jacob say that he now owned?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Did Jacob feel that God had fulfilled his promise to treat him well/to do good for him?</Original>
		<Alt>Did Jacob feel that God had fulfilled his promise to treat him well?</Alt>
		<Alt>Did Jacob feel that God had fulfilled his promise to do good for him?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>As Jacob approached/came near to Esau, what did Jacob do?</Original>
		<Alt>As Jacob approached Esau, what did Jacob do?</Alt>
		<Alt>As Jacob came near to Esau, what did Jacob do?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>According to Jacob, why did he very much want his brother to accept the animals/the greeting gifts?</Original>
		<Alt>According to Jacob, why did he very much want his brother to accept the animals?</Alt>
		<Alt>According to Jacob, why did he very much want his brother to accept the greeting gifts?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>But if the men of Hamor's family did not want/were not willing to be circumcised, what would Jacob's sons do?</Original>
		<Alt>But if the men of Hamor's family did not want to be circumcised, what would Jacob's sons do?</Alt>
		<Alt>But if the men of Hamor's family were not willing to be circumcised, what would Jacob's sons do?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What are some of the things that God said to Jacob at the time of this account/at this time?</Original>
		<Alt>What are some of the things that God said to Jacob at the time of this account?</Alt>
		<Alt>What are some of the things that God said to Jacob at this time?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did Jacob do with Rachel's dead body/corpse?</Original>
		<Alt>What did Jacob do with Rachel's dead body?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Jacob do with Rachel's corpse?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Where did Jacob go at that time/at the time of this account?</Original>
		<Alt>Where did Jacob go at that time?</Alt>
		<Alt>Where did Jacob go at the time of this account?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>About whom is this section/passage of Scripture?</Original>
		<Alt>About whom is this section of Scripture?</Alt>
		<Alt>About whom is this passage of Scripture?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Where were Esau and his descendents at that time/the time of this account?</Original>
		<Alt>Where were Esau and his descendents at that time?</Alt>
		<Alt>Where were Esau and his descendents at the time of this account?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>How many dreams did Joseph recount/relate to his brothers/tell his brothers about?</Original>
		<Alt>How many dreams did Joseph recount?</Alt>
		<Alt>How many dreams did Joseph relate to his brothers?</Alt>
		<Alt>How many dreams did Joseph tell his brothers about?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>For what reason do you think Jacob scolded Joseph when Joseph recounted/told his family about his dreams?</Original>
		<Alt>For what reason do you think Jacob scolded Joseph when Joseph recounted his dreams?</Alt>
		<Alt>For what reason do you think Jacob scolded Joseph when Joseph told his family about his dreams?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>To what place/Where did Jacob say that he would go in his grief?</Original>
		<Alt>To what place did Jacob say that he would go in his grief?</Alt>
		<Alt>Where did Jacob say that he would go in his grief?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What was the cause for which God took Er's life/for which God caused Er to die?</Original>
		<Alt>What was the cause for which God took Er's life?</Alt>
		<Alt>What was the cause for which God caused Er to die?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What was the cause for which God took Onan's life/for which God caused Onan to die?</Original>
		<Alt>What was the cause for which God took Onan's life?</Alt>
		<Alt>What was the cause for which God caused Onan to die?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Joseph was able to prosper/be very successful during this time. What was the cause of that?</Original>
		<Alt>Joseph was able to prosper during this time. What was the cause of that?</Alt>
		<Alt>Joseph was able to be very successful during this time. What was the cause of that?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>In what way was Potiphar affected by God helping Joseph/caring for Joseph?</Original>
		<Alt>In what way was Potiphar affected by God helping Joseph?</Alt>
		<Alt>In what way was Potiphar affected by God caring for Joseph?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What was the only thing that Potiphar had to do for/attend to himself?</Original>
		<Alt>What was the only thing that Potiphar had to do for himself?</Alt>
		<Alt>What was the only thing that Potiphar had to attend to himself?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Although Joseph had done only good, Potiphar put him in jail. Did that mean that God had forgotten about Joseph and was no longer caring for him/watching over him/helping him?</Original>
		<Alt>Although Joseph had done only good, Potiphar put him in jail. Did that mean that God had forgotten about Joseph and was no longer caring for him?</Alt>
		<Alt>Although Joseph had done only good, Potiphar put him in jail. Did that mean that God had forgotten about Joseph and was no longer watching over him?</Alt>
		<Alt>Although Joseph had done only good, Potiphar put him in jail. Did that mean that God had forgotten about Joseph and was no longer helping him?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>According to Joseph, who knows how to interpret dreams/explain the meaning of dreams?</Original>
		<Alt>According to Joseph, who knows how to interpret dreams?</Alt>
		<Alt>According to Joseph, who knows how to explain the meaning of dreams?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Tell me about the dream of the chief drink-server/cup-bearer/the leader of Pharaoh's drink-servers.</Original>
		<Alt>Tell me about the dream of the chief drink-server.</Alt>
		<Alt>Tell me about the dream of the chief cup-bearer.</Alt>
		<Alt>Tell me about the dream of the cup-bearer.</Alt>
		<Alt>Tell me about the dream of the leader of Pharaoh's drink-servers.</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did Paul think about those things which were important to him/he depended on [for God to consider him to be good]?</Original>
		<Alt>What did Paul think about those things which were important to him?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Paul think about those things which he depended on?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Paul think about those things which were important to him for God to consider him to be good?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Paul think about those things which he depended on for God to consider him to be good?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What is the reason that Paul said/considered that all that [he did before to please God] as worthless/like garbage?</Original>
		<Alt>What is the reason that Paul said that all that as worthless?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that Paul said that all that like garbage?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that Paul said that all that he did before to please God as worthless?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that Paul said that all that he did before to please God like garbage?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that Paul considered that all that as worthless?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that Paul considered that all that like garbage?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that Paul considered that all that he did before to please God as worthless?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that Paul considered that all that he did before to please God like garbage?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What will the one/[God] who sits on the throne do?</Original>
		<Alt>What will the one who sits on the throne do?</Alt>
		<Alt>What will God, who sits on the throne, do?</Alt>
		<Alt>What will God do?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did John say about him/[Christ]?</Original>
		<Alt>What did John say about him?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did John say about Christ?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What didn't [God] use to redeem them from the empty/worthless ways that they learned from their ancestors?</Original>
		<Alt>What didn't God use to redeem them from the empty ways that they learned from their ancestors?</Alt>
		<Alt>What didn't God use to redeem them from the Sworthless ways that they learned from their ancestors?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did [the preachers/teachers] preach to them?</Original>
		<Alt>What did the preachers preach to them?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did the teachers preach to them?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>How strongly are they supposed to love pure spiritual milk/[God's word]?</Original>
		<Alt>How strongly are they supposed to love pure spiritual milk?</Alt>
		<Alt>How strongly are they supposed to love God's word?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What is the reason that they should love pure spiritual milk/[God's word] in this way?</Original>
		<Alt>What is the reason that they should love pure spiritual milk in this way?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that they should love God's word in this way?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What other reason did Peter give for why they should love pure spiritual milk/[God's word]?</Original>
		<Alt>What other reason did Peter give for why they should love pure spiritual milk?</Alt>
		<Alt>What other reason did Peter give for why they should love God's word?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Since [God] has appointed [Christ] as the cornerstone in Zion, what can anyone who trusts/believes in him be sure of?</Original>
		<Alt>Since God has appointed Christ as the cornerstone in Zion, what can anyone who trusts in him be sure of?</Alt>
		<Alt>Since God has appointed Christ as the cornerstone in Zion, what can anyone who believes in him be sure of?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>If these elders followed/obeyed Peter's advice, what will happen when [Christ], who is the Chief Shepherd, appears?</Original>
		<Alt>If these elders followed Peter's advice, what will happen when the Chief Shepherd appears?</Alt>
		<Alt>If these elders followed Peter's advice, what will happen when Christ, who is the Chief Shepherd, appears?</Alt>
		<Alt>If these elders followed Peter's advice, what will happen when Christ appears?</Alt>
		<Alt>If these elders obeyed Peter's advice, what will happen when the Chief Shepherd appears?</Alt>
		<Alt>If these elders obeyed Peter's advice, what will happen when Christ, who is the Chief Shepherd, appears?</Alt>
		<Alt>If these elders obeyed Peter's advice, what will happen when Christ appears?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>How did they know that Peter [and the other apostles] were not making up stories when they told them about the power/might of the Lord Jesus Christ and of his coming/return?</Original>
		<Alt>How did they know that Peter was not making up stories when they told them about the power of the Lord Jesus Christ and of his coming?</Alt>
		<Alt>How did they know that Peter was not making up stories when they told them about the power of the Lord Jesus Christ and of his return?</Alt>
		<Alt>How did they know that Peter was not making up stories when they told them about the might of the Lord Jesus Christ and of his coming?</Alt>
		<Alt>How did they know that Peter was not making up stories when they told them about the might of the Lord Jesus Christ and of his return?</Alt>
		<Alt>How did they know that Peter and the other apostles were not making up stories when they told them about the power of the Lord Jesus Christ and of his coming?</Alt>
		<Alt>How did they know that Peter and the other apostles were not making up stories when they told them about the power of the Lord Jesus Christ and of his return?</Alt>
		<Alt>How did they know that Peter and the other apostles were not making up stories when they told them about the might of the Lord Jesus Christ and of his coming?</Alt>
		<Alt>How did they know that Peter and the other apostles were not making up stories when they told them about the might of the Lord Jesus Christ and of his return?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Who did those people/the Pharisees not know?</Original>
		<Alt>Who did those people not know?</Alt>
		<Alt>Who did the Pharisees not know?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What could they do so that God forgave their sins/they would not die in their sins?</Original>
		<Alt>What could they do so that God forgave their sins?</Alt>
		<Alt>What could they do so they would not die in their sins?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What was the difference between Jesus and those people/the Pharisees?</Original>
		<Alt>What was the difference between Jesus and those people?</Alt>
		<Alt>What was the difference between Jesus and the Pharisees?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>According to Jesus what would they know after the people crucified him/put him on a cross?</Original>
		<Alt>According to Jesus what would they know after the people crucified him?</Alt>
		<Alt>According to Jesus what would they know after the people put him on a cross?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did Jesus tell the Jews/them?</Original>
		<Alt>What did Jesus tell the Jews?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Jesus tell them?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did the people/they ask him?</Original>
		<Alt>What did the people ask him?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did they ask him?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What was the blind man's/his answer?</Original>
		<Alt>What was the blind man's answer?</Alt>
		<Alt>What was his answer?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What was his purpose for dying/laying down his life?</Original>
		<Alt>What was his purpose for dying?</Alt>
		<Alt>What was his purpose for laying down his life?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Who was able to take Jesus' life from him/ kill him?</Original>
		<Alt>Who was able to take Jesus' life from him?</Alt>
		<Alt>Who was able to kill Jesus?</Alt>
		<Alt>Who was able to kill him?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What is the reason that the Pharisees said that they were not succeeding/not able to arrest Jesus? </Original>
		<Alt>What is the reason that the Pharisees said that they were not succeeding? </Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that the Pharisees said that they were not able to arrest Jesus? </Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>For whose benefit had God/the voice spoken?</Original>
		<Alt>For whose benefit had God spoken?</Alt>
		<Alt>For whose benefit had the voice spoken?</Alt>
	</Alternative>	
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did those people/Jewish leaders love more?</Original>
		<Alt>What did those people love more?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did those Jewish leaders love more?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>How many of the disciples there were not clean/did not have good hearts?</Original>
		<Alt>How many of the disciples there were not clean?</Alt>
		<Alt>How many of the disciples there did not have good hearts?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did he ask them/his disciples?</Original>
		<Alt>What did he ask them?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did he ask his disciples?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>In what way was Jesus changing/going to change the way he told them about his Father?</Original>
		<Alt>In what way was Jesus changing the way he told them about his Father?</Alt>
		<Alt>In what way was Jesus going to change the way he told them about his Father?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What would be the result of the Father honoring/showing the power of/glorifying his Son?</Original>
		<Alt>What would be the result of the Father honoring his Son?</Alt>
		<Alt>What would be the result of the Father showing the power of his Son?</Alt>
		<Alt>What would be the result of the Father glorifying his Son?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did those men/the disciples know?</Original>
		<Alt>What did those men know?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did the disciples know?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did those men/the disciples know and believe about Jesus?</Original>
		<Alt>What did those men know and believe about Jesus?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did the disciples know and believe about Jesus?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Where were those men/the disciples going?</Original>
		<Alt>Where were those men going?</Alt>
		<Alt>Where were the disciples going?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>In what way would the Father protect those men/the disciples?</Original>
		<Alt>In what way would the Father protect those men?</Alt>
		<Alt>In what way would the Father protect the disciples?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Which of the men/the disciples was lost?</Original>
		<Alt>Which of the men was lost?</Alt>
		<Alt>Which of the disciples was lost?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What is the reason that Jesus prayed in that way for those men/the disciples?</Original>
		<Alt>What is the reason that Jesus prayed in that way for those men?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that Jesus prayed in that way for the disciples?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did the people of the world feel about those men/the disciples?</Original>
		<Alt>What did the people of the world feel about those men?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did the people of the world feel about the disciples?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What would be the result of their being in agreement/united?</Original>
		<Alt>What would be the result of their being in agreement?</Alt>
		<Alt>What would be the result of their being united?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did Jesus give to those people/the disciples?</Original>
		<Alt>What did Jesus give to those people?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Jesus give to the disciples?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Who gave those people/the disciples/believers to Jesus?</Original>
		<Alt>Who gave those people to Jesus?</Alt>
		<Alt>Who gave the disciples to Jesus?</Alt>
		<Alt>Who gave the believers to Jesus?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did Jesus want for those people/believers/the disciples?</Original>
		<Alt>What did Jesus want for those people?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Jesus want for those believers?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Jesus want for the disciples?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Who was Jesus making known to those people/the disciples?</Original>
		<Alt>Who was Jesus making known to those people?</Alt>
		<Alt>Who was Jesus making known to the disciples?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did Pilate say to Jesus after that/next?</Original>
		<Alt>What did Pilate say to Jesus after that?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Pilate say to Jesus next?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What does a person do who belongs/is committed to the truth?</Original>
		<Alt>What does a person do who belongs to the truth?</Alt>
		<Alt>What does a person do who is committed to the truth?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did the soldiers/they do to alleviate/quench Jesus' thirst?</Original>
		<Alt>What did the soldiers do to alleviate Jesus' thirst?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did the soldiers do to quench Jesus' thirst?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did they do to alleviate Jesus' thirst?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did they do to quench Jesus' thirst?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>How many times had Jesus appeared/shown himself to his disciples?</Original>
		<Alt>How many times had Jesus appeared to his disciples?</Alt>
		<Alt>How many times had Jesus shown himself to his disciples?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did Jesus tell him to do then/that time?</Original>
		<Alt>What did Jesus tell him to do then?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Jesus tell him to do that time?</Alt>
	</Alternative>	
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What had that disciple, whom Jesus loved, done at another time/in the past?</Original>
		<Alt>What had that disciple, whom Jesus loved, done at another time?</Alt>
		<Alt>What had that disciple, whom Jesus loved, done in the past?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What do we know about what he testified/his testimony?</Original>
		<Alt>What do we know about what he testified?</Alt>
		<Alt>What do we know about his testimony?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Even though the readers knew how the Lord had dealt with/punished those who acted wickedly in the past, what did Jude want to do?</Original>
		<Alt>Even though the readers knew how the Lord had dealt with those who acted wickedly in the past, what did Jude want to do?</Alt>
		<Alt>Even though the readers knew how the Lord had punished those who acted wickedly in the past, what did Jude want to do?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What do you know about these kind of angels/fallen angels?</Original>
		<Alt>What do you know about these kind of angels?</Alt>
		<Alt>What do you know about fallen angels?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Who were the men spoken of/mentioned here who practiced the same kinds of sins that are mentioned above in verses 5-7?</Original>
		<Alt>Who were the men spoken of here who practiced the same kinds of sins that are mentioned above in verses 5-7?</Alt>
		<Alt>Who were the men mentioned here who practiced the same kinds of sins that are mentioned above in verses 5-7?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Unlike Michael, what did those men/false teachers do?</Original>
		<Alt>Unlike Michael, what did those men do?</Alt>
		<Alt>Unlike Michael, what did those false teachers do?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>In what way were those false teachers/men like wild animals?</Original>
		<Alt>In what way were those false teachers like wild animals?</Alt>
		<Alt>In what way were those men like wild animals?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did the apostles warn the Christians will happen in the last days/when the world is about to end?</Original>
		<Alt>What did the apostles warn the Christians will happen in the last days?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did the apostles warn the Christians will happen when the world is about to end?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did Elizabeth feel was the reason that Mary was so blessed/fortunate/in such a happy state?</Original>
		<Alt>What did Elizabeth feel was the reason that Mary was so blessed?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Elizabeth feel was the reason that Mary was so fortunate?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Elizabeth feel was the reason that Mary was in such a happy state?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>How did Simeon know he would not die before he saw the Christ/(the Messiah)?</Original>
		<Alt>How did Simeon know he would not die before he saw the Christ?</Alt>
		<Alt>How did Simeon know he would not die before he saw the Messiah?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>How many people came to where John was staying in that uninhabited area/wilderness/desert?</Original>
		<Alt>How many people came to where John was staying in that uninhabited area?</Alt>
		<Alt>How many people came to where John was staying in that wilderness?</Alt>
		<Alt>How many people came to where John was staying in that desert?</Alt>
	</Alternative>	
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Why did Jesus go into an uninhabited area/into the wilderness/desert?</Original>
		<Alt>Why did Jesus go into an uninhabited area?</Alt>
		<Alt>Why did Jesus go into the wilderness?</Alt>
		<Alt>Why did Jesus go into the desert?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>There were many people sick with leprosy/bad skin disease in Israel when Elisha lived. Whom did God bring to Elisha to be made well?</Original>
		<Alt>There were many people sick with leprosy in Israel when Elisha lived. Whom did God bring to Elisha to be made well?</Alt>
		<Alt>There were many people sick with a bad skin disease in Israel when Elisha lived. Whom did God bring to Elisha to be made well?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What do the people who speak your language say are the characteristics/signs to know a spirit is a demon/an evil spirit?</Original>
		<Alt>What do the people who speak your language say are the characteristics to know a spirit is a demon?</Alt>
		<Alt>What do the people who speak your language say are the characteristics to know a spirit is an evil spirit?</Alt>
		<Alt>What do the people who speak your language say are the signs to know a spirit is a demon?</Alt>
		<Alt>What do the people who speak your language say are the signs to know a spirit is an evil spirit?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did Jesus strongly warn/sternly command those demons/evil spirits not to do?</Original>
		<Alt>What did Jesus strongly warn those demons not to do?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Jesus strongly warn those evil spirits not to do?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Jesus sternly command those demons not to do?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Jesus sternly command those evil spirits not to do?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>After Jesus healed the man who had leprosy/a bad skin disease, how did people respond?</Original>
		<Alt>After Jesus healed the man who had leprosy, how did people respond?</Alt>
		<Alt>After Jesus healed the man who had a bad skin disease, how did people respond?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>How did Jesus and the man sick with leprosy/the bad skin disease meet?</Original>
		<Alt>How did Jesus and the man sick with leprosy meet?</Alt>
		<Alt>How did Jesus and the man sick with the bad skin disease meet?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Why did Jesus go to an uninhabited area/into the wilderness/desert?</Original>
		<Alt>Why did Jesus go to an uninhabited area?</Alt>
		<Alt>Why did Jesus go into the wilderness?</Alt>
		<Alt>Why did Jesus go into the desert?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Why were the Pharisees and the teachers of the Law/scribes upset when Jesus said that he had forgiven the sick man's sins?</Original>
		<Alt>Why were the Pharisees and teachers of the Law upset when Jesus said that he had forgiven the sick man's sins?</Alt>
		<Alt>Why were the Pharisees and scribes upset when Jesus said that he had forgiven the sick man's sins?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	
	<Alternative>
		<Original>When Jesus ate food with many other people at Levi's house, how did the Pharisees and teachers of the Law/scribes respond?</Original>
		<Alt>When Jesus ate food with many other people at Levi's house, how did the Pharisees and teachers of the Law respond?</Alt>
		<Alt>When Jesus ate food with many other people at Levi's house, how did the Pharisees and scribes respond?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Why did the Pharisees and teachers of the Law/scribes complain to the disciples?</Original>
		<Alt>Why did the Pharisees and teachers of the Law complain to the disciples?</Alt>
		<Alt>Why did the Pharisees and scribes complain to the disciples?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What comparison, do you think, was Jesus making when he used the picture language/parable about the new clothing and the old clothing and a patch?</Original>
		<Alt>What comparison, do you think, was Jesus making when he used the picture language about the new clothing and the old clothing and a patch?</Alt>
		<Alt>What comparison, do you think, was Jesus making when he used the parable about the new clothing and the old clothing and a patch?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>If the people who speak your language use picture language/parables, tell me one of those stories and then tell me its meaning.</Original>
		<Alt>If the people who speak your language use picture language, tell me one of those stories and then tell me its meaning.</Alt>
		<Alt>If the people who speak your language use parables, tell me one of those stories and then tell me its meaning.</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Why were the Pharisees and the teachers of the Law/scribes carefully watching Jesus?</Original>
		<Alt>Why were the Pharisees and teachers of the Law carefully watching Jesus?</Alt>
		<Alt>Why were the Pharisees and scribes carefully watching Jesus?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What are some of the characteristics of those whom Jesus says are happy/feel blessed by God?</Original>
		<Alt>What are some of the characteristics of those whom Jesus says are happy?</Alt>
		<Alt>What are some of the characteristics of those whom Jesus says are feel blessed by God?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Why would the disciples know they should expect this kind of trouble/bad treatment?</Original>
		<Alt>Why would the disciples know they should expect this kind of trouble?</Alt>
		<Alt>Why would the disciples know they should expect this kind of bad treatment?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Why are the people who have these troubles called happy/blessed by God?</Original>
		<Alt>Why are the people who have these troubles called happy?</Alt>
		<Alt>Why are the people who have these troubles called blessed by God?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What do you think was the reason that the person selling the grain (6:38) would pour it into the buyer's lap/onto the buyer's clothing?</Original>
		<Alt>What do you think was the reason that the person selling the grain (6:38) would pour it into the buyer's lap?</Alt>
		<Alt>What do you think was the reason that the person selling the grain (6:38) would pour it onto the buyer's clothing?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Why did the army officer himself not want to inconvenience/cause any problem for Jesus?</Original>
		<Alt>Why did the army officer himself not want to inconvenience for Jesus?</Alt>
		<Alt>Why did the army officer himself not want to cause any problem for Jesus?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What does it mean that someone believes/has faith in another person?</Original>
		<Alt>What does it mean that someone believes in another person?</Alt>
		<Alt>What does it mean that someone has faith in another person?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>How did Jesus' ministry relate to/compare with John's ministry?</Original>
		<Alt>How did Jesus' ministry relate to John's ministry?</Alt>
		<Alt>How did Jesus' ministry compare with John's ministry?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Why had people gone into the uninhabited area/wilderness/desert to see John?</Original>
		<Alt>Why had people gone into the uninhabited area to see John?</Alt>
		<Alt>Why had people gone into the wilderness to see John?</Alt>
		<Alt>Why had people gone into the desert to see John?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>How did the Pharisees and the experts in the Law of Moses respond when they heard Jesus speak of John like this/when they heard John speak like this?</Original>
		<Alt>How did the Pharisees and the experts in the Law of Moses respond when they heard Jesus speak of John like this?</Alt>
		<Alt>How did the Pharisees and the experts in the Law of Moses respond when they heard John speak like this?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did the demons keep on urging/earnestly ask/strongly request Jesus not to do to them?</Original>
		<Alt>What did the demons keep on urging Jesus not to do to them?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did the demons earnestly ask Jesus not to do to them?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did the demons strongly request Jesus not to do to them?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Who went with Jesus into Jairus' house/the room where the girl was?</Original>
		<Alt>Who went with Jesus into Jairus' house?</Alt>
		<Alt>Who went with Jesus into the room where the girl was?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did Joseph do with all the money he received from the sale of the grain/from selling the grain?</Original>
		<Alt>What did Joseph do with all the money he received from the sale of the grain?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Joseph do with all the money he received from selling the grain?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>How much longer did Jacob live/How long did Jacob live, after he and his family moved to Egypt?</Original>
		<Alt>How much longer did Jacob live, after he and his family moved to Egypt?</Alt>
		<Alt>How long did Jacob live, after he and his family moved to Egypt?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What name did Jacob use to refer to God at that time/in this account?</Original>
		<Alt>What name did Jacob use to refer to God at that time?</Alt>
		<Alt>What name did Jacob use to refer to God in this account?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What do you think that Jacob meant, when he said that Reuben was unstable as water/like a flood/unruly as the waves of the sea?</Original>
		<Alt>What do you think that Jacob meant, when he said that Reuben was unstable as water?</Alt>
		<Alt>What do you think that Jacob meant, when he said that Reuben was like a flood?</Alt>
		<Alt>What do you think that Jacob meant, when he said that Reuben was unruly as the waves of the sea?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did Jacob say about Joseph in relationship to/in comparison to his brothers?</Original>
		<Alt>What did Jacob say about Joseph in relationship to to his brothers?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Jacob say about Joseph in comparison to his brothers?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What do you think that Jacob meant by comparing Benjamin to a ferocious/fierce wolf/a wild dog?</Original>
		<Alt>What do you think that Jacob meant by comparing Benjamin to a ferocious wolf?</Alt>
		<Alt>What do you think that Jacob meant by comparing Benjamin to a fierce wolf?</Alt>
		<Alt>What do you think that Jacob meant by comparing Benjamin to a wild dog?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>When the local people saw that funeral/saw all the people mourning, what did they do?</Original>
		<Alt>When the local people saw that funeral, what did they do?</Alt>
		<Alt>When the local people saw all the people mourning, what did they do?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What specifically did Joseph say about the good that God caused through/by means of the hardships/the evil events that happened to him?</Original>
		<Alt>What specifically did Joseph say about the good that God caused through the hardships that happened to him?</Alt>
		<Alt>What specifically did Joseph say about the good that God caused through the evil events that happened to him?</Alt>
		<Alt>What specifically did Joseph say about the good that God caused by means of the hardships that happened to him?</Alt>
		<Alt>What specifically did Joseph say about the good that God caused by means of the evil events that happened to him?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>It says, "He sat down on the right hand of the majesty in heaven/the right side of God, the supreme Power. How would you explain that to someone?</Original>
		<Alt>It says, "He sat down on the right hand of the majesty in heaven, the supreme Power. How would you explain that to someone?</Alt>
		<Alt>It says, "He sat down on the right side of God, the supreme Power. How would you explain that to someone?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What can we learn/what does it say about the Son here?</Original>
		<Alt>What can we learn about the Son here?</Alt>
		<Alt>What does it say about the Son here?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>It says God called his Son, "Lord." Why do you think the writer told us that? (or, What does that teach/show us?)</Original>
		<Alt>It says God called his Son, "Lord." Why do you think the writer told us that? (or, What does that show us?)</Alt>
		<Alt>It says God called his Son, "Lord." Why do you think the writer told us that? (or, What does that teach us?)</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>How did they confirm it/prove it to be true? How did people know that what they said was true?</Original>
		<Alt>How did they confirm it to be true? How did people know that what they said was true?</Alt>
		<Alt>How did they prove it to be true? How did people know that what they said was true?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What does this say/tell us about God?</Original>
		<Alt>What does this say about God?</Alt>
		<Alt>What does this tell us about God?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>The author reminds them that they have been chosen/set apart for God. Why do you think he does that here? (Optional question, few readers can answer.)</Original>
		<Alt>The author reminds them that they have been chosen for God. Why do you think he does that here? (Optional question, few readers can answer.)</Alt>
		<Alt>The author reminds them that they have been set apart for God. Why do you think he does that here? (Optional question, few readers can answer.)</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>The author tells them to be careful/to watch. What are they to watch for? (or, The part before talked about the Israelite ancestors. Why do you think he was talking about them?) (or, What does this part have to do with what he just said about the ancestors?)</Original>
		<Alt>The author tells them to be careful. What are they to watch for? (or, The part before talked about the Israelite ancestors. Why do you think he was talking about them?) (or, What does this part have to do with what he just said about the ancestors?)</Alt>
		<Alt>The author tells them to watch. What are they to watch for? (or, The part before talked about the Israelite ancestors. Why do you think he was talking about them?) (or, What does this part have to do with what he just said about the ancestors?)</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Why is the author telling them what David said? or What do these words of David tell/teach them about the rest God gives his people?</Original>
		<Alt>Why is the author telling them what David said? or What do these words of David teach them about the rest God gives his people?</Alt>
		<Alt>Why is the author telling them what David said? or What do these words of David tell them about the rest God gives his people?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>It says God made him a priest after the order of/like Melchizedek. What do you think that means?</Original>
		<Alt>It says God made him a priest after the order of Melchizedek. What do you think that means?</Alt>
		<Alt>It says God made him a priest  like Melchizedek. What do you think that means?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Why is the author telling us about a field/ground?</Original>
		<Alt>Why is the author telling us about a field?</Alt>
		<Alt>Why is the author telling us about ground?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Why? (or, the translator may need to ask what each part of the metaphor represents and "What does God do with a field/ground which produces well?")</Original>
		<Alt>Why? (or, the translator may need to ask what each part of the metaphor represents and "What does God do with a field which produces well?")</Alt>
		<Alt>Why? (or, the translator may need to ask what each part of the metaphor represents and "What does God do with ground which produces well?")</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What else? or How/Why did he become a priest then?</Original>
		<Alt>What else? or How did he become a priest then?</Alt>
		<Alt>What else? or Why did he become a priest then?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What else does it say about a way to come to God/be made acceptable to God?</Original>
		<Alt>What else does it say about a way to come to God?</Alt>
		<Alt>What else does it say about a way to be made acceptable to God?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What kind of system/what way do the earthly priests offer sacrifices?</Original>
		<Alt>According to what kind of system do the earthly priests offer sacrifices?</Alt>
		<Alt>Under what kind of system do the earthly priests offer sacrifices?</Alt>
		<Alt>What way do the earthly priests offer sacrifices?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>In what way/why was it not adequate?</Original>
		<Alt>In what way was it not adequate?</Alt>
		<Alt>Why was it not adequate?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What about past sins? How should they feel/what should they think about them?</Original>
		<Alt>What about past sins? How should they feel about them?</Alt>
		<Alt>What about past sins? What should they think about them?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What does it say about one another/how people should live with one another?</Original>
		<Alt>What does it say about one another?</Alt>
		<Alt>What does it say about how people should live with one another?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Briefly tell in your own words what the author said. What is faith/what does it mean to believe God?</Original>
		<Alt>Briefly tell in your own words what the author said.</Alt>
		<Alt>Briefly tell in your own words what the author said. What is faith?</Alt>
		<Alt>Briefly tell in your own words what the author said. What does it mean to believe God?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is faith?</Alt>
		<Alt>What does it mean to believe God?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>How much/to what extent did he believe/trust God?</Original>
		<Alt>How much did he believe God?</Alt>
		<Alt>How much did he trust God?</Alt>
		<Alt>To what extent did he believe God?</Alt>
		<Alt>To what extent did he trust God?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>He says they are to leave sin/stop sinning. What else does he say about the sin?</Original>
		<Alt>He says they are to leave sin. What else does he say about the sin?</Alt>
		<Alt>He says they are to stop sinning. What else does he say about the sin?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>If we do accept his discipline, what will happen/be the result?</Original>
		<Alt>If we do accept his discipline, what will happen?</Alt>
		<Alt>If we do accept his discipline, what will be the result?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>If they set a good example for those who are weak, what will happen/be the result?</Original>
		<Alt>If they set a good example for those who are weak, what will happen?</Alt>
		<Alt>If they set a good example for those who are weak, what will be the result?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What does he say to them/want/tell them to do? (Reread and follow with "What else?" as necessary.)</Original>
		<Alt>What does he say to them? (Reread and follow with "What else?" as necessary.)</Alt>
		<Alt>What does he want them to do? (Reread and follow with "What else?" as necessary.)</Alt>
		<Alt>What does he tell them to do? (Reread and follow with "What else?" as necessary.)</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did he say about it/taking care of them?</Original>
		<Alt>What did he say about it?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did he say about taking care of them?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What does he say about an altar/a place were people's sins are paid for/the Cross on which Christ died?</Original>
		<Alt>What does he say about an altar?</Alt>
		<Alt>What does he say about a place were people's sins are paid for?</Alt>
		<Alt>What does he say about the Cross on which Christ died?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What should they do if they lack wisdom/the wisdom that God gives?</Original>
		<Alt>What should they do if they lack wisdom?</Alt>
		<Alt>What should they do if they lack the wisdom that God gives?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What value/use is it for a person to say/claim that he is a Christian, but he does not control what he says/speaks bad/evil things?</Original>
		<Alt>What value is it for a person to say that he is a Christian, but he does not control what he says?</Alt>
		<Alt>What value is it for a person to say that he is a Christian, but he speaks bad things?</Alt>
		<Alt>What value is it for a person to say that he is a Christian, but he speaks evil things?</Alt>
		<Alt>What value is it for a person to claim that he is a Christian, but he does not control what he says?</Alt>
		<Alt>What value is it for a person to claim that he is a Christian, but he speaks bad things?</Alt>
		<Alt>What value is it for a person to claim that he is a Christian, but he speaks evil things?</Alt>
		<Alt>What use is it for a person to say that he is a Christian, but he does not control what he says?</Alt>
		<Alt>What use is it for a person to say that he is a Christian, but he speaks bad things?</Alt>
		<Alt>What use is it for a person to say that he is a Christian, but he speaks evil things?</Alt>
		<Alt>What use is it for a person to claim that he is a Christian, but he does not control what he says?</Alt>
		<Alt>What use is it for a person to claim that he is a Christian, but he speaks bad things?</Alt>
		<Alt>What use is it for a person to claim that he is a Christian, but he speaks evil things?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>How do we know that the rich are not superior to/better than the poor?</Original>
		<Alt>How do we know that the rich are not superior to the poor?</Alt>
		<Alt>How do we know that the rich are not better than the poor?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>But what if they show favoritism/treat some people in different ways according to how they look?</Original>
		<Alt>But what if they show favoritism according to how they look?</Alt>
		<Alt>But what if they treat some people in different ways according to how they look?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What place of water/water supply can pour out both sweet and bitter water from the same place?</Original>
		<Alt>What place of water can pour out both sweet and bitter water from the same place?</Alt>
		<Alt>What water supply can pour out both sweet and bitter water from the same place?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>If a person claims that he is wise, but he does the things mentioned in verse 14, what did James say about the thinking/claim of a person like that?</Original>
		<Alt>If a person claims that he is wise, but he does the things mentioned in verse 14, what did James say about the thinking of a person like that?</Alt>
		<Alt>If a person claims that he is wise, but he does the things mentioned in verse 14, what did James say about the claim of a person like that?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What happens when those who promote peace/peacemakers give advice in a peaceful manner?</Original>
		<Alt>What happens when those who promote peace give advice in a peaceful manner?</Alt>
		<Alt>What happens when peacemakers give advice in a peaceful manner?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did he say about another person/this other person who was coming?</Original>
		<Alt>What did he say about another person who was coming?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did he say about this other person who was coming?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did John's two disciples/the two disciples of John do?</Original>
		<Alt>What did John's two disciples do?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did the two disciples of John do?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What were the results of Jesus doing/performing this miracle/miraculous sign?</Original>
		<Alt>What were the results of Jesus doing this miracle?</Alt>
		<Alt>What were the results of Jesus doing this miraculous sign?</Alt>
		<Alt>What were the results of Jesus performing this miracle?</Alt>
		<Alt>What were the results of Jesus performing this miraculous sign?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did Jesus do to stop that/the wrong activity in the temple court?</Original>
		<Alt>What did Jesus do to stop that wrong activity in the temple court?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Jesus do to stop the wrong activity in the temple court?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What Old Testament scripture did his disciples remember after seeing what he did/had done in the temple?</Original>
		<Alt>What Old Testament scripture did his disciples remember after seeing what he did in the temple?</Alt>
		<Alt>What Old Testament scripture did his disciples remember after seeing what he had done in the temple?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did Jesus do toward the people who trusted in his name/believed in him?</Original>
		<Alt>What did Jesus do toward the people who trusted in his name?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Jesus do toward the people who believed in him?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What do you think it means if someone perishes/for someone to perish? </Original>
		<Alt>What do you think it means if someone perishes? </Alt>
		<Alt>What do you think it means for someone to perish? </Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What do you think it means if someone condemns someone else/for someone to condemn someone else?</Original>
		<Alt>What do you think it means if someone condemns someone else?</Alt>
		<Alt>What do you think it means for someone to condemn someone else?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What does a person do who is doing true deeds/living in truth /living truthfully?</Original>
		<Alt>What does a person do who is doing true deeds?</Alt>
		<Alt>What does a person do who is living in truth?</Alt>
		<Alt>What does a person do who is living truthfully?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What was Jesus' reason for always doing as he did/working?</Original>
		<Alt>What was Jesus' reason for always doing as he did?</Alt>
		<Alt>What was Jesus' reason for always working?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What happened when Jesus entered/got into the boat?</Original>
		<Alt>What happened when Jesus entered the boat?</Alt>
		<Alt>What happened when Jesus got into the boat?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What feast was near at hand/close/approaching/about to start?</Original>
		<Alt>What feast was near at hand?</Alt>
		<Alt>What feast was close?</Alt>
		<Alt>What feast was approaching?</Alt>
		<Alt>What feast was about to start?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>For whom were the Jews/Jewish leaders watching/searching at the feast?</Original>
		<Alt>For whom were the Jews watching at the feast?</Alt>
		<Alt>For whom were the Jews searching at the feast?</Alt>
		<Alt>For whom were the Jewish leaders watching at the feast?</Alt>
		<Alt>For whom were the Jewish leaders searching at the feast?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What do you think it means that God glorified/for God to glorify Jesus?</Original>
		<Alt>What do you think it means that God glorified Jesus?</Alt>
		<Alt>What do you think it means for God to glorify Jesus?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did they/the Pharisees ask Jesus?</Original>
		<Alt>What did they ask Jesus?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did the Pharisees ask Jesus?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Why did the people laugh at/make fun of Jesus?</Original>
		<Alt>Why did the people laugh at Jesus?</Alt>
		<Alt>Why did the people make fun of Jesus?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Jesus strongly warned/sternly commanded his disciples not to tell anyone what they knew about him. What did they know?</Original>
		<Alt>Jesus strongly warned his disciples not to tell anyone what they knew about him. What did they know?</Alt>
		<Alt>Jesus sternly commanded his disciples not to tell anyone what they knew about him. What did they know?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What do you think it means for people today to take up/carry one's cross?</Original>
		<Alt>What do you think it means for people today to take up one's cross?</Alt>
		<Alt>What do you think it means for people today to carry one's cross?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Who did Jesus say would be the greatest/most important disciple? -OR- Who did Jesus say would be the greatest/most important person in the kingdom of God?</Original>
		<Alt>Who did Jesus say would be the greatest disciple?</Alt>
		<Alt>Who did Jesus say would be the most important disciple?</Alt>
		<Alt>Who did Jesus say would be the greatest person in the kingdom of God?</Alt>
		<Alt>Who did Jesus say would be the most important person in the kingdom of God?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Whom did Jesus say should feel happy/blessed by God?</Original>
		<Alt>Whom did Jesus say should feel happy?</Alt>
		<Alt>Whom did Jesus say should feel blessed by God?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>How does a person forgive another person who is indebted to him/who has sinned against him?</Original>
		<Alt>How does a person forgive another person who has sinned against him?</Alt>
		<Alt>How does a person forgive another person who is indebted to him?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Who did the woman say was blessed/truly happy?</Original>
		<Alt>Who did the woman say was blessed?</Alt>
		<Alt>Who did the woman say was truly happy?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Who did Jesus say were even more blessed/happier than his mother?</Original>
		<Alt>Who did Jesus say were even more blessed than his mother?</Alt>
		<Alt>Who did Jesus say were even happier than his mother?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>In verse 39 Jesus said that the Pharisees' (centers of emotions, thoughts or belief) were very greedy/full of greedy actions. What does he say that they should do to show that they were clean inside (that is, they were free from sin)?</Original>
		<Alt>In verse 39 Jesus said that the Pharisees' (centers of emotions, thoughts or belief) were very greedy. What does he say that they should do to show that they were clean inside (that is, they were free from sin)?</Alt>
		<Alt>In verse 39 Jesus said that the Pharisees' (centers of emotions, thoughts or belief) were full of greedy actions. What does he say that they should do to show that they were clean inside (that is, they were free from sin)?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>While the Pharisees and teachers of the Law/scribes were opposing Jesus, what was happening with the people who came to listen to Jesus?</Original>
		<Alt>While the Pharisees and teachers of the Law were opposing Jesus, what was happening with the people who came to listen to Jesus?</Alt>
		<Alt>While the Pharisees and scribes were opposing Jesus, what was happening with the people who came to listen to Jesus?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What will Jesus, the Son of Man, do when a person acknowledges/openly says to people that he believes that Jesus is the savior?</Original>
		<Alt>What will Jesus, the Son of Man, do when a person acknowledges that he believes that Jesus is the savior?</Alt>
		<Alt>What will Jesus, the Son of Man, do when a person openly says to people that he believes that Jesus is the savior?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Since God has been pleased already to give blessings related to his kingdom/his ruling over us and providing for us, what should the people who are in God's kingdom do?</Original>
		<Alt>Since God has been pleased already to give blessings related to his kingdom, what should the people who are in God's kingdom do?</Alt>
		<Alt>Since God has been pleased already to give blessings related to his ruling over us and providing for us, what should the people who are in God's kingdom do?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Since God does that for birds, which do not get ready for the dry time/cold time when no new food will grow, what should that show to the disciples?</Original>
		<Alt>Since God does that for birds, which do not get ready for the dry time when no new food will grow, what should that show to the disciples?</Alt>
		<Alt>Since God does that for birds, which do not get ready for the cold time when no new food will grow, what should that show to the disciples?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>How will those servants/slaves whom the master finds ready and waiting for him be fortunate/made very happy?</Original>
		<Alt>How will those servants whom the master finds ready and waiting for him be fortunate?</Alt>
		<Alt>How will those servants whom the master finds ready and waiting for him be made very happy?</Alt>
		<Alt>How will those slaves whom the master finds ready and waiting for him be fortunate?</Alt>
		<Alt>How will those slaves whom the master finds ready and waiting for him be made very happy?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>To what time, do you think, was Jesus referring when the people of Jerusalem/the Jews would finally ask the Lord God to bless him? (35)</Original>
		<Alt>To what time, do you think, was Jesus referring when the people of Jerusalem would finally ask the Lord God to bless him? (35)</Alt>
		<Alt>To what time, do you think, was Jesus referring when the Jews would finally ask the Lord God to bless him? (35)</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What do you think was the reason that the Pharisees and the experts in the Law did not answer Jesus either time he asked them a question/made a strong statement to them? (3-4, 5-6)</Original>
		<Alt>What do you think was the reason that the Pharisees and the experts in the Law did not answer Jesus either time he asked them a question? (3-4, 5-6)</Alt>
		<Alt>What do you think was the reason that the Pharisees and the experts in the Law did not answer Jesus either time he made a strong statement to them? (3-4, 5-6)</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did Jesus say might happen if a guest sat in/chose the most honored place at a wedding feast?</Original>
		<Alt>What did Jesus say might happen if a guest sat in the most honored place at a wedding feast?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Jesus say might happen if a guest chose the most honored place at a wedding feast?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Of what do you think this great feast/banquet is a picture?</Original>
		<Alt>Of what do you think this great feast is a picture?</Alt>
		<Alt>Of what do you think this banquet is a picture?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>When a person is serious about following Jesus, how must he regard/think about his family?</Original>
		<Alt>When a person is serious about following Jesus, how must he regard his family?</Alt>
		<Alt>When a person is serious about following Jesus, how must he think about his family?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>How must that person regard/think about his own life and the things he hopes will happen to him?</Original>
		<Alt>How must that person regard his own life and the things he hopes will happen to him?</Alt>
		<Alt>How must that person think about his own life and the things he hopes will happen to him?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did Jesus say about God punishing a person who tempts/causes another person to sin?</Original>
		<Alt>What did Jesus say about God punishing a person who tempts another person to sin?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Jesus say about God punishing a person who causes another person to sin?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>God had told Moses that a person who had been healed of leprosy/bad skin disease should show his skin to a priest (see Lev. 13:9, 16-17, and 14:1-9). What happened to those ten men when they obeyed Jesus and started to go to a priest while they were still sick?</Original>
		<Alt>God had told Moses that a person who had been healed of leprosy should show his skin to a priest (see Lev. 13:9, 16-17, and 14:1-9). What happened to those ten men when they obeyed Jesus and started to go to a priest while they were still sick?</Alt>
		<Alt>God had told Moses that a person who had been healed of bad skin disease should show his skin to a priest (see Lev. 13:9, 16-17, and 14:1-9). What happened to those ten men when they obeyed Jesus and started to go to a priest while they were still sick?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did Jesus say was the cause of the Samaritan man being healed/being saved?</Original>
		<Alt>What did Jesus say was the cause of the Samaritan man being healed?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Jesus say was the cause of the Samaritan man being saved?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Jesus talked much about the Son of Man returning/coming again. To whom, do you think, was he referring? (22, 24, 26, 30)</Original>
		<Alt>Jesus talked much about the Son of Man coming again. To whom, do you think, was he referring? (22, 24, 26, 30)</Alt>
		<Alt>Jesus talked much about the Son of Man returning. To whom, do you think, was he referring? (22, 24, 26, 30)</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Jesus clearly implied that there would be a difference between the kingdom of God coming and the Son of Man coming again/returning. What was different in the way he talked about those two things?</Original>
		<Alt>Jesus clearly implied that there would be a difference between the kingdom of God coming and the Son of Man coming again. What was different in the way he talked about those two things?</Alt>
		<Alt>Jesus clearly implied that there would be a difference between the kingdom of God coming and the Son of Man returning. What was different in the way he talked about those two things?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did Jesus say would happen to the person who wanted to save his own life/keep on living the way he was?</Original>
		<Alt>What did Jesus say would happen to the person who wanted to save his own life?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Jesus say would happen to the person who wanted to keep on living the way he was?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>When Jesus returns to earth as the Son of Man, for what will he be looking/wanting to find?</Original>
		<Alt>When Jesus returns to earth as the Son of Man, for what will he be looking?</Alt>
		<Alt>When Jesus returns to earth as the Son of Man, what will he be wanting to find?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did Jesus say was the cause of the blind man being able to see again/being saved?</Original>
		<Alt>What did Jesus say was the cause of the blind man being able to see again?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Jesus say was the cause of the blind man being saved?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Whom do you think the important man who was to become king was a picture of/represented? (12)</Original>
		<Alt>Whom do you think the important man who was to become king was a picture of? (12)</Alt>
		<Alt>Whom do you think the important man who was to become king represented? (12)</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Why did the owner of the vineyard/grape garden rent it out to some farmers/tenants?</Original>
		<Alt>Why did the owner of the vineyard rent it out to some farmers?</Alt>
		<Alt>Why did the owner of the vineyard rent it out to some tenants?</Alt>
		<Alt>Why did the owner of the grape garden rent it out to some farmers?</Alt>
		<Alt>Why did the owner of the grape garden rent it out to some tenants?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>When a person in your language group uses the garden/land area of another person, how does that one give a payment to the owner of the land?</Original>
		<Alt>When a person in your language group uses the garden of another person, how does that one give a payment to the owner of the land?</Alt>
		<Alt>When a person in your language group uses the land area of another person, how does that one give a payment to the owner of the land?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>When people read verse 16, is it clear to them/can they tell who was Jesus' mother?</Original>
		<Alt>When people read verse 16, is it clear to them who was Jesus' mother?</Alt>
		<Alt>When people read verse 16, can they tell who was Jesus' mother?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What sort of person does the text/the Scripture say Joseph was?</Original>
		<Alt>What sort of person does the text say Joseph was?</Alt>
		<Alt>What sort of person does the Scripture say Joseph was?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did Joseph do after the angel told him that Mary had been faithful to him, and explained how she had become/it was that she was pregnant?</Original>
		<Alt>What did Joseph do after the angel told him that Mary had been faithful to him, and explained how she had become pregnant?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Joseph do after the angel told him that Mary had been faithful to him, and explained how it was that she was pregnant?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What happened at Bethlehem at that time/at the time of this passage?</Original>
		<Alt>What happened at Bethlehem at that time?</Alt>
		<Alt>What happened at Bethlehem at the time of this passage?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What do you think those men wanted to do when they said that they wanted to worship Jesus/the newborn king?</Original>
		<Alt>What do you think those men wanted to do when they said that they wanted to worship Jesus?</Alt>
		<Alt>What do you think those men wanted to do when they said that they wanted to worship the newborn king?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>In verses 14 and 15 Matthew wrote/it says that they went and stayed in Egypt, until Herod died, and that what they did fulfilled what a prophet had written in the Old Testament. That prophet had written, "I called my son out of Egypt." How do you think this event fulfilled that prophecy/writing/saying? (See also verses 19 and 20.)</Original>
		<Alt>In verses 14 and 15 Matthew wrote that they went and stayed in Egypt, until Herod died, and that what they did fulfilled what a prophet had written in the Old Testament. That prophet had written, "I called my son out of Egypt." How do you think this event fulfilled that prophecy? (See also verses 19 and 20.)</Alt>
		<Alt>In verses 14 and 15 Matthew wrote that they went and stayed in Egypt, until Herod died, and that what they did fulfilled what a prophet had written in the Old Testament. That prophet had written, "I called my son out of Egypt." How do you think this event fulfilled that writing? (See also verses 19 and 20.)</Alt>
		<Alt>In verses 14 and 15 Matthew wrote that they went and stayed in Egypt, until Herod died, and that what they did fulfilled what a prophet had written in the Old Testament. That prophet had written, "I called my son out of Egypt." How do you think this event fulfilled that saying? (See also verses 19 and 20.)</Alt>
		<Alt>In verses 14 and 15 it says that they went and stayed in Egypt, until Herod died, and that what they did fulfilled what a prophet had written in the Old Testament. That prophet had written, "I called my son out of Egypt." How do you think this event fulfilled that prophecy? (See also verses 19 and 20.)</Alt>
		<Alt>In verses 14 and 15 it says that they went and stayed in Egypt, until Herod died, and that what they did fulfilled what a prophet had written in the Old Testament. That prophet had written, "I called my son out of Egypt." How do you think this event fulfilled that writing? (See also verses 19 and 20.)</Alt>
		<Alt>In verses 14 and 15 it says that they went and stayed in Egypt, until Herod died, and that what they did fulfilled what a prophet had written in the Old Testament. That prophet had written, "I called my son out of Egypt." How do you think this event fulfilled that saying? (See also verses 19 and 20.)</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What kind of fire did John say God would use to burn up the chaff/unusable part?</Original>
		<Alt>What kind of fire did John say God would use to burn up the chaff?</Alt>
		<Alt>What kind of fire did John say God would use to burn up the unusable part?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What is the reason that the Spirit/Holy Spirit led Jesus into the desert?</Original>
		<Alt>What is the reason that the Spirit led Jesus into the desert?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that the Holy Spirit led Jesus into the desert?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did Jesus do when he heard that John the Baptist had been imprisoned/incarcerated/put in prison?</Original>
		<Alt>What did Jesus do when he heard that John the Baptist had been imprisoned?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Jesus do when he heard that John the Baptist had been incarcerated?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Jesus do when he heard that John the Baptist had been put in prison?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>How did people feel about Jesus at that time/at the time of this incident?</Original>
		<Alt>How did people feel about Jesus at that time?</Alt>
		<Alt>How did people feel about Jesus at the time of this incident?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What do you think it means for someone to have a demon/be demon possessed?</Original>
		<Alt>What do you think it means for someone to have a demon?</Alt>
		<Alt>What do you think it means for someone to be demon possessed?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What sort of people are those who are/these meek people?</Original>
		<Alt>What sort of people are those who are meek people?</Alt>
		<Alt>What sort of people are these meek people?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What do you think might be the reason that some people would do evil/bad to righteous people, that is, those who have a right/are in a right relationship with God?</Original>
		<Alt>What do you think might be the reason that some people would do evil to righteous people, that is, those who have a right relationship with God?</Alt>
		<Alt>What do you think might be the reason that some people would do evil to righteous people, that is, those who are in a right relationship with God?</Alt>
		<Alt>What do you think might be the reason that some people would do bad to righteous people, that is, those who have a right relationship with God?</Alt>
		<Alt>What do you think might be the reason that some people would do bad to righteous people, that is, those who are in a right relationship with God?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What must anyone do who wants to follow Jesus/be a disciple of Jesus?</Original>
		<Alt>What must anyone do who wants to follow Jesus?</Alt>
		<Alt>What must anyone do who wants to be a disciple of Jesus?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What will happen to a person, who loses his life for Jesus/to follow Jesus/to be a disciple of Jesus?</Original>
		<Alt>What will happen to a person, who loses his life for Jesus?</Alt>
		<Alt>What will happen to a person, who loses his life to follow Jesus?</Alt>
		<Alt>What will happen to a person, who loses his life to be a disciple of Jesus?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did Jesus say about anyone who welcomed/accepted a little child in his name/for his sake/because of him?</Original>
		<Alt>What did Jesus say about anyone who welcomed a little child in his name?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Jesus say about anyone who welcomed a little child for his sake?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Jesus say about anyone who welcomed a little child because of him?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Jesus say about anyone who accepted a little child in his name?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Jesus say about anyone who accepted a little child for his sake?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Jesus say about anyone who accepted a little child because of him?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What should they do if the offending person will not listen/admit that he was wrong?</Original>
		<Alt>What should they do if the offending person will not listen?</Alt>
		<Alt>What should they do if the offending person will not admit that he was wrong?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did the king decide to do with a servant who owed him much money/ten thousand talents/millions of dollars?</Original>
		<Alt>What did the king decide to do with a servant who owed him much money?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did the king decide to do with a servant who owed him ten thousand talents?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did the king decide to do with a servant who owed him millions of dollars?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did the Pharisees ask Jesus at that time/in that place?</Original>
		<Alt>What did the Pharisees ask Jesus at that time?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did the Pharisees ask Jesus in that place?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Who did Jesus say would be able to accept/understand the meaning of what he had said/this word/this teaching?</Original>
		<Alt>Who did Jesus say would be able to accept what he had said?</Alt>
		<Alt>Who did Jesus say would be able to accept this word?</Alt>
		<Alt>Who did Jesus say would be able to accept this teaching?</Alt>
		<Alt>Who did Jesus say would be able to understand the meaning of what he had said?</Alt>
		<Alt>Who did Jesus say would be able to understand this word?</Alt>
		<Alt>Who did Jesus say would be able to understand this teaching?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did Jesus say about those people, who are first/most important now, and those who are last/least important now?</Original>
		<Alt>What did Jesus say about those people, who are first now, and those who are last now?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Jesus say about those people, who are most important now, and those who are least important now?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Jesus say about those people, who are first now, and those who are last now?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Jesus say about those people, who are most important now, and those who are least important now?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did the landowner tell his foreman to do, when the evening came/at 6:00 p.m.?</Original>
		<Alt>What did the landowner tell his foreman to do, when the evening came?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did the landowner tell his foreman to do, at 6:00 p.m.?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did the mother of Zebedee's sons/wife of Zebedee ask Jesus to do for her sons?</Original>
		<Alt>What did the mother of Zebedee's sons ask Jesus to do for her sons?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did the wife of Zebedee ask Jesus to do for her sons?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What is the reason that the Son of Man came to the earth/the world?</Original>
		<Alt>What is the reason that the Son of Man came to the earth?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that the Son of Man came to the world?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What were the two disciples supposed to say if anyone asked them what they were doing/why they were taking the donkey and the colt?</Original>
		<Alt>What were the two disciples supposed to say if anyone asked them what they were doing?</Alt>
		<Alt>What were the two disciples supposed to say if anyone asked them why they were taking the donkey and the colt?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>How did the disciples react, when they saw that the fig tree had withered/dried up?</Original>
		<Alt>How did the disciples react, when they saw that the fig tree had withered?</Alt>
		<Alt>How did the disciples react, when they saw that the fig tree had dried up?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What is the reason that the chief priests and the elders did not want to answer that John's/say that John's baptism/authority to baptize was from heaven/God?</Original>
		<Alt>What is the reason that the chief priests and the elders did not want to answer that John's baptism was from heaven?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that the chief priests and the elders did not want to answer that John's baptism was from God?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that the chief priests and the elders did not want to answer that John's authority to baptize was from heaven?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that the chief priests and the elders did not want to answer that John's authority to baptize was from God?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that the chief priests and the elders did not want to say that John's baptism was from heaven?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that the chief priests and the elders did not want to say that John's baptism was from God?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that the chief priests and the elders did not want to say that John's authority to baptize was from heaven?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that the chief priests and the elders did not want to say that John's authority to baptize was from God?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What is the reason that the chief priests and the elders did not want to answer that/say that John's baptism/authority to baptize was from men?</Original>
		<Alt>What is the reason that the chief priests and the elders did not want to answer that John's baptism was from men?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that the chief priests and the elders did not want to answer that John's authority to baptize was from men?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that the chief priests and the elders did not want to say that John's baptism was from men?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that the chief priests and the elders did not want to say that John's authority to baptize was from men?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did his first son answer him/say to him?</Original>
		<Alt>What did his first son answer him?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did his first son say to him?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did the second son answer him/say to him?</Original>
		<Alt>What did the second son answer him?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did the second son say to him?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did Jesus say would happen to the teachers of the law and the Pharisees because of all the righteous people whom they would kill/whom they have killed?</Original>
		<Alt>What did Jesus say would happen to the teachers of the law and the Pharisees because of all the righteous people whom they would kill?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Jesus say would happen to the teachers of the law and the Pharisees because of all the righteous people whom they have killed?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did Jesus say that people should do when they see the abomination that causes desolation/the shameful/forbidden thing that makes God's altar impure which the prophet Daniel spoke about long ago?</Original>
		<Alt>What did Jesus say that people should do when they see the abomination that causes desolation which the prophet Daniel spoke about long ago?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Jesus say that people should do when they see the shameful thing that makes God's altar impure which the prophet Daniel spoke about long ago?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Jesus say that people should do when they see the forbidden thing that makes God's altar impure which the prophet Daniel spoke about long ago?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What should they believe if at the time of the tribulation/great suffering someone says to them: "Here is the Messiah"?</Original>
		<Alt>What should they believe if at the time of the tribulation someone says to them: "Here is the Messiah"?</Alt>
		<Alt>What should they believe if at the time of the great suffering someone says to them: "Here is the Messiah"?</Alt>
		<Alt>What should they believe if at the time when people suffer someone says to them: "Here is the Messiah"?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What will happen after the tribulation/the time when people suffer?</Original>
		<Alt>What will happen after the tribulation?</Alt>
		<Alt>What will happen after the time of the great suffering?</Alt>
		<Alt>What will happen after the time when people suffer?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Who knows when Jesus/the Son of Man will return to this world?</Original>
		<Alt>Who knows when Jesus will return to this world?</Alt>
		<Alt>Who knows when the Son of Man will return to this world?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>For what did Jesus tell the disciples to keep watching/be prepared?</Original>
		<Alt>For what did Jesus tell the disciples to keep watching?</Alt>
		<Alt>For what did Jesus tell the disciples to be prepared?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What will the King/the Son of Man say to those people who are on his right?</Original>
		<Alt>What will the King say to those people who are on his right?</Alt>
		<Alt>What will the Son of Man say to those people who are on his right?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What will the King say to those people who are on his left/whom he sent to his left?</Original>
		<Alt>What will the King say to those people who are on his left?</Alt>
		<Alt>What will the King say to those people whom he sent to his left?</Alt>
		<Alt>What will the Son of Man say to those people who are on his left?</Alt>
		<Alt>What will the Son of Man say to those people whom he sent to his left?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What is the reason that Judas returned the thirty pieces of silver/silver coins to the chief priests and the elders?</Original>
		<Alt>What is the reason that Judas returned the thirty pieces of silver to the chief priests and the elders?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that Judas returned the thirty silver coins to the chief priests and the elders?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did the governor/Pilate ask Jesus?</Original>
		<Alt>What did the governor ask Jesus?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Pilate ask Jesus?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What happened, after Jesus gave up his spirit/died?</Original>
		<Alt>What happened, after Jesus gave up his spirit?</Alt>
		<Alt>What happened, after Jesus died?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What happened on the earth/land from the sixth hour/twelve o'clock noon until the ninth hour/three o'clock?</Original>
		<Alt>What happened on the earth from the sixth hour until the ninth hour?</Alt>
		<Alt>What happened on the earth from twelve o'clock noon until three o'clock?</Alt>
		<Alt>What happened on the land from the sixth hour until the ninth hour?</Alt>
		<Alt>What happened on the land from twelve o'clock noon until three o'clock?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What happened while the women were running to tell Jesus' disciples/the disciples of Jesus what the angel had told them?</Original>
		<Alt>What happened while the women were running to tell Jesus' disciples what the angel had told them?</Alt>
		<Alt>What happened while the women were running to tell the disciples of Jesus what the angel had told them?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What reasons did Paul give to show that he could rely on/put confidence in what he had done and what he was?</Original>
		<Alt>What reasons did Paul give to show that he could rely on what he had done and what he was?</Alt>
		<Alt>What reasons did Paul give to show that he could put confidence in what he had done and what he was?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did Paul tell them to think about that which is very good and about that which people say good/speak well?</Original>
		<Alt>What did Paul tell them to think about?</Alt>
		<Alt>How did Paul tell them to think about that which is very good and about that which people say good?</Alt>
		<Alt>How did Paul tell them to think about that which is very good and about that which people speak well?</Alt>
		<Alt>On what did Paul tell them to concentrate?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What has Jesus Christ done for us/all Christians?</Original>
		<Alt>What has Jesus Christ done for us?</Alt>
		<Alt>What has Jesus Christ done for all Christians?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What will those people do that have not been doing sinful deeds/soiled their clothes?</Original>
		<Alt>What will those people do that have not been doing sinful deeds?</Alt>
		<Alt>What will those people do that have not soiled their clothes?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What will be the reward of anyone who overcomes/is victorious?</Original>
		<Alt>What will be the reward of anyone who overcomes?</Alt>
		<Alt>What will be the reward of anyone who is victorious?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>For what reason were the Christians/they killed?</Original>
		<Alt>For what reason were the Christians killed?</Alt>
		<Alt>For what reason were they killed?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What were those people doing then/after that?</Original>
		<Alt>What were those people doing then?</Alt>
		<Alt>What were those people doing after that?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did the angel do with the golden censer/incense container?</Original>
		<Alt>What did the angel do with the golden censer?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did the angel do with the golden incense container?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What will happen to the two men, when they have finished with their testimony/proclaiming the message that God told them to give?</Original>
		<Alt>What will happen to the two men, when they have finished with their testimony?</Alt>
		<Alt>What will happen to the two men, when they have finished proclaiming the message that God told them to give?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What sign/amazing sight appeared in heaven?</Original>
		<Alt>What sign appeared in heaven?</Alt>
		<Alt>What amazing sight appeared in heaven?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Who are those people/her offspring/descendants?</Original>
		<Alt>Who are those people?</Alt>
		<Alt>Who are her offspring?</Alt>
		<Alt>Who are her descendants?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What do you think it means for someone to deal with someone else justly/in a just manner?</Original>
		<Alt>What do you think it means for someone to deal with someone else justly?</Alt>
		<Alt>What do you think it means for someone to deal with someone else in a just manner?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Who came out of the place where God is/temple?</Original>
		<Alt>Who came out of the place where God is?</Alt>
		<Alt>Who came out of the temple?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Where did they/the demons gather all the kings together?</Original>
		<Alt>Where did they gather all the kings together?</Alt>
		<Alt>Where did the demons gather all the kings together?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What is the one on the throne offering to anyone who is thirsty/wants to live forever?</Original>
		<Alt>What is the one on the throne offering to anyone who is thirsty?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the one on the throne offering to anyone who wants to live forever?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Who will be able to drink the water of life/receive eternal life?</Original>
		<Alt>Who will be able to drink the water of life?</Alt>
		<Alt>Who will be able to receive eternal life?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>In what way is Paul's preaching work like that of a priest/sacrifice offerer?</Original>
		<Alt>In what way is Paul's preaching work like that of a priest?</Alt>
		<Alt>In what way is Paul's preaching work like that of a sacrifice offerer?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>These things are not a law but are permission/are good advice. Which things?</Original>
		<Alt>These things are not a law but are permission. Which things?</Alt>
		<Alt>These things are not a law but are good advice. Which things?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Why is it only permission/good advice?</Original>
		<Alt>Why is it only permission?</Alt>
		<Alt>Why is it only good advice?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Who will collect back/destroy the power of death?</Original>
		<Alt>Who will destroy the power of death?</Alt>
		<Alt>Who will collect back the power of death?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>If we say we have fellowship with God, but at the same time, we walk in the darkness/do evil deeds, what are we saying?</Original>
		<Alt>If we say we have fellowship with God, but at the same time, we walk in the darkness, what are we saying?</Alt>
		<Alt>If we say we have fellowship with God, but at the same time, we do evil deeds, what are we saying?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>If we walk in the light/do not do evil deeds, we will have fellowship with God. With whom else will we have fellowship?</Original>
		<Alt>If we walk in the light, we will have fellowship with God. With whom else will we have fellowship?</Alt>
		<Alt>If we do not do evil deeds, we will have fellowship with God. With whom else will we have fellowship?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What is a person doing who/when he says that he knows God but does not do what he commands him to do?</Original>
		<Alt>What is a person doing who says that he knows God but does not do what he commands him to do?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is a person doing when he says that he knows God but does not do what he commands him to do?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>If someone accepts/acknowledges the Son/agrees that Jesus is the Son of God, what will be the result?</Original>
		<Alt>If someone accepts the Son of God, what will be the result?</Alt>
		<Alt>If someone accepts the Son, what will be the result?</Alt>
		<Alt>If someone acknowledges the Son of God, what will be the result?</Alt>
		<Alt>If someone acknowledges the Son, what will be the result?</Alt>
		<Alt>If someone agrees that Jesus is the Son of God, what will be the result?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What will those who are united to him/continually have a close relationship to him do about sin?</Original>
		<Alt>What will those who are united to him do about sin?</Alt>
		<Alt>What will those who continually have a close relationship to him do about sin?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did the prophets try to find out/understand?</Original>
		<Alt>What did the prophets try to find out?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did the prophets try to understand?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Even though these builders rejected this stone, what did this stone finally become/turn out to be?</Original>
		<Alt>Even though these builders rejected this stone, what did this stone finally become?</Alt>
		<Alt>Even though these builders rejected this stone, what did this stone finally turn out to be?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What reason did Peter give concerning/as to why they should not do evil things?</Original>
		<Alt>What reason did Peter give concerning why they should not do evil things?</Alt>
		<Alt>What reason did Peter give as to why they should not do evil things?</Alt>
		<Alt>Why did Peter say they should not do evil things?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>How should a servant treat/work for his master?</Original>
		<Alt>How should a servant treat his master?</Alt>
		<Alt>How should a servant work for his master?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>How should a servant treat/work for his master if he is harsh?</Original>
		<Alt>How should a servant treat his master if he is harsh?</Alt>
		<Alt>How should a servant work for his master if he is harsh?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What do you think it means when someone/a person is unjust to someone else?</Original>
		<Alt>What do you think it means when someone is unjust to someone else?</Alt>
		<Alt>What do you think it means when a person is unjust to someone else?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What will happen to a person who/if he suffers when he has done good things and yet/still he endures?</Original>
		<Alt>What will happen to a person who suffers when he has done good things and yet he endures?</Alt>
		<Alt>What will happen to a person who suffers when he has done good things and still endures?</Alt>
		<Alt>What will happen to a person if he suffers when he has done good things and yet he endures?</Alt>
		<Alt>What will happen to a person if he suffers when he has done good things and still endures?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What should a person do if God has given him the ability/gift to help others/of helping others?</Original>
		<Alt>What should a person do if God has given him the ability to help others?</Alt>
		<Alt>What should a person do if God has given him the ability of helping others?</Alt>
		<Alt>What should a person do if God has given him the gift to help others?</Alt>
		<Alt>What should a person do if God has given him the gift of helping others?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What should they do/their attitude be, when these things happen/come?</Original>
		<Alt>What should they do when these things happen?</Alt>
		<Alt>What should they do when these things come?</Alt>
		<Alt>What should their attitude be when these things happen?</Alt>
		<Alt>What should their attitude be when these things come?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did Peter say about those who do not believe the Good News/gospel from him?</Original>
		<Alt>What did Peter say about those who do not believe the Good News from him?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Peter say about those who do not believe the gospel from him?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What right did Peter have to give advice/make an appeal to these elders?</Original>
		<Alt>What right did Peter have to give advice to these elders?</Alt>
		<Alt>What right did Peter have to make an appeal to these elders?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What is the reason that they should cast/commit their cares to him?</Original>
		<Alt>What is the reason that they should cast their cares on him?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that they should commit their cares to him?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>In order to win over/in their fight with the Devil, what should they do?</Original>
		<Alt>In order to win over the Devil, what should they do?</Alt>
		<Alt>In order to win in their fight with the Devil, what should they do?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Why did Paul say these people should not always think about/discuss these things?</Original>
		<Alt>Why did Paul say these people should not always think about these things?</Alt>
		<Alt>Why did Paul say these people should not always discuss these things?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>In order to be a pastor, how must a man live/conduct himself?</Original>
		<Alt>In order to be a pastor, how must a man live?</Alt>
		<Alt>In order to be a pastor, how must a man conduct himself?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>When did the prophets tell him/prophesy about him?</Original>
		<Alt>When did the prophets tell him?</Alt>
		<Alt>When did the prophets prophesy about him?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Since Paul knows that he has a better living place/house in heaven what does he think of life in this world?</Original>
		<Alt>Since Paul knows that he has a better living place in heaven what does he think of life in this world?</Alt>
		<Alt>Since Paul knows that he has a better house in heaven what does he think of life in this world?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What is the grace/great thing, that God has done for the Corinthians (and us)?</Original>
		<Alt>What is the grace that God has given the Corinthians (and us)?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the great thing that God has done for the Corinthians (and us)?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>In what ways will God the Father and the Son show favor to them/show them favor?</Original>
		<Alt>In what ways will God the Father and the Son show favor to them?</Alt>
		<Alt>In what ways will God the Father and the Son show them favor?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did John say about anyone who does not stay with/follow the things that Christ taught?</Original>
		<Alt>What did John say about anyone who does not stay with the things that Christ taught?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did John say about anyone who does not follow the things that Christ taught?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What do you think it means for God/Jesus Christ to be righteous?</Original>
		<Alt>What do you think it means for God to be righteous?</Alt>
		<Alt>What do you think it means for Jesus Christ to be righteous?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What is the reason that they should, in addition to believing/having faith, also do the things mentioned in verse 5-7?</Original>
		<Alt>What is the reason that they should, in addition to believing, also do the things mentioned in verse 5-7?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that they should, in addition to having faith, also do the things mentioned in verse 5-7?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>If they believe/have faith, what must they also do/add to it?</Original>
		<Alt>If they believe, what must they also do?</Alt>
		<Alt>If they believe, what must they also add to it?</Alt>
		<Alt>If they have faith, what must they also do?</Alt>
		<Alt>If they have faith, what must they also add to it?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>If someone does not have these/those things/does not do these/those things, what does it show about him?</Original>
		<Alt>If someone does not have these things, what does it show about him?</Alt>
		<Alt>If someone does not have those things, what does it show about him?</Alt>
		<Alt>If someone does not do these things, what does it show about him?</Alt>
		<Alt>If someone does not do those things, what does it show about him?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>If they never stop believing/abandon their faith, but instead prove that God has chosen and called them, what will happen in the end/finally?</Original>
		<Alt>If they never stop believing, but instead prove that God has chosen and called them, what will happen in the end?</Alt>
		<Alt>If they never stop believing, but instead prove that God has chosen and called them, what will finally happen?</Alt>
		<Alt>If they never abandon their faith, but instead prove that God has chosen and called them, what will happen in the end?</Alt>
		<Alt>If they never abandon their faith, but instead prove that God has chosen and called them, what will finally happen?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What happens when those false teachers join the believers in their meals/love feasts?</Original>
		<Alt>What happens when those false teachers join the believers in their meals?</Alt>
		<Alt>What happens when those false teachers join the believers in their love feasts?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>How do these false teachers conduct themselves among/act toward women?</Original>
		<Alt>How do these false teachers conduct themselves among women?</Alt>
		<Alt>How do these false teachers act toward women?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>How/by what means were they saved?</Original>
		<Alt>How were they saved?</Alt>
		<Alt>By what means were they saved?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What does Paul say Timothy has known/has followed closely in Paul's life?</Original>
		<Alt>What does Paul say Timothy has known in Paul's life?</Alt>
		<Alt>What does Paul say Timothy has followed closely in Paul's life?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Did Jesus say that giving her the written divorce paper made the divorce legal/all right with God?</Original>
		<Alt>Did Jesus say that giving her the written divorce paper made the divorce legal?</Alt>
		<Alt>Did Jesus say that giving her the written divorce paper made the divorce all right with God?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What reason did Jesus give for his coming to/say that he had come to this world?</Original>
		<Alt>What reason did Jesus give for his coming to this world?</Alt>
		<Alt>What reason did Jesus say that he had come to this world?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Did Jesus mean in verses 29 &amp; 30 for someone/a person to gouge out his or her/their eye, or to cut off his or her/their arm, if he or she/they had used those parts of their bodies to sin?</Original>
		<Alt>Did Jesus mean in verses 29 &amp; 30 for someone to gouge out his or her eye, or to cut off his or her arm, if he or she had used those parts of his or her body to sin?</Alt>
		<Alt>Did Jesus mean in verses 29 &amp; 30 for someone to gouge out his eye, or to cut off his arm, if he had used those parts of his body to sin?</Alt>
		<Alt>Did Jesus mean in verses 29 &amp; 30 for people to gouge out their eyes, or to cut off their arms, if they had used those parts of their bodies to sin?</Alt>
		<Alt>Did Jesus mean in verses 29 &amp; 30 for a person to gouge out his or her eye, or to cut off his or her arm, if he or she had used those parts of his or her body to sin?</Alt>
		<Alt>Did Jesus mean in verses 29 &amp; 30 for a person to gouge out his eye, or to cut off his arm, if he had used those parts of his body to sin?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>In verse 48, what is it that Jesus wants believers/his followers to do?</Original>
		<Alt>In verse 48, what is it that Jesus wants believers to do?</Alt>
		<Alt>In verse 48, what is it that Jesus wants his followers to do?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Do you think Jesus meant that the prayer he suggested/suggested prayer he gave is the only way to pray?</Original>
		<Alt>Do you think Jesus meant that the prayer he suggested is the only way to pray?</Alt>
		<Alt>Do you think Jesus meant that the suggested prayer he gave is the only way to pray?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What do you think happens when a person/someone forgives someone else?</Original>
		<Alt>What do you think happens when a person forgives someone else?</Alt>
		<Alt>What do you think happens when someone forgives someone else?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What is the reason that Jesus does not want us to spend much time and great effort in accumulating/to accumulate many possessions here on earth?</Original>
		<Alt>What is the reason that Jesus does not want us to spend much time and great effort in accumulating many possessions here on earth?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that Jesus does not want us to spend much time and great effort to accumulate many possessions here on earth?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What is the reason that Jesus did not want his followers/believers/people to be overly concerned/worry about their future needs for food and clothing?</Original>
		<Alt>What is the reason that Jesus did not want his followers to be overly concerned about their future needs for food and clothing?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that Jesus did not want his followers to worry about their future needs for food and clothing?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that Jesus did not want believers to be overly concerned about their future needs for food and clothing?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that Jesus did not want believers to worry about their future needs for food and clothing?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that Jesus did not want people to be overly concerned about their future needs for food and clothing?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that Jesus did not want people to worry about their future needs for food and clothing?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>(Ask this question only if verse 27 is in a question form after being translated.) What do you think is the reason that Jesus asked them the question about who could live longer/add more days to their life by worrying?</Original>
		<Alt>What do you think is the reason that Jesus asked them the question about who could live longer by worrying?</Alt>
		<Alt>What do you think is the reason that Jesus asked them the question about who could add more days to their life by worrying?</Alt>
		<Alt>Why did Jesus ask them the question about who could live longer by worrying?</Alt>
		<Alt>Why did Jesus ask them the question about who could add more days to their life by worrying?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What else did Jesus say to make us know for sure/feel sure that God will only do what is good for us?</Original>
		<Alt>What else did Jesus say to make us know for sure that God will only do what is good for us?</Alt>
		<Alt>What else did Jesus say to make us feel sure that God will only do what is good for us?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What do you think Jesus meant would happen to the foolish people who would not obey him/his teaching?</Original>
		<Alt>What do you think Jesus meant would happen to the foolish people who would not obey him?</Alt>
		<Alt>What do you think Jesus meant would happen to the foolish people who would not obey his teaching?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>How can you discern whether/tell if Jesus was willing to heal him?</Original>
		<Alt>How can you discern whether Jesus was willing to heal him?</Alt>
		<Alt>How can you tell if Jesus was willing to heal him?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What happened/event occurred in these verses?</Original>
		<Alt>What happened in these verses?</Alt>
		<Alt>What event occurred in these verses?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What do you think is the reason that, right in the middle of this/his talk/teaching about his eating with sinners, Jesus talked about mercy being better than making sacrifices?</Original>
		<Alt>What do you think is the reason that, right in the middle of this, Jesus talked about mercy being better than making sacrifices?</Alt>
		<Alt>What do you think is the reason that, right in the middle of his talk, Jesus talked about mercy being better than making sacrifices?</Alt>
		<Alt>What do you think is the reason that, right in the middle of his talk about his eating with sinners, Jesus talked about mercy being better than making sacrifices?</Alt>
		<Alt>What do you think is the reason that, right in the middle of his teaching about his eating with sinners, Jesus talked about mercy being better than making sacrifices?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>When Jesus answered their question, what do you think is the reason that Jesus told them about/talked about what friends of a bridegroom would do?</Original>
		<Alt>When Jesus answered their question, what do you think is the reason that Jesus told them about what friends of a bridegroom would do?</Alt>
		<Alt>When Jesus answered their question, what do you think is the reason that Jesus talked about what friends of a bridegroom would do?</Alt>
		<Alt>When Jesus answered their question, why do you think Jesus told them about what friends of a bridegroom would do?</Alt>
		<Alt>When Jesus answered their question, why do you think Jesus talked about what friends of a bridegroom would do?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What was it about the crowds of people that caused Jesus to have extra compassion/pity/feel sorry for them?</Original>
		<Alt>What was it about the crowds of people that caused Jesus to have extra compassion for them?</Alt>
		<Alt>What was it about the crowds of people that caused Jesus to have extra pity for them?</Alt>
		<Alt>What was it about the crowds of people that caused Jesus to have pity on them?</Alt>
		<Alt>What was it about the crowds of people that caused Jesus to feel sorry for them?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What is the reason that he told the disciples to watch out/be careful, and to have only good motives?</Original>
		<Alt>What is the reason that he told the disciples to watch out and to have only good motives?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that he told the disciples to be careful and to have only good motives?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Although/Even though some of Jesus' believers/followers might be killed, what did Jesus say would happen to all those who remained faithful to him?</Original>
		<Alt>Although some of Jesus' believers might be killed, what did Jesus say would happen to all those who remained faithful to him?</Alt>
		<Alt>Although some of Jesus' followers might be killed, what did Jesus say would happen to all those who remained faithful to him?</Alt>
		<Alt>Even though some of Jesus' believers might be killed, what did Jesus say would happen to all those who remained faithful to him?</Alt>
		<Alt>Even though some of Jesus' followers might be killed, what did Jesus say would happen to all those who remained faithful to him?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What do you think is the reason that Jesus started speaking of/talking about sparrows?</Original>
		<Alt>What do you think is the reason that Jesus started speaking of sparrows?</Alt>
		<Alt>What do you think is the reason that Jesus started talking about sparrows?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did John the Baptist, who was now in prison, want to know/determine/find out from Jesus?</Original>
		<Alt>What did John the Baptist, who was now in prison, want to know from Jesus?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did John the Baptist, who was now in prison, want to determine from Jesus?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did John the Baptist, who was now in prison, want to find out from Jesus?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What had David done that was somewhat like/a bit like what the disciples were doing?</Original>
		<Alt>What had David done that was somewhat like what the disciples were doing?</Alt>
		<Alt>What had David done that was a bit like what the disciples were doing?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What do you think is the reason that it was lawful/acceptable to God/permissible?</Original>
		<Alt>What do you think is the reason that it was lawful?</Alt>
		<Alt>What do you think is the reason that it was acceptable to God?</Alt>
		<Alt>What do you think is the reason that it was permissible?</Alt>
		<Alt>Why do you think it was lawful?</Alt>
		<Alt>Why do you think it was acceptable to God?</Alt>
		<Alt>Why do you think it was permissible?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What is the reason that the Pharisees asked Jesus if it was lawful/all right to heal on the Sabbath day?</Original>
		<Alt>What is the reason that the Pharisees asked Jesus if it was lawful to heal on the Sabbath day?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that the Pharisees asked Jesus if it was all right to heal on the Sabbath day?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did the Pharisees do after that/then?</Original>
		<Alt>What did the Pharisees do after that?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did the Pharisees do then?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>By using the Old Testament quotation/quote from Isaiah's writings, what was Matthew teaching/making clear about Jesus?</Original>
		<Alt>By using the Old Testament quotation from Isaiah's writings, what was Matthew teaching about Jesus?</Alt>
		<Alt>By using the Old Testament quotation from Isaiah's writings, what was Matthew making clear about Jesus?</Alt>
		<Alt>By using the quote from Isaiah's writings, what was Matthew teaching about Jesus?</Alt>
		<Alt>By using the quote from Isaiah's writings, what was Matthew making clear about Jesus?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Can you think of something which/that the Pharisees did that would have caused Jesus to talk in that manner/like that?</Original>
		<Alt>Can you think of something which the Pharisees did that would have caused Jesus to talk in that manner?</Alt>
		<Alt>Can you think of something which the Pharisees did that would have caused Jesus to talk like that?</Alt>
		<Alt>Can you think of something that the Pharisees did that would have caused Jesus to talk in that manner?</Alt>
		<Alt>Can you think of something that the Pharisees did that would have caused Jesus to talk like that?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What do you think was the reason that Jesus called them the offspring of vipers/poisonous snakes?</Original>
		<Alt>What do you think was the reason that Jesus called them the offspring of vipers?</Alt>
		<Alt>What do you think was the reason that Jesus called them the offspring of poisonous snakes?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>How will what the queen did testify against/convict the people of Jesus' generation, at the time when God judges the people of earth?</Original>
		<Alt>How will what the queen did testify against the people of Jesus' generation, at the time when God judges the people of earth?</Alt>
		<Alt>How will what the queen did convict the people of Jesus' generation, at the time when God judges the people of earth?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What do you think is the reason that Jesus talked about the evil spirit going through dry places/uninhabited places, as the evil spirit wandered around when it had no place to stay?</Original>
		<Alt>What do you think is the reason that Jesus talked about the evil spirit going through dry places, as the evil spirit wandered around when it had no place to stay?</Alt>
		<Alt>What do you think is the reason that Jesus talked about the evil spirit going through uninhabited places, as the evil spirit wandered around when it had no place to stay?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>In this account/his little story, Jesus said that the evil spirit left the person and later came back to that person, but whom was he really warning?</Original>
		<Alt>In this account, Jesus said that the evil spirit left the person and later came back to that person, but whom was he really warning?</Alt>
		<Alt>In his little story, Jesus said that the evil spirit left the person and later came back to that person, but whom was he really warning?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Who came looking/to look for Jesus?</Original>
		<Alt>Who came looking for Jesus?</Alt>
		<Alt>Who came to look for Jesus?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What was the owner's plan to separate/for separating the weeds from the real wheat?</Original>
		<Alt>What was the owner's plan to separate the weeds from the real wheat?</Alt>
		<Alt>What was the owner's plan for separating the weeds from the real wheat?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What happened after Jesus returned/went home?</Original>
		<Alt>What happened after Jesus returned?</Alt>
		<Alt>What happened after Jesus went home?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did Jesus do during the fourth watch/between 3:00am and 6:00am of the night?</Original>
		<Alt>What did Jesus do during the fourth watch of the night?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Jesus do between 3:00am and 6:00am?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What did Jesus tell the disciples made a person sinful/unacceptable to God?</Original>
		<Alt>What did Jesus tell the disciples made a person sinful?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Jesus tell the disciples made a person unacceptable to God?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What is the reason that the thoughts/ideas that come from the heart make a person sinful/unacceptable to God?</Original>
		<Alt>What is the reason that the thoughts that come from the heart make a person sinful?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that the thoughts that come from the heart make a person unacceptable to God?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that the ideas that come from the heart make a person sinful?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the reason that the ideas that come from the heart make a person unacceptable to God?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>In what way did a person make himself sinful/unacceptable to God when he ate without washing his hands?</Original>
		<Alt>In what way did a person make himself sinful when he ate without washing his hands?</Alt>
		<Alt>In what way did a person make himself unacceptable to God when he ate without washing his hands?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>How much food remained/was left over?</Original>
		<Alt>How much food remained?</Alt>
		<Alt>How much food was left over?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>What could Peter do with the keys to/authority over the kingdom of heaven?</Original>
		<Alt>What could Peter do with the keys to the kingdom of heaven?</Alt>
		<Alt>What could Peter do with the authority over the kingdom of heaven?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>The translator may need to have each doctrine read and ask what the reader understands by what is said there. An unbeliever especially will not fully understand these doctrines, but the surface meaning should be clear. At this point ask the reader if he/she has any further comments to make about the passage just checked.</Original>
		<Alt>At this point ask the reader if he/she has any further comments to make about the passage just checked.</Alt>
		<Alt>Do you have any other comments to make about the passage just checked?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>The translator may need to go back and ask what the reader understands by "they have come to understand God's Message" and "they have received the good things God gives his people" and "experienced the Holy Spirit in their lives" and "seen God using his power as He will in the Coming Age." At this point ask the reader if he/she has any further comments to make about the passage just checked.</Original>
		<Alt>What do you understand by "they have come to understand God's Message" and "they have received the good things God gives his people" and "experienced the Holy Spirit in their lives" and "seen God using his power as He will in the Coming Age."?</Alt>
		<Alt>a) What do you understand by "they have come to understand God's Message"? b) What do you understand by "they have received the good things God gives his people"? c) What do you understand by "experienced the Holy Spirit in their lives" d) What do you understand by "seen God using his power as He will in the Coming Age."?</Alt>
		<Alt>What do you understand by "they have come to understand God's Message" and "they have received the good things God gives his people" and "experienced the Holy Spirit in their lives" and "seen God using his power as He will in the Coming Age."? At this point ask the reader if he/she has any further comments to make about the passage just checked.</Alt>
		<Alt>a) What do you understand by "they have come to understand God's Message"? b) What do you understand by "they have received the good things God gives his people"? c) What do you understand by "experienced the Holy Spirit in their lives" d) What do you understand by "seen God using his power as He will in the Coming Age."? At this point ask the reader if he/she has any further comments to make about the passage just checked.</Alt>
		<Alt>What do you understand by "they have come to understand God's Message" and "they have received the good things God gives his people" and "experienced the Holy Spirit in their lives" and "seen God using his power as He will in the Coming Age."? Do you have any other comments to make about the passage just checked?</Alt>
		<Alt>a) What do you understand by "they have come to understand God's Message"? b) What do you understand by "they have received the good things God gives his people"? c) What do you understand by "experienced the Holy Spirit in their lives" d) What do you understand by "seen God using his power as He will in the Coming Age."? e) Do you have any other comments to make about the passage just checked?</Alt>
		<Alt>At this point ask the reader if he/she has any further comments to make about the passage just checked.</Alt>
		<Alt>Do you have any other comments to make about the passage just checked?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>The translator should probably get the reader to describe how he thinks all these things looked, things like the Chest of the Agreement, stone tablets, etc. At this point ask the reader if he/she has any further comments to make about the passage just checked.</Original>
		<Alt>The translator should probably get the reader to describe how he thinks all these things looked, things like the Chest of the Agreement, stone tablets, etc.</Alt>
		<Alt>Describe how you think all these things (the Chest of the Agreement, stone tablets, etc.) looked.</Alt>
		<Alt>Describe how you think all these things (the Chest of the Agreement, stone tablets, etc.) looked. Do you have any other comments to make about the passage just checked?</Alt>
		<Alt>At this point ask the reader if he/she has any further comments to make about the passage just checked.</Alt>
		<Alt>Do you have any other comments to make about the passage just checked?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>The translator should probably discuss the ideas of "putting an operation into effect," "the wonderful things God promises his people," etc., with the reader to be sure the translation is clear enough. At this point ask the reader if he/she has any further comments to make about the passage just checked.</Original>
		<Alt>At this point ask the reader if he/she has any further comments to make about the passage just checked.</Alt>
		<Alt>Do you have any other comments to make about the passage just checked?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Why do you think that it tells us that the curtain was torn from top to bottom? (Here you just want to be sure they don't understand the wrong thing and you may want to tell them why.) Ask the reader if he/she has any other comments to make about the passage just checked.</Original>
		<Alt>Why do you think that it tells us that the curtain was torn from top to bottom? Do you have any other comments to make about the passage just checked?</Alt>
		<Alt>Ask the reader if he/she has any other comments to make about the passage just checked.</Alt>
		<Alt>Do you have any other comments to make about the passage just checked?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>The translator should be sure that the reader understands that all the references in these verses to the mountain, Mt. Sinai, etc., are referring to when God spoke to the ancestors of the Jews long ago and gave them the Old Agreement. Ask the reader if he/she has any other comments to make about the passage just checked.</Original>
		<Alt>What is the meaning of the references in these verses to the mountain, Mt. Sinai, etc.?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the meaning of the references in these verses to the mountain, Mt. Sinai, etc.? Do you have any other comments to make about the passage just checked?</Alt>
		<Alt>Ask the reader if he/she has any other comments to make about the passage just checked.</Alt>
		<Alt>Do you have any other comments to make about the passage just checked?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>(For) how long did Jacob work for Laban?</Original>
		<Alt>For how long did Jacob work for Laban?</Alt>
		<Alt>How long did Jacob work for Laban?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>(Some time later,) what did Tamar discover was the result of her union with Judah?</Original>
		<Alt>Some time later, what did Tamar discover was the result of her union with Judah?</Alt>
		<Alt>What did Tamar discover was the result of her union with Judah?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>(Then) what is the significance of Pharaoh having two dreams (rather than only one dream)?</Original>
		<Alt>Then what is the significance of Pharaoh having two dreams rather than only one dream?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the significance of Pharaoh having two dreams rather than only one dream?</Alt>
		<Alt>Then what is the significance of Pharaoh having two dreams?</Alt>
		<Alt>What is the significance of Pharaoh having two dreams?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
	<Alternative>
		<Original>Why would John not want to do (or, hesitate to do) even very simple work for such a person, like untying his shoes?</Original>
		<Alt>Why would John not want to do even very simple work for such a person, like untying his shoes?</Alt>
		<Alt>Why would John hesitate to do even very simple work for such a person, like untying his shoes?</Alt>
	</Alternative>
</QuestionAlternativeOverrides>