<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE xlingpaper PUBLIC "-//XMLmind//DTD XLingPap//EN"
"XLingPap.dtd">
<xlingpaper
version="2.24.0"
><styledPaper
><lingPaper
automaticallywrapinterlinears="yes"
version="2.28.0"
><frontMatter
><title
><object
type="tPcPatrFLEx"
></object
> User Documentation</title
><author
>H. Andrew Black</author
><affiliation
>SIL International</affiliation
><emailAddress
>blackhandrew@gmail.com</emailAddress
><date
>4 August, 2022</date
><version
>Version 1.12.0 Beta</version
><version
>Copyright © 2018-2022 SIL International</version
><contents
></contents
></frontMatter
><section1
id="sIntro"
><secTitle
>Introduction</secTitle
><p
><object
type="tPcPatrFLEx"
></object
> is a tool that works as a utility in <object
type="tFieldWorks"
></object
> (aka <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
>). <object
type="tPcPatrFLEx"
></object
> can use a <object
type="tPcPatrGrammar"
></object
> to disambiguate a text or a portion of a text that has been analyzed in a <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
> project. You tell <object
type="tPcPatrFLEx"
></object
> the <object
type="tPcPatrGrammar"
></object
> file to use. Then you can choose a text or a portion of that text and ask <object
type="tPcPatrFLEx"
></object
> to try and disambiguate it.</p
><p
><object
type="tPcPatrFLEx"
></object
> works with version <object
type="tFLExVersion"
></object
> or higher of <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
> and is only available on 64-bit Windows computers.</p
><p
>While you can use any <object
type="tPcPatrGrammar"
></object
> file, <object
type="tPcPatrFLEx"
></object
> expects that you will have used the <object
type="tPAWS"
></object
> program to create the <object
type="tPcPatrGrammar"
></object
> file. See <link
href="https://software.sil.org/paws/"
>https://software.sil.org/paws/</link
> for more on <object
type="tPAWS"
></object
>.</p
><section2
id="sInstallation"
><secTitle
>Installation</secTitle
><p
>To install <object
type="tPcPatrFLEx"
></object
>, obtain the installer from <link
href="https://github.com/sillsdev/pcpatrflex/tree/master/Installer/Output/UsePcPatrWithFLExDllSetup.exe"
>https://​github.com/​sillsdev/pcpatrflex/​tree/​master/​Installer/​Output/​UsePcPatrWithFLExDllSetup.exe</link
>. The installer will check to see if you have installed <object
type="tFieldWorks"
></object
> version 9. If not, it will abort.</p
><p
>We recommend that you close <object
type="tFieldWorks"
></object
> before running the <object
type="tPcPatrFLEx"
></object
> installer.</p
></section2
><section2
id="sInvokingFromFLEx"
><secTitle
>Invoking <object
type="tPcPatrFLEx"
></object
> from within <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
></secTitle
><p
>While running <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
>, use <object
type="tMenuItem"
>Tools</object
> menu item / <object
type="tMenuItem"
>Utilities...</object
>. Find the “Use PC-PATR with FLEx” item, check it, and then click on the “Run Checked Utilities Now” button.</p
></section2
><section2
id="sInitialRun"
><secTitle
>Initial invocation</secTitle
><p
>The first time you invoke <object
type="tPcPatrFLEx"
></object
> on a <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
> database, it will automatically add to your <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
> database the following:</p
><ol
><li
>a custom field to each sense (called “PCPATR”) and</li
><li
>a custom list (called “PCPATR Feature Descriptors”) containing the template names that the <object
type="tPcPatrGrammar"
></object
> generated by the <object
type="tPAWS"
></object
> program expects.</li
></ol
><p
>The names shown above are always in the English analysis writing system and English is the only writing system containing these names.</p
><p
>You can find the custom list by clicking on the “Lists” button in <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
>.</p
></section2
><section2
id="sAppearance"
><secTitle
>Appearance</secTitle
><p
><object
type="tPcPatrFLEx"
></object
> looks like what is shown in <exampleRef
letter="xNewPcPatrFLEx"
num="xNewPcPatrFLEx"
></exampleRef
>.</p
><example
num="xNewPcPatrFLEx"
><chart
><img
XeLaTeXSpecial="scaled='600'"
src="resources/PcPatrFLExEmpty.png"
width="450"
></img
></chart
></example
><p
>The texts in the <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
> database are shown in the left pane and the segments of the first text are shown in the right pane.</p
><p
>There are buttons you can click. Each is discussed in section <sectionRef
sec="sButtons"
></sectionRef
> below.</p
></section2
></section1
><section1
id="sButtons"
><secTitle
>Buttons</secTitle
><p
>You control <object
type="tPcPatrFLEx"
></object
> by using the various buttons. This section briefly describes them. See sections <sectionRef
sec="sParsingSegment"
></sectionRef
>–<sectionRef
sec="sDisambiguating"
textBefore="none"
></sectionRef
> for more on what happens for the segment and text buttons, respectively.</p
><section2
id="sBrowse"
><secTitle
><object
type="tPcPatrGrammar"
></object
> Browse button</secTitle
><p
>To choose which <object
type="tPcPatrGrammar"
></object
> file to use, click on the Browse button. By convention, <object
type="tPcPatrGrammar"
></object
> files have an extension of “.grm” so this is what the file browser uses.</p
></section2
><section2
id="sRootGloss"
><secTitle
>Rootgloss choices</secTitle
><p
><object
type="tPcPatr"
></object
> allows you to have “rootglosses” in rules. This section allows you to set one of four options with respect to how rootglosses are handled. See section 3.2.14.22 “set rootgloss” in the PC-PATR Reference Manual.<endnote
id="nPCPTRRefManual"
><p
>Use the <object
type="tMenuItem"
>Help</object
> menu item / <object
type="tMenuItem"
> PC-PATR Reference Manual</object
> to see this document.</p
></endnote
> The four options are:</p
><ol
><li
>off: rootglosses are not used; this is the default;</li
><li
>leftmost root: the first / leftmost root is used;</li
><li
>rightmost root: the last / rightmost root is used;</li
><li
>all: every root is used.</li
></ol
></section2
><section2
id="sAdvanced"
><secTitle
>Advanced</secTitle
><p
>The “Advanced” button is used to changed some advanced options. It brings up a dialog that looks like what is shown in <exampleRef
letter="xAdvanced"
num="xAdvanced"
></exampleRef
>.</p
><example
num="xAdvanced"
><chart
><img
XeLaTeXSpecial="scaled='600'"
src="resources/AdvancedDialog.png"
width="450"
></img
></chart
></example
><p
>There are three options:</p
><ol
><li
>“Maximum number of ambiguities to output:” is the maximum number of ambiguities that will appear in the <object
type="tPcPatrBrowser"
></object
>. The default is 100.</li
><li
>“Parsing time limit:” is how many seconds to allow for parsing the segments. The default is 0 (which means no time limit).</li
><li
>“Run PC-PATR on each sentence individually” is for running each segment individually when disambiguating a text. It is most useful when using a time limit. With this option, you can have <object
type="tPcPatrFLEx"
></object
> parse each segment for a maximum number of seconds given by the parsing time limit. Without this option, the maximum time limit is for the entire text. With this option, the maximum time limit is for each segment.</li
></ol
><p
><object
type="tPcPatrFLEx"
></object
> will remember the settings for each of these three options when you close <object
type="tPcPatrFLEx"
></object
>.</p
></section2
><section2
id="sHelp"
><secTitle
>Help button</secTitle
><p
>The “Help...” button is used to get this user documentation file, show the PC-PATR Reference Manual, or to show the “About” dialog box.</p
></section2
><section2
id="sRefresh"
><secTitle
>Refresh texts button</secTitle
><p
>Whenever you click on the “Refresh texts” button, <object
type="tPcPatrFLEx"
></object
> will reload all of the texts from <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
>. This is so if you know that if some texts have been added, deleted or changed since you first started <object
type="tPcPatrFLEx"
></object
>, you can get the most current list of texts.</p
></section2
><section2
id="sDisambiguate"
><secTitle
>Disambiguate button</secTitle
><p
>Above the pane containing the texts is a button labeled “Disambiguate &amp; show this text.” You use this button to try and use the <object
type="tPcPatrGrammar"
></object
> to disambiguate this entire text. See section <sectionRef
sec="sDisambiguating"
></sectionRef
> for more.</p
></section2
><section2
id="sParse"
><secTitle
>Parse button</secTitle
><p
>Above the pane containing the segments of the selected text is a button labeled “Parse &amp; show this segment.” You use this button to try and use the <object
type="tPcPatrGrammar"
></object
> to parse this particular segment. See section <sectionRef
sec="sParsingSegment"
></sectionRef
> for more.</p
></section2
></section1
><section1
id="sParsingSegment"
><secTitle
>Parsing a segment</secTitle
><p
>When you use the “Parse &amp; show this segment” button for a segment or double click on that segment, <object
type="tPcPatrFLEx"
></object
> will pass the parsing information that you entered in <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
> to <object
type="tPcPatr"
></object
>, along with the <object
type="tPcPatrGrammar"
></object
>, and process that segment. The result will be shown in a slightly newer version of the <object
type="tPcPatrBrowser"
></object
> tool (<link
href="https://software.sil.org/carla/pc-patr-browser/"
>https://​software.​sil.​org/​carla/​pc-patr-browser/</link
>). See appendix <appendixRef
app="aPcPatrBrowser"
></appendixRef
> for more information on this tool.</p
><p
>You use this tool to see all the parses the <object
type="tPcPatr"
></object
> program produced for this segment using the <object
type="tPcPatrGrammar"
></object
> file. When there are two or more parses, you can show the correct one and then use <object
type="tMenuItem"
>Parse / Use This Parse</object
> menu item (or click on the <img
XeLaTeXSpecial="scaled='250'"
src="resources/yes.png"
></img
> tool bar button) to have this analysis be recorded in the <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
> database for this segment. That is, this segment will be disambiguated, using the information from this parse.</p
><p
>If you are using the <object
type="tTool"
>TreeTran</object
> program, you can save the results of the disambiguated parses in a file called Invoker.xml in the %TEMP% directory. You do this by using <object
type="tMenuItem"
>File / Save for TreeTran</object
> to make sure there is a check mark before it. Alternatively, you can click on the <img
src="resources/TreeTranOutput.png"
></img
> item in the tool bar.</p
><p
>When you are done looking at the results, close the <object
type="tPcPatrBrowser"
></object
> tool and you will return to <object
type="tPcPatrFLEx"
></object
>.</p
><p
>You can also select more than one segment. When you then use the “Parse &amp; show this segment” button, <object
type="tPcPatrFLEx"
></object
> will parse and show all of the selected segments.</p
></section1
><section1
id="sDisambiguating"
><secTitle
>Disambiguating a text</secTitle
><p
>When you use the “Disambiguate &amp; show this text” button, <object
type="tPcPatrFLEx"
></object
> will pass the parsing information for all segments in the text to <object
type="tPcPatr"
></object
>, along with the <object
type="tPcPatrGrammar"
></object
>, and process all those segments. Since all the segments are processed, this will probably take a while. So please be patient. The result will be shown in the slightly newer version of the <object
type="tPcPatrBrowser"
></object
> tool. See appendix <appendixRef
app="aPcPatrBrowser"
></appendixRef
> for more information on this tool.</p
><p
>Unlike with parsing a segment (see section <sectionRef
sec="sParsingSegment"
></sectionRef
>), the result will have as many “sentences” as there are segments in the text.</p
><p
>By default, <object
type="tPcPatrFLEx"
></object
> will disambiguate a segment in the <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
> database whenever the result of the parsing uniquely identifies the analysis of each word in the segment. For those cases where there are still ambiguities, you can use the <object
type="tPcPatrBrowser"
></object
> tool to select a given parse to use. Like with parsing a segment, you show the correct parse and then use <object
type="tMenuItem"
>Parse / Use This Parse</object
> menu item (or click on the <img
XeLaTeXSpecial="scaled='250'"
src="resources/yes.png"
></img
> tool bar button) to have this analysis be recorded in the <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
> database for this segment. That is, this segment will be disambiguated, using the information from this parse.</p
><p
>When you are done looking at the results, close the <object
type="tPcPatrBrowser"
></object
> tool and you will return to <object
type="tPcPatrFLEx"
></object
>.</p
></section1
><section1
id="sRemembering"
><secTitle
>Restarting <object
type="tPcPatrFLEx"
></object
></secTitle
><p
>Whenever you exit and restart <object
type="tPcPatrFLEx"
></object
>, it will do the following:</p
><ol
><li
>remember its window size, location, and layout;</li
><li
>remember which <object
type="tPcPatrGrammar"
></object
> file you last chose;</li
><li
>remember which text in that project you last selected; and</li
><li
>remember which segment in that text you last selected.<endnote
id="nMultiSelectRemember"
><p
>If you selected more than one segment, <object
type="tPcPatrFLEx"
></object
> will remember the bottom-most one.</p
></endnote
></li
></ol
></section1
><section1
id="sErrorMessage"
><secTitle
>Error messages</secTitle
><p
>In certain situations,<object
type="tPcPatrFLEx"
></object
> will issue an error message.</p
><p
>Table <tablenumberedRef
table="ntErrorMessages"
></tablenumberedRef
> lists the errors <object
type="tPcPatrFLEx"
></object
> reports along with a brief description of what the error might mean.</p
><tablenumbered
id="ntErrorMessages"
><table
border="1"
><caption
>Error messages</caption
><tr
><th
width="3in"
>Error</th
><th
width="2.85in"
>Meaning</th
></tr
><tr
><td
><object
type="tErrorType"
>The PC-PATR grammar file had an error in it and failed to load. We will show the error log after you click on OK. Please fix all errors in the grammar file and then try again.</object
></td
><td
>The <object
type="tPcPatrGrammar"
></object
> file being used has at least one error in it so the <object
type="tPcPatr"
></object
> program could not load and use it. The list of errors (and any warning messages, too) will be shown as soon as you click on the OK button. Note that in the error message file, the grammar file's location may look odd, but it is the same as what is showing before the “Browse” button.<endnote
id="nOddGrammarFile"
><p
>This happens for long file names or folder names. <object
type="tPcPatr"
></object
> is a “DOS” program and uses this cryptic format.</p
></endnote
> Also, the error messages and warnings may be a bit cryptic. See the PC-PATR Reference Manual for (some possible) help on this. (The manual is available via the "Help” button; see section <sectionRef
sec="sHelp"
></sectionRef
>.)</td
></tr
><tr
XeLaTeXSpecial="row-separation='-6pt'"
><td
> </td
><td
> </td
></tr
><tr
><td
><object
type="tErrorType"
>The following glosses contain a space. Please fix them and try again.</object
></td
><td
>At least one gloss used in one of the segments has a space in it. This will produce incorrect values in some of the files used. You will continue to get this message until you find and fix the gloss. You should be able to search for the gloss in Lexicon Edit in <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
>.</td
></tr
><tr
XeLaTeXSpecial="row-separation='-6pt'"
><td
> </td
><td
> </td
></tr
><tr
><td
><object
type="tErrorType"
>Segment number <object
type="tErrorMessageItem"
>number</object
> does not have any words in it. Please remove it or add words and try again.</object
></td
><td
>The indicated segment number does not have any words in it. You need to either remove the segment from the text or add some words to the segment in <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
>.</td
></tr
><tr
XeLaTeXSpecial="row-separation='-6pt'"
><td
> </td
><td
> </td
></tr
><tr
><td
><object
type="tErrorType"
>Sorry, but not every sentence has every word parsed. At least the word '<object
type="tErrorMessageItem"
>word</object
>' did not parse. Please make sure every word is parsed and try again.</object
></td
><td
>The indicated word does not have a parse. You need to give that word a parse in <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
>.</td
></tr
><tr
XeLaTeXSpecial="row-separation='-6pt'"
><td
> </td
><td
> </td
></tr
><tr
><td
><object
type="tErrorType"
>Sorry, but at least the word '<object
type="tErrorMessageItem"
>word</object
>' has an analysis with an invalid parse. Please make sure every word has valid parses and try again.</object
></td
><td
>The indicated word does not have a valid parse. You need to fix it in <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
>.</td
></tr
><tr
><td
> </td
><td
> </td
></tr
><tr
><td
><object
type="tErrorType"
>The read failed for segment number <object
type="tErrorMessageItem"
>number</object
>; <object
type="tErrorMessageItem"
>some error message</object
></object
></td
><td
>Something went wrong while processing the indicated segment number. This only shows when the “Run PC-PATR on each sentence individually” option is set (see section <sectionRef
sec="sAdvanced"
></sectionRef
>). It may be that the “Parsing time limit” was met and <object
type="tPcPatrFLEx"
></object
> had some issue trying to read one of its temporary files.</td
></tr
><tr
XeLaTeXSpecial="row-separation='-6pt'"
><td
> </td
><td
> </td
></tr
><tr
><td
><object
type="tErrorType"
>The PC-PATR processing failed! Perhaps there are incompatible feature values in one of the forms. We will show the error log after you click on OK. You may also want to try and run the PcPatrFLEx.bat file in the %TEMP% directory. This may or may not show which features are incompatible or some other PC-PATR error or warning message.</object
></td
><td
>When processing the input segment, the <object
type="tPcPatrGrammar"
></object
> file being used has at least one incompatibility in it. The list of errors (and any warning messages, too) will be shown as soon as you click on the OK button. Note that in the error message file, the grammar file's location may look odd, but it is the same as what is showing before the “Browse” button. Also, the error messages and warnings may be a bit cryptic. See the PC-PATR Reference Manual for (some possible) help on this. (The manual is available via the "Help” button; see section <sectionRef
sec="sHelp"
></sectionRef
>.)</td
></tr
></table
></tablenumbered
><p
>If you get an error message not in the list above, please report it. See section <sectionRef
sec="sSupport"
></sectionRef
>.</p
></section1
><section1
id="sKnownProblems"
><secTitle
>Known problems</secTitle
><p
>The following items are known to be less than desirable with this version of <object
type="tPcPatrFLEx"
></object
>:</p
><ol
><li
><object
type="tPcPatrFLEx"
></object
> only works with version <object
type="tFLExVersion"
></object
> or higher of <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
>.</li
><li
><object
type="tPcPatrFLEx"
></object
> assumes that the comment character in the <object
type="tPcPatrGrammar"
></object
> file is a vertical bar |. If you use something else, the parser will fail every segment.</li
><li
>When a word in <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
> does not have the “Word Cat" field filled out for a word in the interlinear, <object
type="tPcPatrFLEx"
></object
> will try and guess what the category of the word should be. It does this as follows:<ol
><li
>If there is only one morpheme, use its category.</li
><li
>If there are two or more morphemes and only one stem/root, find the stem and use its category. (This could be incorrect if one of the affixes is derivational and changes the category.)</li
><li
>If there are two or more stems, use the category of the left-most one. (This could be incorrect if some other stem is the correct category to use or if the stem compounding results in a different category or if one of the affixes is derivational and changes the category.)</li
></ol
><pc
>Therefore, it is always a good idea to overtly fill out the “Word Cat” field in <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
>.</pc
></li
><li
>When a morpheme in a word analysis has just the form but no sense or grammatical info, then the gloss showing in the output will be the gloss of the first sense of the entry for the morpheme.</li
><li
>When a morpheme in a word analysis has the form and grammatical info but no sense overtly indicated and there are two or more senses using the grammatical info in the entry, then the gloss showing in the output will be the gloss of the first sense which uses the grammatical info.</li
><li
>The user interface is in English only.</li
></ol
></section1
><section1
id="sSupport"
><secTitle
>Support</secTitle
><p
>If you have any questions with <object
type="tPcPatrFLEx"
></object
> or find bugs in it, please send an email to <link
href="mailto:blackhandrew@gmail.com"
>blackhandrew@gmail.com</link
>.</p
></section1
><backMatter
><appendix
id="aPcPatrBrowser"
><secTitle
>The <object
type="tPcPatrBrowser"
></object
> tool</secTitle
><p
>This appendix briefly covers the various parts of the <object
type="tPcPatrBrowser"
></object
> tool.</p
><section1
id="sOverview"
><secTitle
>Overview</secTitle
><p
>Example <exampleRef
letter="xPcPatrBrowser1"
num="xPcPatrBrowser1"
></exampleRef
> is a screen shot of what it looks like for one segment using one <object
type="tPcPatrGrammar"
></object
>.</p
><example
num="xPcPatrBrowser1"
><chart
><img
src="resources/PcPatrBrowser1.png"
></img
></chart
></example
><p
>There are four panes:</p
><ol
><li
>the segment in an interlinear form (at the top);</li
><li
>the syntactic tree, if any (left, middle);</li
><li
>the feature structure of the selected node in the tree (right, middle); and</li
><li
>the <object
type="tPcPatrGrammar"
></object
> file used (bottom)</li
></ol
><p
>When a node in the tree is selected, the bottom pane will show the rule in the <object
type="tPcPatrGrammar"
></object
> file that produced that node. In addition, the features for that selected node will appear in the right, middle pane. For example, when clicking on the IP node, it looked like example <exampleRef
letter="xPcPatrBrowser2"
num="xPcPatrBrowser2"
></exampleRef
>.</p
><example
num="xPcPatrBrowser2"
><chart
><img
src="resources/PcPatrBrowser2.png"
></img
></chart
></example
><p
>When there is more than one segment, you can use the <object
type="tMenuItem"
>Sentence</object
> menu item options or the first set of arrow buttons on the tool bar to navigate from one sentence to another. See appendix <appendixRef
app="sKeyBoardShortcuts"
></appendixRef
> for keyboard shortcuts. (Please note that with <object
type="tPcPatrFLEx"
></object
>, “sentence” is the same as “segment.”)</p
><p
>When there is more than one parse for a given segment, you can use the <object
type="tMenuItem"
>Parse</object
> menu item options or the second set of arrow buttons on the tool bar to navigate from one parse to another. See appendix <appendixRef
app="sKeyBoardShortcuts"
></appendixRef
> for keyboard shortcuts.</p
><p
>When you manually select to use a parse, then the entire tree description will be highlighted in yellow. In addition, the sentence number in the interlinear pane will be highlighted in yellow.</p
></section1
><section1
id="sRightToLeft"
><secTitle
>Right-to-left script</secTitle
><p
>If the vernacular language of your <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
> project is a right-to-left script, <object
type="tPcPatrFLEx"
></object
> will try to tell the <object
type="tPcPatrBrowser"
></object
> this. You may need to use the <object
type="tMenuItem"
>Language</object
> menu item, though, and uncheck and then check the “Use right-to-left orientation in parse tree and interlinear” option.</p
></section1
><section1
id="sKeyBoardShortcuts"
><secTitle
>Keyboard shortcuts</secTitle
><p
>To make processing texts faster, there are several keyboard shortcuts available. These only work when the “focus" is in the interlinear, tree, or feature panes. When <object
type="tPcPatrBrowser"
></object
> begins, the default is to have the “focus” on the feature pane. If you have clicked in the <object
type="tPcPatr"
></object
> grammar file pane or if you are using the keyboard to select a menu item, then these shortcuts will not work. You will need to click in the interlinear, tree, or feature pane first.</p
><p
>The shortcuts are as in example <exampleRef
letter="xPcPatrBowserShortcuts"
num="xPcPatrBowserShortcuts"
></exampleRef
>:</p
><example
num="xPcPatrBowserShortcuts"
><table
border="1"
><tr
><th
>Shortcut</th
><th
>Operation</th
></tr
><tr
><td
><object
type="tKey"
>Ctrl+Down Arrow</object
></td
><td
>Next sentence</td
></tr
><tr
><td
><object
type="tKey"
>Ctrl+Up Arrow</object
></td
><td
>Previous sentence</td
></tr
><tr
><td
><object
type="tKey"
>Ctrl+Right Arrow</object
></td
><td
>Next parse</td
></tr
><tr
><td
><object
type="tKey"
>Ctrl+Left Arrow</object
></td
><td
>Previous parse</td
></tr
><tr
><td
><object
type="tKey"
>Ctrl+Shift+Down Arrow</object
></td
><td
>Use this parse &amp; go to next sentence</td
></tr
><tr
><td
><object
type="tKey"
>Ctrl+/</object
><endnote
id="nCtrlSlash"
><p
>Some keyboards may not work with this sequence. Therefore we also offer the <object
type="tKey"
>Ctrl+L</object
> option.</p
></endnote
></td
><td
>Use this parse</td
></tr
><tr
><td
><object
type="tKey"
>Ctrl+L</object
></td
><td
>Use this parse</td
></tr
></table
></example
></section1
></appendix
><appendix
id="aGrammarAsXML"
><secTitle
>Another way to edit a <object
type="tPcPatrGrammar"
></object
> file</secTitle
><p
>One challenge with editing a <object
type="tPcPatrGrammar"
></object
> file is that it is a plain text file. If one wants to try and debug a grammar, one has to comment off a large amount of lines. It can get to be tricky.</p
><p
>Some tentative work has been done on a tool that will take a <object
type="tPcPatrGrammar"
></object
> file and convert it to a form that can be used in a tool like the <object
type="tXXE"
></object
>. Some advantages of this are that one can:</p
><ol
><li
>Quickly enable/disable given rules</li
><li
>Quickly enable/disable given templates</li
></ol
><p
>A major disadvantage is that once converted to this form, large <object
type="tPcPatrGrammar"
></object
> files are quite slow to load into the <object
type="tXXE"
></object
>.s</p
><p
>If you are interested in trying this, please contact <link
href="mailto:blackhandrew@gmail.com"
>blackhandrew@gmail.com</link
>.</p
></appendix
><endnotes
></endnotes
><references
></references
></backMatter
><languages
><language
id="lVernacular"
name="vernacular"
></language
><language
id="lGloss"
name="gloss"
></language
><language
id="en"
></language
><language
font-family="Ezra SIL"
id="lHebrew"
></language
><language
color="black"
font-family="Courier New"
id="lTreeExample"
></language
></languages
><types
><comment
>The following types are provided as pre-set examples. You may well want to create your own types that refer to one or more of these. You do that by typing in the names of the types in the types attribute of your type.</comment
><type
font-weight="bold"
id="tBold"
></type
><type
font-style="italic"
font-weight="bold"
id="tBoldItalic"
></type
><type
font-weight="bold"
id="tEmphasis"
></type
><type
id="tGrammaticalGloss"
types="tSmallCaps"
></type
><type
font-style="italic"
id="tItalic"
></type
><type
cssSpecial="text-decoration:none"
id="tNoOverline"
xsl-foSpecial="text-decoration=&quot;no-overline&quot;"
></type
><type
font-variant="normal"
id="tNoSmallCaps"
></type
><type
cssSpecial="text-decoration:none"
id="tNoStrikethrough"
xsl-foSpecial="text-decoration=&quot;no-line-through&quot;"
></type
><type
cssSpecial="text-decoration:none"
id="tNoUnderline"
xsl-foSpecial="text-decoration=&quot;no-underline&quot;"
></type
><type
cssSpecial="text-decoration:overline"
id="tOverline"
xsl-foSpecial="text-decoration=&quot;overline&quot;"
></type
><type
font-style="normal"
font-variant="normal"
font-weight="normal"
id="tRegular"
></type
><type
font-family="Charis SIL Small Caps"
id="tSmallCaps"
></type
><type
XeLaTeXSpecial="line-through"
cssSpecial="text-decoration:line-through"
id="tStrikethrough"
xsl-foSpecial="text-decoration=&quot;line-through&quot;"
></type
><type
XeLaTeXSpecial="subscript"
cssSpecial="vertical-align:sub;"
font-size="65%"
id="tSubscript"
xsl-foSpecial="baseline-shift='sub'"
></type
><type
XeLaTeXSpecial="superscript"
cssSpecial="vertical-align:super;"
font-size="65%"
id="tSuperscript"
xsl-foSpecial="baseline-shift='super'"
></type
><type
XeLaTeXSpecial="underline"
cssSpecial="text-decoration:underline"
id="tUnderline"
xsl-foSpecial="text-decoration=&quot;underline&quot;"
></type
><comment
>Add your custom types here.</comment
><type
id="tDialogTitle"
></type
><type
color="#800080"
font-family="Arial"
font-size="12pt"
font-style="italic"
id="tEmpty"
></type
><type
color="black"
font-style="italic"
id="tErrorMessageItem"
></type
><type
color="red"
id="tErrorType"
></type
><type
color="blue"
font-family="Arial"
id="tGloss"
></type
><type
color="#009900"
font-family="Charis SIL"
font-weight="bold"
id="tKey"
></type
><type
color="red"
font-family="Arial"
font-size="12pt"
id="tLexical"
></type
><type
color="maroon"
id="tMenuItem"
></type
><type
color="black"
font-family="Arial"
font-size="12pt"
id="tNonterminal"
></type
><type
before="PAWS"
color="navy"
font-style="italic"
id="tPAWS"
></type
><type
before="PC-PATR"
color="navy"
font-style="italic"
id="tPcPatr"
></type
><type
before="PC-PATR grammar"
id="tPcPatrGrammar"
></type
><type
before="9.1.14 Beta"
id="tFLExVersion"
></type
><type
before="700072"
id="tFWDatabaseVersion"
></type
><type
before="PcPatr Browser"
color="navy"
font-style="italic"
id="tPcPatrBrowser"
></type
><type
before="Use PC-PATR with FLEx"
color="navy"
font-style="italic"
id="tPcPatrFLEx"
></type
><type
before="FieldWorks Language Explorer"
color="navy"
font-style="italic"
id="tFieldWorks"
></type
><type
before="FLEx"
color="navy"
font-style="italic"
id="tFLEx"
></type
><type
color="black"
font-family="Monospaced"
font-weight="bold"
id="tSynTagmeme"
></type
><type
color="navy"
id="tTool"
></type
><type
before="XMLmind XML Editor"
color="navy"
font-style="italic"
id="tXXE"
></type
></types
><contentControl
><contentTypes
><contentType
id="ctKeyColor"
>Tree description in color/font</contentType
><contentType
id="ctRegular"
>Tree description plain</contentType
></contentTypes
><contentControlChoices
><contentControlChoice
active="yes"
exclude="ctKeyColor"
>Tree description regular</contentControlChoice
><contentControlChoice
active="no"
>Tree description color/font</contentControlChoice
></contentControlChoices
></contentControl
></lingPaper
><publisherStyleSheet
><publisherStyleSheetName
>SIL International Paper Stylesheet</publisherStyleSheetName
><publisherStyleSheetVersion
>0.4.5</publisherStyleSheetVersion
><pageLayout
><pageWidth
>8.5in</pageWidth
><pageHeight
>11in</pageHeight
><pageTopMargin
>.7in</pageTopMargin
><pageBottomMargin
>.675in</pageBottomMargin
><pageInsideMargin
>1.5in</pageInsideMargin
><pageOutsideMargin
>1in</pageOutsideMargin
><useThesisSubmissionStyle
></useThesisSubmissionStyle
><headerMargin
>.25in</headerMargin
><footerMargin
>.25in</footerMargin
><paragraphIndent
>1em</paragraphIndent
><blockQuoteIndent
>.125in</blockQuoteIndent
><lineSpacing
></lineSpacing
><defaultFontFamily
>Charis SIL</defaultFontFamily
><basicPointSize
>12</basicPointSize
><footnotePointSize
>10</footnotePointSize
><footnoteLine
leaderlength="2in"
leaderpattern="rule"
textalign="left"
></footnoteLine
><linkLayout
color="blue"
decoration="underline"
><abbrRefLinkLayout
></abbrRefLinkLayout
><appendixRefLinkLayout
></appendixRefLinkLayout
><citationLinkLayout
></citationLinkLayout
><contentsLinkLayout
></contentsLinkLayout
><endnoteRefLinkLayout
></endnoteRefLinkLayout
><exampleRefLinkLayout
></exampleRefLinkLayout
><genericRefLinkLayout
></genericRefLinkLayout
><indexLinkLayout
></indexLinkLayout
><interlinearRefLinkLayout
></interlinearRefLinkLayout
><linkLinkLayout
></linkLinkLayout
><sectionRefLinkLayout
></sectionRefLinkLayout
><urlLinkLayout
></urlLinkLayout
></linkLayout
><headerFooterPageStyles
font-family="Times New Roman"
font-size="9pt"
font-style="italic"
><headerFooterFirstPage
><header
><leftHeaderFooterItem
><nothing
></nothing
></leftHeaderFooterItem
><centerHeaderFooterItem
><nothing
></nothing
></centerHeaderFooterItem
><rightHeaderFooterItem
><nothing
></nothing
></rightHeaderFooterItem
></header
><footer
><leftHeaderFooterItem
><nothing
></nothing
></leftHeaderFooterItem
><centerHeaderFooterItem
><pageNumber
font-size="smaller"
font-style="italic"
></pageNumber
></centerHeaderFooterItem
><rightHeaderFooterItem
><nothing
></nothing
></rightHeaderFooterItem
></footer
></headerFooterFirstPage
><headerFooterOddEvenPages
><headerFooterEvenPage
><header
><leftHeaderFooterItem
><pageNumber
font-size="smaller"
font-style="italic"
></pageNumber
></leftHeaderFooterItem
><centerHeaderFooterItem
><nothing
></nothing
></centerHeaderFooterItem
><rightHeaderFooterItem
><paperTitle
font-size="smaller"
font-style="italic"
></paperTitle
></rightHeaderFooterItem
></header
><footer
><leftHeaderFooterItem
><nothing
></nothing
></leftHeaderFooterItem
><centerHeaderFooterItem
><nothing
></nothing
></centerHeaderFooterItem
><rightHeaderFooterItem
><nothing
></nothing
></rightHeaderFooterItem
></footer
></headerFooterEvenPage
><headerFooterOddPage
><header
><leftHeaderFooterItem
><sectionTitle
font-size="smaller"
font-style="italic"
></sectionTitle
></leftHeaderFooterItem
><centerHeaderFooterItem
><nothing
></nothing
></centerHeaderFooterItem
><rightHeaderFooterItem
><pageNumber
font-size="smaller"
font-style="italic"
></pageNumber
></rightHeaderFooterItem
></header
><footer
><leftHeaderFooterItem
><nothing
></nothing
></leftHeaderFooterItem
><centerHeaderFooterItem
><nothing
></nothing
></centerHeaderFooterItem
><rightHeaderFooterItem
><nothing
></nothing
></rightHeaderFooterItem
></footer
></headerFooterOddPage
></headerFooterOddEvenPages
></headerFooterPageStyles
></pageLayout
><frontMatterLayout
><comment
>Front Matter Layout</comment
><titleLayout
font-size="18pt"
font-weight="bold"
pagebreakbefore="yes"
spacebefore="1.25in"
startonoddpage="yes"
textalign="center"
></titleLayout
><subtitleLayout
font-size="14pt"
font-weight="bold"
textalign="center"
></subtitleLayout
><authorLayout
font-style="italic"
textalign="center"
></authorLayout
><affiliationLayout
font-style="italic"
textalign="center"
></affiliationLayout
><emailAddressLayout
font-size="90%"
textalign="center"
></emailAddressLayout
><presentedAtLayout
font-size="10pt"
textalign="center"
textbefore="Presented at "
></presentedAtLayout
><dateLayout
font-size="10pt"
textalign="center"
></dateLayout
><versionLayout
font-size="10pt"
textalign="center"
></versionLayout
><contentsLayout
font-size="14pt"
font-weight="bold"
spaceafter="12pt"
spacebefore="24pt"
textalign="center"
useperiodafterappendixletter="yes"
></contentsLayout
><abstractLayout
font-size="14pt"
font-weight="bold"
spaceafter="12pt"
spacebefore="24pt"
textalign="center"
></abstractLayout
><acknowledgementsLayout
font-size="14pt"
font-weight="bold"
spaceafter="12pt"
spacebefore="24pt"
textalign="center"
></acknowledgementsLayout
><prefaceLayout
font-size="14pt"
font-weight="bold"
spaceafter="12pt"
spacebefore="24pt"
textalign="center"
></prefaceLayout
></frontMatterLayout
><bodyLayout
><comment
>Body Layout</comment
><section1Layout
><sectionTitleLayout
font-size="14pt"
font-weight="bold"
spaceafter="12pt"
spacebefore="24pt"
textalign="center"
></sectionTitleLayout
></section1Layout
><section2Layout
><sectionTitleLayout
font-size="12pt"
font-weight="bold"
spaceafter="12pt"
spacebefore="12pt"
textalign="start"
></sectionTitleLayout
></section2Layout
><section3Layout
><sectionTitleLayout
font-style="italic"
font-weight="bold"
spaceafter="12pt"
spacebefore="12pt"
textalign="start"
></sectionTitleLayout
></section3Layout
><section4Layout
><sectionTitleLayout
font-style="italic"
spaceafter="12pt"
spacebefore="12pt"
textalign="start"
></sectionTitleLayout
></section4Layout
><section5Layout
ignore="yes"
><sectionTitleLayout
></sectionTitleLayout
></section5Layout
><section6Layout
ignore="yes"
><sectionTitleLayout
></sectionTitleLayout
></section6Layout
></bodyLayout
><backMatterLayout
><comment
>Back Matter Layout</comment
><acknowledgementsLayout
font-size="14pt"
font-weight="bold"
spaceafter="12pt"
spacebefore="24pt"
textalign="center"
></acknowledgementsLayout
><appendixLayout
><appendixTitleLayout
font-size="14pt"
font-weight="bold"
spaceafter="12pt"
spacebefore="24pt"
textafterletter=". "
textalign="center"
></appendixTitleLayout
></appendixLayout
><glossaryLayout
font-size="14pt"
font-weight="bold"
spaceafter="12pt"
spacebefore="24pt"
textalign="center"
></glossaryLayout
><referencesTitleLayout
font-size="14pt"
font-weight="bold"
spaceafter="12pt"
spacebefore="24pt"
textalign="center"
></referencesTitleLayout
><xi:include
href="SILInternationalReferencesStylesheet.xml"
xpointer="element(/1)"
xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
></xi:include
><indexLayout
font-size="14pt"
font-weight="bold"
spaceafter="12pt"
spacebefore="24pt"
textalign="center"
></indexLayout
></backMatterLayout
><contentLayout
><comment
>Document Content Layout</comment
><exampleLayout
indent-after=".125in"
indent-before=".125in"
></exampleLayout
><interlinearSourceStyle
></interlinearSourceStyle
><endnoteRefLayout
></endnoteRefLayout
><figureLayout
captionLocation="after"
><figureLabelLayout
textafter=" "
></figureLabelLayout
><figureNumberLayout
></figureNumberLayout
><figureCaptionLayout
textbefore=" "
></figureCaptionLayout
></figureLayout
><figureRefLayout
></figureRefLayout
><tablenumberedLayout
captionLocation="after"
><tablenumberedLabelLayout
font-weight="bold"
textafter=" "
></tablenumberedLabelLayout
><tablenumberedNumberLayout
textafter=": "
></tablenumberedNumberLayout
><tablenumberedCaptionLayout
font-style="italic"
textbefore="  "
></tablenumberedCaptionLayout
></tablenumberedLayout
><tablenumberedRefLayout
></tablenumberedRefLayout
></contentLayout
></publisherStyleSheet
></styledPaper
></xlingpaper
>
