<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE xlingpaper PUBLIC "-//XMLmind//DTD XLingPap//EN"
"XLingPap.dtd">
<xlingpaper
version="2.24.0"
><styledPaper
><lingPaper
automaticallywrapinterlinears="yes"
version="2.28.0"
><frontMatter
><title
><object
type="tToneParsFLEx"
></object
> User Documentation</title
><author
>H. Andrew Black</author
><affiliation
>SIL International</affiliation
><emailAddress
>blackhandrew@gmail.com</emailAddress
><date
>29 August, 2023</date
><version
>Version 0.6.0 Beta</version
><version
>Copyright © 2019-2023 SIL International</version
><contents
></contents
></frontMatter
><section1
id="sIntro"
><secTitle
>Introduction</secTitle
><p
><object
type="tToneParsFLEx"
></object
> is a tool that works as a utility in <object
type="tFieldWorks"
></object
> (aka <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
>). <object
type="tToneParsFLEx"
></object
> runs either the <object
type="tXAmple"
></object
> program or the <object
type="tHermitCrab"
></object
> program followed by the <object
type="tTonePars"
></object
> program on a text or a portion of a text that exists in a <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
> project. You tell <object
type="tToneParsFLEx"
></object
> the <object
type="tTonePars"
></object
> rule file to use as well as an <object
type="tXAmple"
></object
> input control file.<endnote
id="nIntextCtrl"
><p
>When using the <object
type="tHermitCrab"
></object
> program, you still need an input control file in order to define the set of input changes.  These are normally used to remove tone markings from an input word.</p
></endnote
> Then you can choose a text or a portion of that text and ask <object
type="tToneParsFLEx"
></object
> to process it. The result will show in <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
> the same as it does when using either of the two morphological parsers that come with <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
>.</p
><p
>When using the <object
type="tXAmple"
></object
> program, the input to the <object
type="tXAmple"
></object
> program is the same as what <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
> uses for the default morphological parser (which is <object
type="tXAmple"
></object
>). This means that you must control <object
type="tXAmple"
></object
> using the capabilities <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
> offers, not what you may have used with <object
type="tAmple"
></object
> via, say, <object
type="tCarlaStudio"
></object
>.</p
><p
><object
type="tToneParsFLEx"
></object
> works with version <object
type="tFLExVersion"
></object
> or higher of <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
> and is only available on 64-bit Windows computers.</p
><section2
id="sInstallation"
><secTitle
>Installation</secTitle
><p
>To install <object
type="tToneParsFLEx"
></object
>, obtain the installer from <link
href="https://github.com/sillsdev/pcpatrflex/blob/ToneParsFLEx/InstallerTonePars/Output/UseToneParsWithFLExDllSetup.exe"
>https://​github.com/​sillsdev/​pcpatrflex/​blob/​ToneParsFLEx/​InstallerTonePars/​Output/​Use​Tone​Pars​With​FLExDll​Setup.exe</link
>. The installer will check to see if you have installed <object
type="tFieldWorks"
></object
> version 9. If not, it will abort.</p
><p
>We recommend that you close <object
type="tFieldWorks"
></object
> before running the <object
type="tToneParsFLEx"
></object
> installer.</p
></section2
><section2
id="sInvokingFromFLEx"
><secTitle
>Invoking <object
type="tToneParsFLEx"
></object
> from within <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
></secTitle
><p
>While running <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
>, use <object
type="tMenuItem"
>Tools</object
> menu item / <object
type="tMenuItem"
>Utilities...</object
>. Find the “Use TonePars with FLEx” item, check it, and then click on the “Run Checked Utilities Now” button.</p
></section2
><section2
id="sInitialRun"
><secTitle
>Initial invocation</secTitle
><p
>The first time you invoke <object
type="tToneParsFLEx"
></object
> on a <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
> database, it will automatically add to your <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
> database the following:</p
><ol
><li
>a custom field to each sense (called “ToneParsSense”);</li
><li
>a custom field for each allomorph/lexeme form<endnote
id="nLexemeFormAlloProp"
><p
>The current version of <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
> does not show this custom field on Lexeme Form. You can set it, though, by swapping the lexeme form with an allomorph. See the <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
> help system for how to do this.</p
></endnote
> (called “ToneParsForm”); and</li
><li
>a custom list (called “TonePars Properties”). You use this custom list to create any allomorph or morpheme properties used in your <object
type="tTonePars"
></object
> rule file.</li
></ol
><p
>The names shown above are always in the English analysis writing system and English is the only writing system containing these names.</p
><p
>You can find the custom list by clicking on the “Lists” button in <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
>.</p
></section2
><section2
id="sAppearance"
><secTitle
>Appearance</secTitle
><p
><object
type="tToneParsFLEx"
></object
> looks like what is shown in <exampleRef
letter="xNewPcPatrFLEx"
num="xNewPcPatrFLEx"
></exampleRef
>.</p
><example
num="xNewPcPatrFLEx"
><chart
><img
XeLaTeXSpecial="scaled='600'"
src="resources/ToneParsFLExEmpty.png "
width="450"
></img
></chart
></example
><p
>The texts in the <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
> database are shown in the left pane and the segments of the first text are shown in the right pane.</p
><p
>There are buttons you can click. Each is discussed in section <sectionRef
sec="sButtons"
></sectionRef
> below.</p
></section2
></section1
><section1
id="sButtons"
><secTitle
>Buttons and check boxes</secTitle
><p
>You control <object
type="tToneParsFLEx"
></object
> by using the various buttons and check boxes. This section briefly describes them.</p
><section2
id="sToneParsRuleBrowse"
><secTitle
><object
type="tTonePars"
></object
> rule file Browse button</secTitle
><p
>To choose which <object
type="tTonePars"
></object
> rule file to use, click on the topmost Browse button. By convention, <object
type="tTonePars"
></object
> rule files have an extension of “.ctl” so this is what the file browser uses.</p
></section2
><section2
id="sAmpleIBrowsentxCtl"
><secTitle
><object
type="tAmple"
></object
> intx ctl file Browse button</secTitle
><p
>As you most likely already know, when using <object
type="tTonePars"
></object
>, one first parses a text via <object
type="tAmple"
></object
> but as part of the processing, <object
type="tAmple"
></object
> strips out tone marking. The result is then passed to <object
type="tTonePars"
></object
>. In order to correctly strip out the tone markings, <object
type="tToneParsFLEx"
></object
> needs to know the location of the input text control file needed. To choose which input text control file to use, click on the Browse button. By convention, <object
type="tAmple"
></object
> input text control file names end with “intx.ctl” so this is what the file browser uses.</p
><p
>If you are using the <object
type="tHermitCrab"
></object
> parser in <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
>, you will still need to specify this file.  <object
type="tToneParsFLEx"
></object
> will read the input text changes from this file and apply them before parsing a word via <object
type="tHermitCrab"
></object
>.</p
></section2
><section2
id="sTraceToneProcessing"
><secTitle
>Trace Tone Processing check box</secTitle
><p
>The next item is a check box with a label of “Trace Tone Processing.” When working with <object
type="tTonePars"
></object
>, you often need to get a trace of what the tool is doing. When this check box is checked, <object
type="tToneParsFLEx"
></object
> invokes <object
type="tTonePars"
></object
> with tracing turned on. The log file will show the results of the tracing process. See section <sectionRef
sec="sTracingOptions"
></sectionRef
> for the various tracing options available and see section <sectionRef
sec="sShowLog"
></sectionRef
> for how to see the resulting log file.</p
></section2
><section2
id="sTracingOptions"
><secTitle
>Tracing Options button</secTitle
><p
>When you click on the “Tracing Options” button, it brings up a dialog box that looks like what is in example <exampleRef
letter="xTracingOptionsDIalog"
num="xTracingOptionsDIalog"
></exampleRef
>:</p
><example
num="xTracingOptionsDIalog"
><chart
><img
src="resources/TracingOptionsDialog.png"
width="450"
></img
></chart
></example
><p
>The options listed are the same as the options available in <object
type="tCarlaStudio"
></object
>.</p
></section2
><section2
id="sShowLog"
><secTitle
>Show Log button</secTitle
><p
>When you click on the “Show Log” button, the log file generated by the last invocation of <object
type="tTonePars"
></object
> will be displayed.</p
></section2
><section2
id="sHelp"
><secTitle
>Help button</secTitle
><p
>The “Help...” button is used to get this user documentation file, show the TonePars Manual, show the TonePars Grammar documentation file, or show the “About” dialog box.</p
></section2
><section2
id="sVerifyControlFileInformation"
><secTitle
>Verify Control File Information check box</secTitle
><p
>One run time option for <object
type="tTonePars"
></object
> is to verify various pieces of information. When the “Verify Control File Information’ check box is checked, <object
type="tToneParsFLEx"
></object
> will invoke <object
type="tTonePars"
></object
> in such a way that this information will be included in the log file. You can see it by showing the log file (see section <sectionRef
sec="sShowLog"
></sectionRef
>).</p
></section2
><section2
id="sIgenoreContext"
><secTitle
>Ignore Context check box</secTitle
><p
>When the “Ignore Context” check box is checked, <object
type="tToneParsFLEx"
></object
> will determine all the unique word forms in the text (or segment) and parse them. This means that each unique word form is parsed once and only once no matter how many times it appears in the text (or segment). It therefore runs much faster especially on a text. This is the default setting.</p
><p
>When this check box is not checked, then the input to parsing is like it is for <object
type="tAmple"
></object
>: Each word is parsed in turn, even if it occurs multiple times. So this takes longer to parse. On the other hand, if your tone rules need to go across word boundaries,<endnote
id="nEdgeRules"
><p
>That is, if some of your tone rules are edge rules…</p
></endnote
> then you may need to process texts (and segments) this way.</p
></section2
><section2
id="sRefresh"
><secTitle
>Refresh Texts button</secTitle
><p
>Whenever you click on the “Refresh Texts” button or press the <object
type="tKey"
>F5</object
> key, <object
type="tToneParsFLEx"
></object
> will reload all of the texts from <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
>. This is so if you know that if some texts have been added, deleted or changed since you first started <object
type="tToneParsFLEx"
></object
>, you can get the most current list of texts.</p
></section2
><section2
id="sDisambiguate"
><secTitle
>Parse this text button</secTitle
><p
>Above the pane containing the texts is a button labeled “Parse this text.” You use this button to parse this entire text via the current parser chosen in <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
><endnote
id="nChooseParser"
><p
>To set the parser in <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
>, use <object
type="tMenuItem"
>Parser</object
> menu item / <object
type="tMenuItem"
>Choose Parser</object
>.</p
></endnote
> and then <object
type="tTonePars"
></object
>. Before parsing the text, <object
type="tToneParsFLEx"
></object
> will check to make sure the following files exist:</p
><ol
><li
>The <object
type="tAmple"
></object
> intx control file.</li
><li
>The <object
type="tTonePars"
></object
> rule file.</li
><li
>The segments file from the <object
type="tTonePars"
></object
> rule file.</li
></ol
><pc
>If any cannot be found, then an error message showing the unfound file(s) will show. The parsing will not be done.</pc
><p
>If these files are there, then the mouse icon will change to the “busy” shape until it is done. The results will show in <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
> the same way as using one of the morphological parsers that come with <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
> show their result. It is easiest to see this in the “Texts &amp; Words" / “Interlinear Texts" view or the “Texts &amp; Words" / “Word Analyses” view.</p
><p
>During the parsing process, the bottom left of the window will display the current step that is occurring.</p
></section2
><section2
id="sParse"
><secTitle
>Parse this segment button</secTitle
><p
>Above the pane containing the segments of the selected text is a button labeled “Parse this segment.” You use this button to parse this particular segment via the current parser chosen in <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
><endnote
id="nChooseParser2"
><p
>To set the parser in <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
>, use <object
type="tMenuItem"
>Parser</object
> menu item / <object
type="tMenuItem"
>Choose Parser</object
>.</p
></endnote
>  and then <object
type="tTonePars"
></object
>. Before parsing the text, <object
type="tToneParsFLEx"
></object
> will check to make sure the following files exist:</p
><ol
><li
>The <object
type="tAmple"
></object
> intx control file.</li
><li
>The <object
type="tTonePars"
></object
> rule file.</li
><li
>The segments file from the <object
type="tTonePars"
></object
> rule file.</li
></ol
><pc
>If any cannot be found, then an error message showing the unfound file(s) will show. The parsing will not be done.</pc
><p
>If these files are there, then the mouse icon will change to the “busy” shape until it is done. The results will show in <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
> the same way as using one of the morphological parsers that come with <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
> show their result. It is easiest to see this in the “Texts &amp; Words" / “Interlinear Texts" view or the “Texts &amp; Words" / “Word Analyses” view.</p
><p
>During the parsing process, the bottom left of the window will display the current step that is occurring.</p
></section2
></section1
><section1
id="sMaxAnalyses"
><secTitle
>Maximum analyses setting for <object
type="tXAmple"
></object
></secTitle
><p
>By default, <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
> only returns a maximum of the first twenty parses found by <object
type="tXAmple"
></object
>. This is often very reasonable when one is not using <object
type="tTonePars"
></object
>. With <object
type="tTonePars"
></object
>, however, this could easily be too few. In one <object
type="tTonePars"
></object
> project, there are twenty-six nulls possible for various tone possibilities within a given word. Only returning twenty will never do. We have changed the default to be 1000. If this is ridiculously high for your situation, you can always change the setting to a different number. To do so, in the main <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
> window, use the <object
type="tMenuItem"
>Parser / Edit Parser Parameters…</object
> menu item and set the “MaxAnalyses” value to what you need. Note that a value of -1 will be treated as 1000 by <object
type="tToneParsFLEx"
></object
>.</p
><p
>This situation is only for when the using the <object
type="tXAmple"
></object
> parser in <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
>.  There is no such restriction when using the <object
type="tHermitCrab"
></object
> parser.</p
></section1
><section1
id="sRemembering"
><secTitle
>Restarting <object
type="tToneParsFLEx"
></object
></secTitle
><p
>Whenever you exit and restart <object
type="tToneParsFLEx"
></object
>, it will do the following:</p
><ol
><li
>remember the size and position of the <object
type="tToneParsFLEx"
></object
> window;</li
><li
>remember which <object
type="tTonePars"
></object
> rule file you last chose;</li
><li
>remember which <object
type="tAmple"
></object
> intx ctl file you last chose;</li
><li
>remember the settings of “Trace Tone Processing,” “Tracing Options.” and “Verify Control File Information;”</li
><li
>remember which text in that project you last selected; and</li
><li
>remember which segment in that text you last selected.</li
></ol
></section1
><section1
id="sKnownProblems"
><secTitle
>Known problems</secTitle
><p
>The following items are known to be less than desirable with this version of <object
type="tToneParsFLEx"
></object
>:</p
><ol
><li
><object
type="tToneParsFLEx"
></object
> only works with version <object
type="tFLExVersion"
></object
> or higher of <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
>.</li
><li
>The location of the <object
type="tTonePars"
></object
> rule file and the <object
type="tAmple"
></object
> intx ctl file work best if the path to them does not contain any spaces.</li
><li
>The location of the segments file within the <object
type="tTonePars"
></object
> rule file needs to follow the MSDOS 8.3 file convention or it may not be found. See <link
href="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/4051088/get-dos-path-instead-of-windows-path"
>here</link
> for some ways to do that.</li
><li
>If a lexical entry in <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
> is marked as either a proclitic or an enclitic, it may not parse correctly. This is because <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
> creates two entries for it with the same morphname; one is as an affix and the other is as a root. <object
type="tToneParsFLEx"
></object
> may not process it correctly due to this ambiguity. It might be possible, however, to model these as affixes instead of as proclitics/ enclitics.</li
><li
>When you need to mark an allomorph with an allomorph property using the custom field of “ToneParsForm,” the custom field only shows up in <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
> for an allomorph. It does not show for a lexeme form. To add an allomorph property to a lexeme form, you can use the “Swap Lexeme Form with Allomorph” capability (on the Lexeme Form item) or the “Swap Allomorph with Lexeme Form” capability (on the Allomorph item). See the <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
> help system for how to do this.</li
><li
>The current version of <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
> does not always parse a capitalized word. Here is one way to try and deal with this:<endnote
id="nLT5722"
><p
>This is a slightly modified version of Kevin Warfel's work-around in <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
>'s issue tracking system at <link
href="https://jira.sil.org/browse/LT-5722"
>LT-5722</link
>.</p
></endnote
><ol
><li
>Go to the Baseline tab and change the upper-case letter to lower case.</li
><li
>Return to the Analyze tab and parse the segment in <object
type="tToneParsFLEx"
></object
>.</li
><li
>If there are multiple parser-generated analyses available, select the correct one, then click on the green check mark. (This marks that particular analysis as “user-approved” in the Word Analyses area, which the interlinear view uses as one of its default sources.)</li
><li
>Go back to the Baseline tab and change the letter back to upper case.</li
><li
>Return to the Analyze tab, click on the word, then use the drop-down arrow on the Morphemes line to select the lower-case form of the word. (This should enable FLEx to associate the previously generated analysis of the lower-case form with the current instance.)</li
></ol
></li
><li
>The user interface is in English only.</li
><li
>Be sure to close <object
type="tToneParsFLEx"
></object
> *before* you close <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
> or there may a version of <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
> running in the background. This can prevent <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
> from starting again.</li
><li
><object
type="tToneParsFLEx"
></object
> produces a copy of the Tone Rule file with an extension of “.hvo” in the directory where the Tone Rule file is. This file is used by <object
type="tTonePars"
></object
> in order to correctly handle “morphname is” statements in the rule file.</li
></ol
></section1
><section1
id="sOutputFiles"
><secTitle
>Output files</secTitle
><p
>When you parse a segment or a text, <object
type="tToneParsFLEx"
></object
> produces several temporary files. There may be times when seeing these files will prove useful, especially if you are used to seeing such files in <object
type="tCarlaStudio"
></object
>. To see the files, open a Windows Explorer window in the temp directory. One way to do this is to click in the address bar and then replace its contents with “%TEMP%” (without the quotes). Next, view the directory showing details and click on the "Date modified” column header so that the most recently used files are ordered first. The files used by <object
type="tToneParsFLEx"
></object
> are shown in example <exampleRef
letter="xTempFiles"
num="xTempFiles"
></exampleRef
> below.</p
><example
num="xTempFiles"
><table
border="1"
><tr
><th
>File name</th
><th
>Contents</th
></tr
><tr
><td
><object
type="tItalic"
>FLExProjectName</object
>adctl.txt</td
><td
>The analysis data control file used by <object
type="tXAmple"
></object
>.</td
></tr
><tr
><td
><object
type="tItalic"
>FLExProjectName</object
>gram.txt</td
><td
>The <object
type="tTool"
>PC-PATR</object
> grammar file used by <object
type="tXAmple"
></object
>. (Most likely this file will not make much sense unless you have a lot of experience with <object
type="tTool"
>PC-PATR</object
> grammar files.</td
></tr
><tr
><td
><object
type="tItalic"
>FLExProjectName</object
>lex.txt</td
><td
>The lexicon file used by <object
type="tXAmple"
></object
>.</td
></tr
><tr
><td
><object
type="tItalic"
>FLExProjectName</object
>TPadctl.txt</td
><td
>The analysis data control file used by <object
type="tTonePars"
></object
>.</td
></tr
><tr
><td
><object
type="tItalic"
>FLExProjectName</object
>TPlex.txt</td
><td
>The lexicon file used by <object
type="tTonePars"
></object
>.</td
></tr
><tr
><td
>ToneParsCmd.cmd</td
><td
>A file containing the files loaded by <object
type="tTonePars"
></object
>.</td
></tr
><tr
><td
>ToneParsFLEx.bat</td
><td
>The batch file which invokes <object
type="tTonePars"
></object
>.</td
></tr
><tr
><td
>ToneParsInvoker.ana</td
><td
>The ANA file produced by <object
type="tXAmple"
></object
> which is used as the input to <object
type="tTonePars"
></object
>.</td
></tr
><tr
><td
>ToneParsInvoker.ant</td
><td
>The output ANA file produced by <object
type="tTonePars"
></object
>.</td
></tr
><tr
><td
>ToneParsInvoker.log</td
><td
>The log file produced by <object
type="tTonePars"
></object
>. See section <sectionRef
sec="sShowLog"
></sectionRef
> for an easier way to see this.</td
></tr
></table
></example
><p
>Note that most of these files use numbers instead of text for things like morph-names. This is how it needs to be done for <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
> to properly process the data.</p
></section1
><section1
id="sErrorMessages"
><secTitle
>Error messages</secTitle
><p
>When parsing a segment or a text, you may see an error message box. The following tries to explain them.</p
><table
border="1"
><tr
><th
>Message</th
><th
>Explanation</th
></tr
><tr
><td
align="left"
valign="top"
><object
type="tErrorType"
>Could not find the AMPLE intx.ctl file at: <object
type="tItalic"
>file location</object
></object
></td
><td
align="left"
valign="top"
>This appears when you try to parse a text or a segment and the <object
type="tAmple"
></object
> intx ctrl file was not found.</td
></tr
><tr
><td
align="left"
valign="top"
></td
><td
align="left"
valign="top"
></td
></tr
><tr
><td
align="left"
valign="top"
><object
type="tErrorType"
>Could not find the segments file in the TonePars rule file at: <object
type="tItalic"
>file location</object
>. Remember that this file path may need to be in 8.3 format.</object
></td
><td
align="left"
valign="top"
>This appears when you try to parse a text or a segment and while the <object
type="tTonePars"
></object
> rule file was found, the file indicated by the \segments field was not found. See section <sectionRef
sec="sKnownProblems"
></sectionRef
>, item 3.</td
></tr
><tr
><td
align="left"
valign="top"
></td
><td
align="left"
valign="top"
></td
></tr
><tr
><td
align="left"
valign="top"
><object
type="tErrorType"
>Could not find the TonePars rule file at: <object
type="tItalic"
>file location</object
></object
></td
><td
align="left"
valign="top"
>This appears when you try to parse a text or a segment and the <object
type="tTonePars"
></object
> rule file was not found.</td
></tr
><tr
><td
align="left"
valign="top"
></td
><td
align="left"
valign="top"
></td
></tr
><tr
><td
align="left"
valign="top"
><object
type="tErrorType"
>Log file does not exist; please parse a segment or a text.</object
></td
><td
align="left"
valign="top"
>This appears when you try to show the log file and we could not find one.</td
></tr
><tr
><td
align="left"
valign="top"
></td
><td
align="left"
valign="top"
></td
></tr
><tr
><td
align="left"
valign="top"
><object
type="tErrorType"
>Somehow the result file was empty. Please try again.</object
></td
><td
align="left"
valign="top"
>We detected that the resulting <object
type="tTonePars"
></object
> file was empty. This seems to be a result of some kind of timing issue.</td
></tr
><tr
><td
align="left"
valign="top"
></td
><td
align="left"
valign="top"
></td
></tr
><tr
><td
align="left"
valign="top"
><object
type="tErrorType"
>There was a timing problem. Check if the \segments path to xxxTP.seg in xxxTP.ctl is correct. See the Log file.</object
></td
><td
align="left"
valign="top"
>For some reason, the running of <object
type="tTonePars"
></object
> did not finish. One possibility is that the \segments field in the <object
type="tTonePars"
></object
> rule file had a problem or could not be found.</td
></tr
></table
></section1
><section1
id="sSupport"
><secTitle
>Support</secTitle
><p
>If you have any questions with <object
type="tToneParsFLEx"
></object
> or find bugs in it, please send an email to <link
href="mailto:blackhandrew@gmail.com"
>blackhandrew@gmail.com</link
>.</p
></section1
><backMatter
><endnotes
></endnotes
><references
></references
></backMatter
><languages
><language
id="lVernacular"
name="vernacular"
></language
><language
id="lGloss"
name="gloss"
></language
><language
id="en"
></language
><language
font-family="Ezra SIL"
id="lHebrew"
></language
><language
color="black"
font-family="Courier New"
id="lTreeExample"
></language
></languages
><types
><comment
>The following types are provided as pre-set examples. You may well want to create your own types that refer to one or more of these. You do that by typing in the names of the types in the types attribute of your type.</comment
><type
font-weight="bold"
id="tBold"
></type
><type
font-style="italic"
font-weight="bold"
id="tBoldItalic"
></type
><type
font-weight="bold"
id="tEmphasis"
></type
><type
id="tGrammaticalGloss"
types="tSmallCaps"
></type
><type
font-style="italic"
id="tItalic"
></type
><type
cssSpecial="text-decoration:none"
id="tNoOverline"
xsl-foSpecial="text-decoration=&quot;no-overline&quot;"
></type
><type
font-variant="normal"
id="tNoSmallCaps"
></type
><type
cssSpecial="text-decoration:none"
id="tNoStrikethrough"
xsl-foSpecial="text-decoration=&quot;no-line-through&quot;"
></type
><type
cssSpecial="text-decoration:none"
id="tNoUnderline"
xsl-foSpecial="text-decoration=&quot;no-underline&quot;"
></type
><type
cssSpecial="text-decoration:overline"
id="tOverline"
xsl-foSpecial="text-decoration=&quot;overline&quot;"
></type
><type
font-style="normal"
font-variant="normal"
font-weight="normal"
id="tRegular"
></type
><type
font-family="Charis SIL Small Caps"
id="tSmallCaps"
></type
><type
XeLaTeXSpecial="line-through"
cssSpecial="text-decoration:line-through"
id="tStrikethrough"
xsl-foSpecial="text-decoration=&quot;line-through&quot;"
></type
><type
XeLaTeXSpecial="subscript"
cssSpecial="vertical-align:sub;"
font-size="65%"
id="tSubscript"
xsl-foSpecial="baseline-shift='sub'"
></type
><type
XeLaTeXSpecial="superscript"
cssSpecial="vertical-align:super;"
font-size="65%"
id="tSuperscript"
xsl-foSpecial="baseline-shift='super'"
></type
><type
XeLaTeXSpecial="underline"
cssSpecial="text-decoration:underline"
id="tUnderline"
xsl-foSpecial="text-decoration=&quot;underline&quot;"
></type
><comment
>Add your custom types here.</comment
><type
id="tDialogTitle"
></type
><type
color="#800080"
font-family="Arial"
font-size="12pt"
font-style="italic"
id="tEmpty"
></type
><type
color="red"
id="tErrorType"
></type
><type
color="blue"
font-family="Arial"
id="tGloss"
></type
><type
color="#009900"
font-family="Charis SIL"
font-weight="bold"
id="tKey"
></type
><type
color="red"
font-family="Arial"
font-size="12pt"
id="tLexical"
></type
><type
color="maroon"
id="tMenuItem"
></type
><type
color="black"
font-family="Arial"
font-size="12pt"
id="tNonterminal"
></type
><type
before="AMPLE"
color="navy"
font-style="italic"
id="tAmple"
></type
><type
before="CARLAStudio"
color="navy"
font-style="italic"
id="tCarlaStudio"
></type
><type
before="Hermit Crab"
color="navy"
font-style="italic"
id="tHermitCrab"
></type
><type
before="XAmple"
color="navy"
font-style="italic"
id="tXAmple"
></type
><type
before="TonePars"
color="navy"
font-style="italic"
id="tTonePars"
></type
><type
before="PC-PATR grammar"
id="tPcPatrGrammar"
></type
><type
before="9.1.18"
id="tFLExVersion"
></type
><type
before="700072"
id="tFWDatabaseVersion"
></type
><type
before="PcPatr Browser"
color="navy"
font-style="italic"
id="tPcPatrBrowser"
></type
><type
before="Use TonePars with FLEx"
color="navy"
font-style="italic"
id="tToneParsFLEx"
></type
><type
before="FieldWorks Language Explorer"
color="navy"
font-style="italic"
id="tFieldWorks"
></type
><type
before="FLEx"
color="navy"
font-style="italic"
id="tFLEx"
></type
><type
color="black"
font-family="Monospaced"
font-weight="bold"
id="tSynTagmeme"
></type
><type
color="navy"
id="tTool"
></type
><type
before="XMLmind XML Editor"
color="navy"
font-style="italic"
id="tXXE"
></type
></types
><contentControl
><contentTypes
><contentType
id="ctKeyColor"
>Tree description in color/font</contentType
><contentType
id="ctRegular"
>Tree description plain</contentType
></contentTypes
><contentControlChoices
><contentControlChoice
active="yes"
exclude="ctKeyColor"
>Tree description regular</contentControlChoice
><contentControlChoice
active="no"
>Tree description color/font</contentControlChoice
></contentControlChoices
></contentControl
></lingPaper
><publisherStyleSheet
><publisherStyleSheetName
>SIL International Paper Stylesheet</publisherStyleSheetName
><publisherStyleSheetVersion
>0.4.5</publisherStyleSheetVersion
><pageLayout
><pageWidth
>8.5in</pageWidth
><pageHeight
>11in</pageHeight
><pageTopMargin
>.7in</pageTopMargin
><pageBottomMargin
>.675in</pageBottomMargin
><pageInsideMargin
>1.5in</pageInsideMargin
><pageOutsideMargin
>1in</pageOutsideMargin
><useThesisSubmissionStyle
></useThesisSubmissionStyle
><headerMargin
>.25in</headerMargin
><footerMargin
>.25in</footerMargin
><paragraphIndent
>1em</paragraphIndent
><blockQuoteIndent
>.125in</blockQuoteIndent
><lineSpacing
></lineSpacing
><defaultFontFamily
>Charis SIL</defaultFontFamily
><basicPointSize
>12</basicPointSize
><footnotePointSize
>10</footnotePointSize
><footnoteLine
leaderlength="2in"
leaderpattern="rule"
textalign="left"
></footnoteLine
><linkLayout
color="blue"
decoration="underline"
><abbrRefLinkLayout
></abbrRefLinkLayout
><appendixRefLinkLayout
></appendixRefLinkLayout
><citationLinkLayout
></citationLinkLayout
><contentsLinkLayout
></contentsLinkLayout
><endnoteRefLinkLayout
></endnoteRefLinkLayout
><exampleRefLinkLayout
></exampleRefLinkLayout
><genericRefLinkLayout
></genericRefLinkLayout
><indexLinkLayout
></indexLinkLayout
><interlinearRefLinkLayout
></interlinearRefLinkLayout
><linkLinkLayout
></linkLinkLayout
><sectionRefLinkLayout
></sectionRefLinkLayout
><urlLinkLayout
></urlLinkLayout
></linkLayout
><headerFooterPageStyles
font-family="Times New Roman"
font-size="9pt"
font-style="italic"
><headerFooterFirstPage
><header
><leftHeaderFooterItem
><nothing
></nothing
></leftHeaderFooterItem
><centerHeaderFooterItem
><nothing
></nothing
></centerHeaderFooterItem
><rightHeaderFooterItem
><nothing
></nothing
></rightHeaderFooterItem
></header
><footer
><leftHeaderFooterItem
><nothing
></nothing
></leftHeaderFooterItem
><centerHeaderFooterItem
><pageNumber
font-size="smaller"
font-style="italic"
></pageNumber
></centerHeaderFooterItem
><rightHeaderFooterItem
><nothing
></nothing
></rightHeaderFooterItem
></footer
></headerFooterFirstPage
><headerFooterOddEvenPages
><headerFooterEvenPage
><header
><leftHeaderFooterItem
><pageNumber
font-size="smaller"
font-style="italic"
></pageNumber
></leftHeaderFooterItem
><centerHeaderFooterItem
><nothing
></nothing
></centerHeaderFooterItem
><rightHeaderFooterItem
><paperTitle
font-size="smaller"
font-style="italic"
></paperTitle
></rightHeaderFooterItem
></header
><footer
><leftHeaderFooterItem
><nothing
></nothing
></leftHeaderFooterItem
><centerHeaderFooterItem
><nothing
></nothing
></centerHeaderFooterItem
><rightHeaderFooterItem
><nothing
></nothing
></rightHeaderFooterItem
></footer
></headerFooterEvenPage
><headerFooterOddPage
><header
><leftHeaderFooterItem
><sectionTitle
font-size="smaller"
font-style="italic"
></sectionTitle
></leftHeaderFooterItem
><centerHeaderFooterItem
><nothing
></nothing
></centerHeaderFooterItem
><rightHeaderFooterItem
><pageNumber
font-size="smaller"
font-style="italic"
></pageNumber
></rightHeaderFooterItem
></header
><footer
><leftHeaderFooterItem
><nothing
></nothing
></leftHeaderFooterItem
><centerHeaderFooterItem
><nothing
></nothing
></centerHeaderFooterItem
><rightHeaderFooterItem
><nothing
></nothing
></rightHeaderFooterItem
></footer
></headerFooterOddPage
></headerFooterOddEvenPages
></headerFooterPageStyles
></pageLayout
><frontMatterLayout
><comment
>Front Matter Layout</comment
><titleLayout
font-size="18pt"
font-weight="bold"
pagebreakbefore="yes"
spacebefore="1.25in"
startonoddpage="yes"
textalign="center"
></titleLayout
><subtitleLayout
font-size="14pt"
font-weight="bold"
textalign="center"
></subtitleLayout
><authorLayout
font-style="italic"
textalign="center"
></authorLayout
><affiliationLayout
font-style="italic"
textalign="center"
></affiliationLayout
><emailAddressLayout
font-size="90%"
textalign="center"
></emailAddressLayout
><presentedAtLayout
font-size="10pt"
textalign="center"
textbefore="Presented at "
></presentedAtLayout
><dateLayout
font-size="10pt"
textalign="center"
></dateLayout
><versionLayout
font-size="10pt"
textalign="center"
></versionLayout
><contentsLayout
font-size="14pt"
font-weight="bold"
spaceafter="12pt"
spacebefore="24pt"
textalign="center"
useperiodafterappendixletter="yes"
></contentsLayout
><abstractLayout
font-size="14pt"
font-weight="bold"
spaceafter="12pt"
spacebefore="24pt"
textalign="center"
></abstractLayout
><acknowledgementsLayout
font-size="14pt"
font-weight="bold"
spaceafter="12pt"
spacebefore="24pt"
textalign="center"
></acknowledgementsLayout
><prefaceLayout
font-size="14pt"
font-weight="bold"
spaceafter="12pt"
spacebefore="24pt"
textalign="center"
></prefaceLayout
></frontMatterLayout
><bodyLayout
><comment
>Body Layout</comment
><section1Layout
><sectionTitleLayout
font-size="14pt"
font-weight="bold"
spaceafter="12pt"
spacebefore="24pt"
textalign="center"
></sectionTitleLayout
></section1Layout
><section2Layout
><sectionTitleLayout
font-size="12pt"
font-weight="bold"
spaceafter="12pt"
spacebefore="12pt"
textalign="start"
></sectionTitleLayout
></section2Layout
><section3Layout
><sectionTitleLayout
font-style="italic"
font-weight="bold"
spaceafter="12pt"
spacebefore="12pt"
textalign="start"
></sectionTitleLayout
></section3Layout
><section4Layout
><sectionTitleLayout
font-style="italic"
spaceafter="12pt"
spacebefore="12pt"
textalign="start"
></sectionTitleLayout
></section4Layout
><section5Layout
ignore="yes"
><sectionTitleLayout
></sectionTitleLayout
></section5Layout
><section6Layout
ignore="yes"
><sectionTitleLayout
></sectionTitleLayout
></section6Layout
></bodyLayout
><backMatterLayout
><comment
>Back Matter Layout</comment
><acknowledgementsLayout
font-size="14pt"
font-weight="bold"
spaceafter="12pt"
spacebefore="24pt"
textalign="center"
></acknowledgementsLayout
><appendixLayout
><appendixTitleLayout
font-size="14pt"
font-weight="bold"
spaceafter="12pt"
spacebefore="24pt"
textafterletter=". "
textalign="center"
></appendixTitleLayout
></appendixLayout
><glossaryLayout
font-size="14pt"
font-weight="bold"
spaceafter="12pt"
spacebefore="24pt"
textalign="center"
></glossaryLayout
><referencesTitleLayout
font-size="14pt"
font-weight="bold"
spaceafter="12pt"
spacebefore="24pt"
textalign="center"
></referencesTitleLayout
><xi:include
href="SILInternationalReferencesStylesheet.xml"
xpointer="element(/1)"
xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
></xi:include
><indexLayout
font-size="14pt"
font-weight="bold"
spaceafter="12pt"
spacebefore="24pt"
textalign="center"
></indexLayout
></backMatterLayout
><contentLayout
><comment
>Document Content Layout</comment
><exampleLayout
indent-after=".125in"
indent-before=".125in"
></exampleLayout
><interlinearSourceStyle
></interlinearSourceStyle
><endnoteRefLayout
></endnoteRefLayout
><figureLayout
captionLocation="after"
><figureLabelLayout
textafter=" "
></figureLabelLayout
><figureNumberLayout
></figureNumberLayout
><figureCaptionLayout
textbefore=" "
></figureCaptionLayout
></figureLayout
><figureRefLayout
></figureRefLayout
><tablenumberedLayout
captionLocation="after"
><tablenumberedLabelLayout
textafter=" "
></tablenumberedLabelLayout
><tablenumberedNumberLayout
></tablenumberedNumberLayout
><tablenumberedCaptionLayout
textbefore="  "
></tablenumberedCaptionLayout
></tablenumberedLayout
><tablenumberedRefLayout
></tablenumberedRefLayout
></contentLayout
></publisherStyleSheet
></styledPaper
></xlingpaper
>
